[WAVES CRASHING]
MAN: Those were the years
after the icecaps had melted...
...because of the greenhouse gases...
...and the oceans had risen
to drown so many cities...
...along all the shorelines
of the world.
Amsterdam, Venice, New York...
...forever lost.
Millions of people were displaced.
Climate became chaotic.
Hundreds of millions of people
starved in poorer countries.
Elsewhere, a high degree
of prosperity survived...
...when most governments
in the developed world...
...introduced legal sanctions
to strictly license pregnancies...
...which was why robots, who are never
hungry and who did not consume resources...
...beyond those of
their first manufacture...
...were so essential
an economic link...
...in the chain mail of society.
To create an artificial being
has been the dream of man...
...since the birth of science.
Not merely the beginning of
the modern age, when our forebears...
...astonished the world
with the first thinking machines...
...primitive monsters that could
play chess.
[ALL CHUCKLE]
How far we have come!
The artificial being is a reality,
a perfect simulacrum...
...articulated in limb,
articulate in speech...
...and not lacking in human response.
[SHEILA SCREAMS]
And even pain-memory response.
[ALL LAUGH]
How did that make you feel?
Angry? Shocked?
-I don't understand.
-What did I do to your feelings?
You did it to my hand.
Aye...
...there's the rub.
Undress.
At Cybertronics of New Jersey, the artificial
being has reached its highest form.
The universally adapted Mecha...
...the basis for hundreds of models
serving the human race...
...in all the multiplicity
of daily life.
That's far enough.
But we have no reason
to congratulate ourselves.
We are rightly proud of it.
But what does it amount to?
Sheila, open.
[CLICKS]
A sensory toy...
...with intelligent behavioral circuits...
...using neurone-sequencing
technology...
...as old as I am.
I believe that my work on mapping
the impulse pathways in a single neurone...
...can enable us to construct...
...a Mecha of
a qualitatively different order.
I propose...
...that we build a robot...
...who can love.
MAN:
Love?
But we ship thousands
of lover-models every month.
MAN: Of course. You're your own
best customer, Syatyoo-Sama.
[ALL LAUGH]
Quality control is very important.
Tell me, what is love?
Love is first widening my eyes
a little bit...
...and quickening my breathing a little
and warming my skin and--
And so on, exactly so. Thank you, Sheila.
But I wasn't referring
to sensuality simulators.
The word that I used was "love."
Love like the love of a child
for its parents.
I propose that we build
a robot-child who can love.
A robot-child who will genuinely love
the parent or parents it imprints on...
...with a love that will never end.
A child-substitute Mecha?
But a Mecha with a mind,
with neuronal feedback.
You see, what I'm suggesting is
that love will be the key...
...by which they acquire a kind of
subconscious never before achieved.
An inner world of metaphor,
of intuition...
...of self-motivated reasoning,
of dreams.
A robot that dreams?
How exactly do we pull this off?
[ALL LAUGH]
It occurs to me...
...with all this animus existing
against Mechas today...
...it isn't simply a question
of creating a robot who can love.
But isn't the real conundrum,
can you get a human to love them back?
Ours will be a perfect child
caught in a freeze-frame...
...always loving,
never ill, never changing.
With all the childless couples
yearning in vain for a license...
...our little Mecha will not only open up
a completely new market...
...it will fill a great human need.
But you haven't answered my question.
If a robot could genuinely love a person...
...what responsibility does that person
hold toward that Mecha in return?
-It's a moral question, isn't it?
-The oldest one of all.
But in the beginning, didn't God
create Adam to love him?
[CHATTERING]
MONICA: "The baby was born
as the first leaves of autumn fell.
A baby boy.
And Marian's wish came true.
The boy had white hair.
He was baptized Martin,
after his grandfather."
-Dr. Frazier, hi, good to see you.
-Hello.
There was an article in
the Journal of Chinese Medicine.
Hello again, Monica.
They talked about virus locators,
these microscopic, synthetic hunter killers.
-Did you read that article?
-I can still hear you.
-I'm worried about her. She's got me worried.
-I know.
She's in the most difficult position of feeling
she should mourn the death of your son.
After five years, your instincts tell you
to mourn him too.
But medicine assures us that mourning is
inappropriate, that Martin is merely pending.
Pending.
So all her grief goes undigested.
[FRAZIER SIGHS]
Henry, your son may be
beyond our science.
But it's your wife
who can still be reached.
The screening process
was extremely difficult.
It was almost tougher
than building the prototype.
Of our 2000 employees, a surprising few
met your requirements for in-house testing.
Initiate.
Employment record,
quality of lifestyle.
Query. Internal data.
Loyalty to the firm,
and in this individual's case...
...a family tragedy that may
qualify him above the rest.
I'll see him.
Henry.
-Don't kill me.
-Henry, what are you doing?
I love you. Don't kill me.
The door's closed.
I like your floor.
I can't accept this! There is
no substitute for your own child!
You don't have to accept it, or even try.
-It's not too late to take him back.
-What were you thinking?
-Shh. I'll do whatever you want me to do.
-Do you think I can just...? I can just...?
-I'll do whatever you want me to do!
-I don't know what to do.
I know, l know. I'll return him
to Cybertronics first thing in the morning.
It's gone.
[SNIFFS]
Good.
I mean, Henry, did you see his face?
He's so real.
-But he's not.
-No, he's not.
-I mean, inside, he's like the rest, isn't he?
-A hundred miles of fiber, yeah.
But outside, he just looks so real...
...like he is a child.
A Mecha-child.
A child.
The show of faith my company has placed
on me, on us, is extraordinary.
There are a few simple procedures
we need to follow...
...if and when you decide to keep David.
If you decide to keep him,
there's an imprinting protocol...
...consisting of a code string
of seven words...
...which need to be spoken to David
in the predefined order here.
Now, Monica, for our own protection,
this imprinting is irreversible.
The robot child's love would be sealed,
hard-wired, and we'd be part of him forever.
Because of this, after imprinting,
no Mecha-child can be resold.
If an adoptive parent
decides not to keep a child...
...they must return it
to Cybertronics for destruction.
I had to sign a letter of agreement
or they wouldn't even let you see David.
You have to sign it too. Right here.
Monica...
...don't imprint until you're entirely sure.
Silly man. Of course I'm not sure.
Would you like me to sleep now?
HENRY:
Good idea. Good idea. Monica?
Uh, well, it's late, you know. It's after 9.
How late do they let you stay up?
I can never go to sleep.
But I can lay quietly
and not make a peep.
So those pajamas will fit you.
We'll be in to check on you
in the morning.
Dress me?
I'm gonna say good night
while you boys be boys.
HENRY:
Raise your arms.
[KETTLE WHISTLING]
[MONlCA GASPS]
[SIGHS]
-Is it a game?
-Yes.
Hide-and-seek.
I found you.
That's your room. Just, uh, go and play.
[TOYS RUSTLING]
[GASPS THEN SCREAMS]
I found you.
Out! Out! Get out of here!
And close the goddamn door!
[CUTLERY CLINKING]
[HENRY CHEWING]
[DAVID LAUGHS
AND MONICA SCREAMS]
[LAUGHING]
[HENRY & MONICA LAUGHING]
[ALL LAUGHING]
[CHUCKLES]
Is it a game?
Now, I'm gonna read some words.
And, um, they won't make any sense,
but I want you to listen to them anyway.
And look at me all the time.
Can you do that?
Yes, Monica.
Can you feel my hand
on the back of your neck?
Yes.
-Does any of this hurt?
-No.
Okay, now...
...look at me.
Ready?
Cirrus.
Socrates.
Particle.
Decibel.
Hurricane.
Dolphin.
Tulip.
Monica.
David.
All right.
I wonder if I did that right.
[MUTTERS]
What were those words for, Mommy?
What did you call me?
Mommy.
Who am I, David?
You are my mommy.
[HUMMING]
[MONlCA CHUCKLES]
You smell lovely. I love it
when you wear this stuff.
-Will you still love me when it's all gone?
-No.
Ha, ha, stop it!
We can get married again and begin with
a fragrance that's not in such short supply.
-Ha, ha.
-We gotta go. Come on, we're late.
[MONlCA HUMMING]
-Hello, David.
DAVID: Hello, Henry.
Walk us out, all right, sweetheart?
Come on.
My shoe!
[MONlCA LAUGHING]
-Your tie! You're hopeless!
HENRY: I'm helpless. He made our bed.
MONICA:
He's just trying so hard!
He's trying so hard to please me.
He has a way with my coffee!
It's creepy. You can never hear him coming.
He's just always there.
-He is only a child.
-Monica, he's a toy.
He's a gift.
From you.
David, when we leave,
the doors will go smart...
...so you can't leave your room,
but if you'd like....
-Oh, l put way too much on.
-Do I smell lovely?
Oh, God, no!
[MONlCA SIGHS]
DAVID:
Mommy?
Will you die?
Well, one day, David, yes, I will.
I'll be alone.
Don't worry yourself so.
How long will you live?
For ages.
For 50 years.
[WHISPERS]
I love you, Mommy.
I hope you never die.
Never.
Yes.
HENRY:
Darling!
We're becoming unfashionably,
unreasonably late.
Hello?
This belonged to Martin, my son.
[YAWNS]
His name is Teddy.
Teddy, this is David.
-Hello, Teddy.
-Hello, David. Unh.
David, Teddy is a supertoy. I know
you'll take good care of each other.
I am not a toy.
MONICA:
Henry!
-Sorry!
-What were you doing up there?
MONICA:
Uh, I'll tell you in the car. Come on!
Is 50 years a long time?
I don't think so.
[PHONE RINGING]
David, I'll get it!
-Honey, hand it to me.
-Look what I can do.
[BEEPS]
WOMAN [OVER SPEAKERPHONE]:
Hello.
[CHUCKLES]
Yes?
WOMAN:
Mrs. Swinton, could you hold a moment?
l have an urgent call from your husband.
Yes, I will.
Uh, David, I need to talk to the phone now.
HENRY [OVER SPEAKERPHONE]:
Monica? Monica, can you hear me?
-Let the phone talk now.
HENRY: Pick up the phone, Monica!
-Run along, play with Teddy.
HENRY: Pick up the phone. Oh, my God--
Hello, Henry, what is it?
What?
When?
Oh, God.
David.
The most wonderful thing
in the whole world has happened.
This is Martin.
This is my son.
Martin, no!
We'll have a contest to see
who he comes to first.
Come here, Teddy! Come here!
Teddy! Come here!
-You call him too.
-Come here, Teddy.
MARTIN: Come on. Teddy!
DAVID: Come here, boy.
-Come here! Come on, Teddy.
-Come here, Teddy.
MARTIN: Teddy, come.
DAVID: Come here, Teddy.
-Come here, Teddy.
-Come, Teddy! Come.
TEDDY:
Mommy! Mommy!
MONICA:
Are they torturing you, Teddy?
He used to be a supertoy, but...
...now he's old and stupid.
You want him?
Yes, please.
Now you're the new supertoy.
So, what good stuff can you do?
Can you do power stuff,
like walk on the ceiling or the walls?
Anti-gravity, like float or fly?
Can you?
No, because I'm real.
Can you break this?
I better not.
These things, they do look better
in pieces. They do.
I can't.
[MARTIN SIGHS]
Stand up.
-Look, they made you bigger than me.
-Who did?
They did. The dollmakers.
They made you taller.
Why don't you look like one?
Like one?
You're not cute like a doll.
You just look like someone's ordinary kid.
When's your birthday?
I never had a birthday.
Okay. When were you first built?
When's your "build-day"?
I don't remember.
[MARTIN SIGHS]
Okay, what's the first thing
you can remember?
A bird.
What sort of bird?
A bird with big wings...
...and feathers sticking up
from the bottom.
Can you draw it?
Yes.
That looks like a peacock.
Can you say "peacock"?
Peacock.
-Can you say "pee"?
-Pee.
Now say that two times fast.
Okay. Then you gotta put
the green ones--
MARTIN: Read to us?
-Hey.
Let's see.
Oh, yeah.
David's going to love it.
MONICA: "As soon as the show was over,
the Showman went into the kitchen...
...where the sheep,
which she was preparing for supper...
...was roasting on the slowly turning spit
in the furnace.
When he saw there was
not enough wood to finish roasting it...
...he called Harlequin
and Punchinello and said:
'Bring me in Pinocchio!
You will find him hanging on a nail.
He is made of nice, dry wood
and will make a nice fire for my roast."'
MONICA:
"Pinocchio worked until midnight.
And instead of making
eight baskets, he made 1 6.
Then he went to bed and fell asleep.
As he slept, he dreamt he saw
the fairy, lovely and smiling...
...who gave him a kiss, saying:
'Brave Pinocchio...
...in return for your good heart,
I forgive all your past misdeeds.
Be good in future, and you will be happy.'
Then the dream ended
and Pinocchio awoke, full of amazement.
You can imagine how astonished
he was when he saw...
...that he was no longer a puppet...
...but a real boy, just like other boys."
Josephine, evidently,
has, uh, taken a leave of absence.
MONICA: Oh, my God.
HENRY: Mm-hm.
MONICA:
Well, I saw that coming.
HENRY: How? They were fabulous together.
MONICA: Come on! She was miserable.
HENRY: He never said they were miserable.
MONICA: That's because....
Is that because of the cutbacks?
HENRY:
No idea. They don't tell me anything.
MONICA:
Didn't they have a weight problem?
HENRY:
Well, so do I.
MONICA:
Ha, ha. You do not! That is ridiculous.
HENRY:
I don't know.
There's something
about inner beauty that....
You will break.
-Oh. That is ridiculous!
-Exactly.
[MONlCA CHUCKLES]
HENRY: Work has become so silly.
-I know what you're talking about.
[DAVID & MARTIN CHEWING]
HENRY: Does he eat?
-I'm not sure.
HENRY: You're not supposed to do that.
MONICA: What are you doing?
Have the manual, the book?
-Martin, put the fork down!
-Stop, David. Will you stop?
Martin, you're provoking him. Stop it.
-Stop it, David! Stop it!
-The two of you, stop! Stop it now!
Stop it!
David, stop it!
[WHIRRING]
-There's sputum in the code lockers.
-Smell that garlic.
We should throw in a chest mint.
-Can you locate the surface?
-Don't touch the merchandise.
TECH 1 : It's all swamp in here.
TECH 2: You made a mess of yourself.
Spinach is for rabbits, people and Popeye.
Not robo-boys.
TECH 1 :
Try to insert yourself.
Through the pantry, the lower shelves.
It's okay, Mommy. It doesn't hurt.
Deactivators are all shut down
on the left side.
-Monica.
-No! I just have to....
[MONlCA SIGHS]
That's not all of it. That's not all of it.
[INSTRUMENT WHIRRING]
MARTlN: If you do something really,
really, really special for me...
...a special mission...
...then I'll go tell Mommy...
...I love you.
And then she'll love you too.
What shall I do?
You have to promise,
and then I'll tell you.
You have to tell me,
and then I'll promise.
I want a lock of Mommy's hair.
I'll share it with you.
And if you had it and wore it...
...she might love you even more.
Like the princess
in the movie we saw.
When she had the prince's hair
in her necklace thing...
...he loved her.
We can ask her.
No, it has to be a secret mission.
[WHISPERS] Sneak into Mommy's bedroom
in the middle of the night...
...and chop it off.
I can't, Martin. I'm not allowed.
You promised.
You said, "Tell me, and then I'll promise."
Didn't you?
MONICA: Ah! Aah!
-David!
Why did you do that?
Why did you do that?!
Talk to me! Goddamn it, talk to me!
Why did you do that?
Henry, you're hurting him!
You're hurting him! You'll break him!
Henry...
...I wanted Mommy to love me...
...more.
-Oh, my God.
-What?
I think l cut my eye. I think it's bleeding.
HENRY:
Come on, watch it.
It's normal for little boys
to feel jealous and competitive.
Martin's only been home a month.
It's normal for brothers
to challenge each other.
He was playing a game, he made
a mistake. He's practically human.
-Not how he looked holding the knife.
-Scissors.
It was a weapon.
Why do you keep imagining
he was trying to harm me?
Because we don't know the answer
to that.
How is he worth the risk to you,
to Martin, to our family?
I won't let you take him back. You told me
what would happen if we did.
Think about this.
If he was created to love, then it's
reasonable to assume he knows how to hate.
And if pushed to those extremes,
what is he really capable of?
[CHILDREN SHOUTING]
Happy birthday, Martin.
I made this for you.
-This him? Is this your little brother?
-Technically, no.
-He's Mecha.
DAVID: What's Mecha?
We're organic...
...you're "mecha-anical."
Orga, Mecha.
Orga, Mecha. Orga, Mecha.
Todd, stop!
I didn't know they even made little kids.
Can you pee?
[BOY 1 CHUCKLES]
-I cannot.
-Let's see what you can't pee with.
[BOYS LAUGH]
MARTIN:
Guys, come on.
Touch it.
BOY 2:
It feels so real!
That's creepy.
BOY 2: Whoa. It feels so real!
BOY 3: That is too real.
Mecha-real.
Does he have DAS?
DAS what?
-Das ist gut.
BOYS: Ha, ha.
Damage Avoidance System. DAS.
It's a pain-alert system.
Our serving man has it.
It's so they don't go picking up fire
with their bare hands.
Watch. Watch this.
I'm not gonna cut you. This won't hurt.
I'm not gonna cut your skin.
Tell me when you feel it.
DAVID: Keep me safe, Martin.
MARTIN: Let me go!
-Keep me safe, Martin. Keep me safe.
-Let me go! Mom!
Mom! Mom!
Keep me safe, keep me safe,
keep me safe.
Henry!
Oh, my God!
[MONlCA SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
Oh, my God, he's not breathing!
He's not breathing!
[HENRY & MONICA
SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
HENRY:
Take a breath.
[MARTIN COUGHING]
HENRY:
Cough it up. That's a great boy!
MONICA: Thank God!
HENRY: Call Frazier. Tell him what happened.
Get him out of the sun.
-Hey, David?
DAVID: Mommy!
I need to, uh, speak to you
for a minute, okay?
Okay.
[SNIFFS]
These are beautiful.
Thank you.
Um....
[MONlCA SNIFFS]
Um, hey, David, I was thinking we could go
for a drive tomorrow in the country.
You and me. What do you say?
-And Teddy?
-Yeah, and Teddy.
Thank you, Mommy.
Thank you so much.
Tomorrow's gonna be just for us, okay?
Where are we going?
Someplace nice?
Are those happy tears?
What's for dinner tonight?
-You know you don't eat.
-Yes.
But I like sitting at the table.
[SIGHS]
MONICA:
David? David, I want-- David, listen.
Listen to me!
David.
David, listen. Now....
You won't understand the reasons...
...but I have to leave you here.
Is it a game?
No.
When will you come back for me?
I'm not, David.
You'll have to be here by yourself.
Alone?
With Teddy.
No.
No, no, no! No, Mommy, please!
-No, no. Please, Mommy.
-Shh, shh. They would destroy you, David.
I'm sorry I broke myself,
I'm so sorry I cut your hair off...
...and I'm sorry I hurt Martin--
I have to go! I have to go! Stop it!
Stop it!
[SOBBING]
-I have to go now.
-Mommy, don't! Mommy! Mommy!
If Pinocchio became a real boy and
I become a real boy, can I come home?
-That's a story.
-But a story tells what happens.
Stories are not real! You're not real!
Now, listen. Look, look!
Take this, all right?
Take this.
Don't let anyone see how much it is.
Look! Don't go that way.
Look! Look at me! Don't go that way.
Go anywhere
but that way or they'll catch you.
Don't ever let them catch you!
Stay away from Flesh Fairs,
away from where there are lots of people.
Stay away from all people.
Only others like you, only Mecha are safe!
DAVID: Why do you wanna leave me?
Why do you wanna leave me?
I'm sorry I'm not real.
If you let me, l'll be so real for you!
MONICA:
Let go. Let go, David.
Let go!
I'm sorry I didn't tell you about the world.
WOMAN:
l'm afraid.
MAN: Of me?
WOMAN: Yes.
MAN:
That I will hurt you?
WOMAN:
Yes.
I think...
...you're afraid of letting go.
I think you're afraid of happiness.
And this is starting to excite me.
Are you afraid of seeing the stars...
...Patricia?
I can show you how to reach them.
I'm afraid of what
you've got under there.
May I see what it looks like first?
Is this your first time...
...with something like me?
I've never been with Mecha.
That makes two of us.
[BOTH LAUGH]
I'm afraid it will hurt.
Patricia...
...once you've had a lover-robot...
...you'll never want a real man...
...again.
Are these the wounds of passion?
[CHUCKLES]
DlCK POWELL [SINGING ON SPEAKER]:
Are the stars out tonight?
l don't know if it's cloudy....
Do you hear that music?
POWELL [SINGING]:
l only have eyes for you, dear
[LAUGHING]
You...
...are a goddess...
...Patricia.
You wind me up inside.
But you deserve much better
in your life.
You deserve...
...me.
CHORUS [SINGING ON SPEAKER]:
'Cause l only have eyes for you, dear
The moon may be high
But l can't see a thing in the sky
[PENDANT BEEPING]
CHORUS [SINGING]:
'Cause l only have eyes for you
[DANCE MUSIC PLAYING]
-Hey, Joe, what do you know?
-Hey, Jane, how's the game?
[PENDANT BEEPING]
[JOE HUMMlNG]
-Hey, Joe, what do you know?
-Hello, Mr. Williamson.
Place a DND on Room 1 02, please.
Sure thing.
[WILLIAMSON GRUNTS]
There you are.
Oh, Joe.
Uh, when you're finished here, crack
your collar, show off your operating license.
The Flesh Fair is in Barn Creek
and the hounds are out hunting for strays.
-Good thing I ran into you. Thanks.
-Sure thing.
Mustn't keep a lady waiting.
STUBBY KAYE [SINGING ON SPEAKER]:
When you see a guy
Reach for stars in the sky
Miss Bevins.
It's Joe.
At your service.
I've been counting the seconds
since last we met.
JOHNNY SILVER [SINGING ON SPEAKER]:
Chances are he's insane
As only a John can be for a Jane
KAYE:
When you meet a gent
Have you been crying, Samantha?
I found a tear.
KAYE [SINGING]:
--Taj Mahal
Call it sad, call it funny
But it's better than even money
That the guy's only doing it for some doll
Hey, Joe, what do you know?
SILVER [SINGING]:
When you see a Joe
Savin' half of his dough
How many seconds has it been...
...the last time
the two of you were together?
Two hundred and fifty-five thousand,
one hundred and thirty-three.
Goodbye, Sam. And never forget:
You killed me first.
I'm in bad trouble.
[SIREN WAILING]
DAVID:
If I am a real boy...
...then l can go back.
And she will love me then.
TEDDY:
How?
DAVID: The Blue Fairy made Pinocchio
into a real boy.
She can make me into a real boy.
I must find her. I must become real.
There must be someone in the whole
world who knows where she lives.
[TRUCK APPROACHING]
[TRUCK BEEPING]
[BUZZING]
[CLICKS THEN WHIRS]
Moon on the rise!
It's the Flesh Fair. They destroy us
on-stage. I've been there.
What do we do?
We run now.
MAN [OVER BULLHORN]:
Any old iron.
Expel your Mecha!
Purge yourselves of artificiality.
Come along, now.
Let some Mecha loose to run.
Any old unlicensed iron down there?
Hey, you see that?
Could be a human thing.
No, he's scanning cold.
No expiration date, no ID.
What's a new model
doing loose and unregistered?
Sir, it's a late-generation lover-Mecha.
That's a relief from all this antique iron.
You are certain he's not a man?
I wouldn't want a repeat
of the Trenton incident.
Sir, he's a free-range Mecha running hot.
Let's reel him in, boys.
Sic the hounds on the rest.
[ENGlNES REVVING]
Shake down shantytown!
What's your name?
DAVID:
My name is David.
Hello, David. How old are you?
I don't know.
You need someone to take care of you?
Would you like a nanny?
I have many good references.
Do you know where the Blue Fairy lives?
[ENGlNE REVVING]
JOHNSON-JOHNSON:
Let out the line. Steady your drift.
Open the lower hold.
Don't be afraid, David.
[NANNY SINGING
"UNE CHANSON DOUCE"]
I'll break, David.
TEDDY:
Ow.
[CROWD CHEERING]
[BAND PLAYING "WHAT ABOUT US"]
SINGER [SINGlNG]:
Just like another speck of dust
That's on the highway of life
He screams at anyone who passes
That the end is in sight
So then he circles the wagons
So then he circles and quits
'Cause the highway could become
The final bottomless pit
So when the company wants another....
Hello!
Anybody lose this?
This your dog?
[TEDDY GROWLS]
Take it to lost and found
for me, okay?
Hey! Lost and found!
[CROWD CHEERING]
TEDDY: Do you know David?
WORKER: Where's the "off" switch?
TEDDY:
Where's David?
Can you help me find David?
I have to find David.
Are you taking me to David?
[CROWD CHEERING]
SINGER [SINGlNG]:
Just like another last call
It means nothing at all
You either kiss a lot of ass
Or blow the clock off the wall
Another warning ignored....
[CROWD SHOUTING AND BOOING]
Could you kind of shoot me
over the propeller thing?
I don't need to go through it. I was
considering it, but I changed my mind.
Gentlemen, start your engines!
[CROWD CHEERING]
CROWD:
Ten! Nine! Eight!
Seven! Six! Five!
Four! Three! Two!
One!
[CROWD CHEERING]
RlNGMASTER:
What about us?
[CROWD CHEERS]
RlNGMASTER:
What about us?
[CROWD CHEERS]
RlNGMASTER:
We are alive...
...and this is a celebration of life!
And this is commitment...
...to a truly human future!
[CROWD CHEERING]
[BAND PLAYING "WHAT ABOUT US"]
-What's your name?
DAVID: Hello, Teddy.
Hello, David.
Take it!
Take it.
-Biker hounds rolling.
-Cue biker hound.
AMANDA: Papa!
-Amanda, go outside. It's smoky here.
There's a boy in the cage.
MAN: What did you say?
-There's a boy in the cage.
MAN: A boy?
-A real boy. He's stuck in the cage.
-In the pen, honey?
-In the jail place.
-Random crowd reaction....
-We got a remote near the pigpen?
Bring it up on VT-1 . Let me see
what she's talking about.
-What are you looking for?
-She says she saw a boy in there.
-How do you know about this?
-The bear told me.
I told her.
[ALL CHEERING]
Would you be so kind
and shut down my pain receivers?
[POWERS DOWN]
Why is this happening?
History repeats itself.
It's the rite of blood and electricity.
When the opportunities avail
themselves, they pick away at us...
...cutting back our numbers so they
can maintain numerical superiority.
[METAL CLANKING]
My time, is it up already?
Goodbye, everyone.
DAVID: Keep me safe, keep me safe!
WORKER 1 : Not yet. They just want him.
Keep me safe, keep me safe,
keep me safe.
WORKER 2:
Security.
Mike, do you have any reports of any
missing kids, any missing children?
All right, thanks, Mike.
How'd you get in there? Boy! You, boy!
What's your name?
I won't bite you.
Come over where I can see you.
I won't hurt you. I just need to see.
[BEEPS]
-You're a machine.
-I'm a boy.
Is he a toy boy?
My name is David.
Impossible.
I still work, don't I? I can work
in the dark, but my lamp is broken.
My lamplight will not work.
I hit my lamp on a girder overhead.
[CROWD SHOUTING AND BOOING]
[CROWD CHEERING]
Goodbye, David.
No one builds children. No one ever has.
What would be the point?
It could be a custom job.
Some rich and lonely guy's pretend child.
I'm a custom job.
Seventy-five years ago, I was
TIME magazine's Mecha of the Year!
Nah, this work is first-rate.
A lot of love went into him. David?
You are one of a kind, you know that?
-Who made you?
-My mommy made me.
Womb was your factory.
One of those built to aspire
to the human condition.
What is the name of your maker?
Serve U.S., E.Z. Living, Robiville?
-Simulit City Center, Cybertronics?
DAVID: Monica is my mommy.
Can I speak with you for a moment?
SINGER [SINGlNG]:
Just like the old soft-shoe
Like the old song and dance
The only check that's in the mail
Is probably already cashed
Are you a victim of chance?
ls this the way to succeed?
You're just a crack in the wall
Of what the people believe
So when the company wants
The final weapon online
Or when the company wants
To repossess your mind
[DINGS]
You gotta wonder if the people
That you love or trust
Would ever waste a precious second
Trying to answer
What about us?
You're thinking of not putting him
in the show?
Something as original as this
you don't toss out with the garbage.
I say originality without purpose
is a white elephant.
If money is your purpose,
here's your refund. My compliments.
-What'll you do with him?
-Put him where he belongs.
In show business.
It was certainly my good fortune,
running into you!
JOHNSON-JOHNS0N: Let go of him.
-Let go of me.
JOHNSON-JOHNSON: Let go.
-I'm trying.
DAVID: Keep me safe! Don't let go.
-Suit yourselves.
SINGER [SINGlNG]:
What about us?
[CROWD CHEERING]
CROWD:
Johnson-Johnson! Johnson-Johnson!
Johnson-Johnson!
[CROWD CHANTING]
[ALL SHOUTING]
Ladies and gentlemen...
...boys and girls and children of all ages.
What will they think of next?
See here!
A bitty-bot, a Tinkertoy, a living doll.
We all know why they made him.
To steal your hearts,
to replace your children.
This is the latest iteration
in their series of insults to human dignity.
And in their grand scheme
to phase out all of God's little children...
...meet the next generation of child...
...designed to do just that.
[CROWD MURMURING]
JOHNSON-JOHNSON:
Do not be fooled...
...by the artistry of this creation.
No doubt there was talent
in the crafting of this Simulator.
Yet, with the very first strike,
you will see the big lie...
...come apart before your very eyes!
Don't burn me! Don't burn me!
I'm not Pinocchio!
Don't make me die! I'm David! I'm David!
I'm David!
Mecha don't plead for their lives!
Who is that? He looks like a boy!
Built like a boy to disarm us.
See how they try
to imitate our emotions now!
Whatever performance
this Sim puts on, remember...
...we are only demolishing artificiality!
Let he who is without Sim...
...cast the first stone.
Oh-ho-ho.
[CROWD LAUGHS]
WOMAN:
He's just a boy!
MAN:
Johnson, you're a monster!
[CROWD SHOUTING AND BOOING]
Get him out of there
before they tear this place apart.
-We found him.
-Where?
MAN: A Flesh Fair outside Haddonfield.
-Is he alive?
Yes. He's in one piece.
I see the moon.
-Is it real?
-I don't know, David.
DAVID:
Is it coming?
I can't tell yet.
Let's not walk this way.
JOE: Where are we going?
DAVID: This way now.
JOE: Are you in bad trouble?
Have you run away from someone?
DAVID: My mommy told me to run away.
JOE: Why did she say that?
DAVID:
I guess because Henry didn't like me.
JOE:
Why was that?
DAVID: Martin came home.
JOE: And who is he?
DAVID:
Martin is Mommy and Henry's real son.
After I find the Blue Fairy,
then I can go home.
Mommy will love a real boy.
The Blue Fairy will make me into one.
Is Blue Fairy Mecha, Orga,
man or woman?
Woman.
Woman?
I know women!
They sometimes ask for me by name.
FRED ASTAlRE [SINGING ON SPEAKER]:
l'm in heaven
I know all about women.
About as much as there is to know.
No two are ever alike.
And after they've met me, no two...
...are ever the same. And I know
where most of them can be found.
-Where?
-Rouge City.
Across the Delaware. Too far for our feet.
We'll need help to get there.
ASTAlRE [SINGING]:
l'm in heaven
And it is not without peril.
We will have to journey...
...towards the moon.
DAVID:
Are there many women in Rouge City?
JOE: As there are stars at night.
-How will we find just one?
We will ask Dr. Know.
There is nothing he doesn't.
Exactly what name
do you give this woman?
DAVID:
She is just Blue Fairy.
JOE:
Blue Fairy.
In the world of Orga,
blue is the color of melancholy.
Yet the services I provide will put
a blush back on anyone's cheek.
I will change the color of your fairy
for you. She will scream out:
[IN HIGH VOICE] "Oh, yes. Oh, God.
Oh, yes. Oh, God. Oh, God!"
[IN NORMAL VOICE] She will make you a
real boy, for I will make her a real woman...
...and all will be right
with the world...
...because you held my hand
and saved my brain...
...so that once again my customers
may ask for me by name:
"Gigolo Joe, what do you know?"
DAVID:
Why do you do that?
That's just what I do.
Now follow me and don't fall behind.
All roads lead to Rouge!
Don't they say that, hey? Don't they just?
There are girls your age
who are just like me.
We are the guiltless pleasures
of the lonely human being.
You're not gonna get us pregnant or
have us to supper with Mommy and Daddy.
We work under you, we work on you
and we work for you.
Man made us better at what we do
than was ever humanly possible.
If you could manage us a lift
to Rouge City, all this...
[WOMAN GIGGLING]
...and much, much more...
...can be yours.
[BOY LAUGHING]
Get in.
Say, "Ah."
ALL:
Ah!
[DANCE MUSIC PLAYING]
[CROWD CHATTERING AND LAUGHING]
Over there is Here Kitty Kitty...
...where the agency held my tryouts
when I was made new.
That's Tails. Very hoity-toity.
I've yet to be asked to perform there.
Only sunrise gents and sunset ladies.
Strictly Sierra Class robots.
Have no idea how to live. Can't even
speak English. All made in Sweden.
Couldn't tell a joke from a poke.
MAN: No cover charge, no cover charge.
Step on in, step in.
There's Mildred.
I have to show you inside Mildred.
Are you her?
That's Our Lady
of the Immaculate Heart.
The ones who made us are always looking
for the ones who made them.
They go in, fold their hands,
look around their feet, sing songs...
...and when they come out,
it's usually me they find.
I've picked up a lot
of business on this spot.
DlCK POWELL [SINGING ON SPEAKER]:
Are the stars out tonight?
But, Joe, where's Blue Fairy?
POWELL [SINGING]:
l don't know if--
That's what we're gonna find out
when we ask Dr. Know.
That's where everyone goes
who needs to know.
Meet the good doctor.
Starving minds,
welcome to Dr. Know...
...where fast food for thought
is served up 24 hours a day...
...in 40,000 locations nationwide.
Ask Dr. Know. There's nothing I don't.
Tell me where l can find the Blue Fairy.
[BUZZER BUZZES]
Question me, you pay the fee.
Two for five, you get one free.
He means two questions cost 5 Newbucks
with a third question on the house.
In this day and age, David,
nothing costs more than information.
-That's everything.
-Ten Newbucks and a 1 0 copper...
...comes to seven questions
for Dr. Know.
That should be enough.
[WHISPERS]
He's a smooth operator.
He'll press our limits, but try we must.
[BELL DINGS]
Greetings, colleagues!
On offer, factual text or fictionalized text.
Literacy range from primal
to postdoctoral.
From fairy tale to religious.
Who's who or where's where.
Or flat fact.
-[WHISPERS] Flat fact?
KNOW: Thank you for Question 1 .
Flat fact is a term demanding
an equal answer....
[IN NORMAL VOICE] That shouldn't count!
That wasn't my question.
You must take care not raise your voice up
at the end of the sentence.
JOE [IN NORMAL VOICE]:
Flat fact.
[BELL DINGS]
KNOW:
You have six more questions.
Where is Blue Fairy?
KNOW:
In the garden. Vascostylis Blue Fairy.
Blooms twice annually
with bright, blue flowers.
A hybrid between Ascola meda Arnold.
You have five more questions!
[BELL DINGS]
Who is Blue Fairy?
KNOW:
Are you sad, lonely, looking for a friend?
Blue Fairy Escort Service
will find a mate for you.
[BELL DINGS]
KNOW:
You have four more questions.
[WHISPERS]
Joe!
Try "fairy tale."
New category.
A fairy's tale.
No! Fairy tale.
No. Fairy tale.
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
What is Blue Fairy?
Pinocchio, by Carlo Collodi.
"There was a rustling
as a flapping of wings...
...and a large falcon flew
to the windowsill.
'What are your orders, beautiful fairy?"'
That's her!
KNOW: "You must know that the child
with blue hair...
...was no other than
the good-hearted fairy...
...who had lived in that wood
for more than a thousand--"
JOE: David! David.
DAVID: That's her!
It was an example of her.
But I think we're getting closer.
[WHISPERS] But if a fairy tale is real,
then wouldn't it be fact?
A flat fact?
[WHISPERS]
Say no more.
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
New category, please.
Combine...
...fact with...
...fairy tale.
[WHISPERS]
Now...
...ask him again.
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
How...
...can the Blue Fairy...
...make...
...a robot...
...into a real, live boy?
KNOW:
Come away O human child
To the waters and the wild
With a fairy hand in hand
For the world's more full of weeping
Than you can understand
Your quest will be perilous,
yet the reward is beyond price.
In his book,
How Can a Robot Become Human?...
...Professor Allen Hobby writes of the power
which will transform Mecha into Orga.
Will you tell me how to find her?
KNOW:
Discovery is quite possible.
Our Blue Fairy does exist
in one place and in one place only.
At the end of the world,
where the lions weep.
Here is the place dreams are born.
Many a Mecha has gone to the end
of the world, never to come back.
That is why they call
the end of the world "Man-hattan."
[WHISPERS]
And that's why we must go there.
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
Wait!
What if the Blue Fairy
isn't real at all, David?
What if she's magic? The supernatural
is the hidden web that unites the universe.
Only Orga believe what cannot be seen
or measured.
It is that oddness that
separates our species.
What if the Blue Fairy is
an electronic parasite...
...that has arisen to haunt the minds
of artificial intelligence?
They hate us, you know. The humans.
They'll stop at nothing.
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
My mommy doesn't hate me.
Because I'm special and unique!
Because there's never been anyone
like me before, ever.
Mommy loves Martin because he is real.
When l am real...
...Mommy's going to read to me
and tuck me in my bed...
...and sing to me and listen to what I say
and she will cuddle with me...
...and tell me every day a hundred times
a day that she loves me!
She loves what you do for her...
...as my customers love
what it is I do for them.
But she does not love you, David.
She cannot love you.
You are neither flesh nor blood. You
are not a dog or a cat or a canary.
You were designed and built specific
like the rest of us.
You are alone now only
because they tired of you...
...or replaced you
with a younger model...
...or were displeased with
something you said or broke.
They made us too smart,
too quick and too many.
We are suffering for the mistakes they made
because when the end comes...
...all that will be left is us.
That's why they hate us.
And that's why you must stay here.
With me.
Goodbye, Joe.
POLICEMAN 1 :
Stay back. Stay back.
POLICEMAN 2:
Let's clear this doorway, please.
You're in bad trouble.
POLICEMAN 1 : Go about
your business now. Let's go. Move it.
[POWERS UP]
[WOMEN SCREAMING]
[CROWD SCREAMING]
Be careful, David. This is not a toy.
COMPUTER: Destination?
-Manhattan.
COMPUTER:
Mecha-restricted area.
-Manhattan.
COMPUTER: Destination achieved.
The lost city in the sea
at the end of the world.
DAVID:
"Where the lions weep."
[TEDDY GROWLING]
Turn around, Joe.
We're not gonna give up yet, David.
Turn all the way around.
DAVID:
Professor Hobby?
JOE: Come away O human child
To the waters and the wild
With a fairy hand in hand
For the world's more full of weeping
Than you can understand
[WHISPERS]
Professor Hobby?
Hello?
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
Hello!
Is this the place they make you real?
This is the place they make you read.
Are you real?
I guess.
Are you me?
-I'm David.
-You're not!
Yes, I am. I'm David.
So am I.
Hello, David.
Can you read?
Can you sit down
and we can read together?
Let's be friends.
[WHISPERS]
You can't have her.
I can't hear you.
She's mine. And I'm the only one.
[SHOUTING]
I'm David! I'm David! I'm David!
I'm special! I'm unique! I'm David!
You can't have her!
-I'm David. I'm David. I'm David.
HOBBY: David? David?
Yes, you are David.
Professor Hobby?
Yes, David. I've been waiting for you.
Dr. Know told me you'd be here.
Is Blue Fairy here too?
I first heard of your Blue Fairy
from Monica.
What did you believe
the Blue Fairy could do for you?
She would make me a real boy.
But you are a real boy.
At least as real as I've ever made one...
...which, by all reasonable accounts,
would make me your Blue Fairy.
You're not her.
Dr. Know told me she'd be here...
...at the lost city in the sea
at the end of the world.
That's what Dr. Know needed to know
to get you to come home to us.
And it's the only time we intervened.
The only help that we gave him...
...to give to you...
...so you could find your way home to us.
Until you were born,
robots didn't dream...
...robots didn't desire
unless we told them what to want.
David, do you have any idea
what a success story you've become?
You found a fairy tale, and inspired
by love, fueled by desire...
...you set out on a journey
to make her real.
Most remarkable of all, no one taught
you how. We actually lost you for a while.
But when you were found again,
we didn't make our presence known.
Our test was a simple one.
Where would your self-motivated
reasoning take you?
To the logical conclusion
the Blue Fairy...
...is part of the great human flaw
to wish for things that don't exist...
...or to the greatest single human gift...
...the ability to chase down our dreams?
And that is something no machine
has ever done until you.
I thought l was one of a kind.
My son was one of a kind.
You are the first of a kind.
David?
My brain is falling out.
Would you like to come meet
your real mothers and fathers?
The team is anxious to talk to you.
I want you to wait here.
I'll gather them up.
We want to hear everything
about your adventures.
We want to thank you...
...and tell you
what's in store for you next.
Mommy.
I saw it, Joe. I saw it.
The place where she lives.
She's right down there, Joe.
-She is?
-She's waiting for me. We have to go!
[PENDANT BEEPING]
Uh-oh.
When you become a real boy, remember
me to the ladies when you grow up.
-Goodbye, Joe.
-Goodbye, David.
[BEEPING]
I am.
I was!
TEDDY:
David, please be careful.
-The Blue Fairy's all right.
-What happened?
-I don't know.
-We are in a cage.
Blue Fairy?
Please.
Please, please, make me
into a real, live boy.
Please.
Blue Fairy?
Please...
...make me real.
Blue Fairy, please.
Please make me real.
Please make me a real boy.
Please, Blue Fairy.
Make me into a real boy.
Please....
MAN: And David continued to pray
to the Blue Fairy there before him...
...she who smiled softly forever.
She who welcomed forever.
Eventually, the floodlights dimmed
and died...
...but David could still see her,
palely, by day.
And he still addressed her, in hope.
He prayed until all the sea anemones
had shriveled and died...
...he prayed as the ocean froze...
...and the ice encased the caged
amphibicopter and the Blue Fairy too...
...locking them together
where he could still make her out...
...a blue ghost in ice.
Always there.
Always smiling.
Always awaiting him.
Eventually, he never moved at all...
...but his eyes always stayed open...
...staring ahead forever all through
the darkness of each night...
...and the next day...
...and the next day....
Thus, 2000 years passed by.
[IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
Teddy, we're home.
Mommy?
Mommy!
We're home!
Where are you?
WOMAN [WHISPERS]:
David!
[SINGSONGY]
[WHISPERS]
David.
[SINGSONGY]
BLUE FAlRY: You have been searching
for me, haven't you, David?
For my whole life.
BLUE FAlRY: And what, after all this time,
have you come to ask me?
DAVID: I have a wish to make.
-And what is your wish?
Please make me a real boy...
...so my mommy will love me
and let me stay with her.
BLUE FAlRY:
David, I will do anything that is possible...
...but I cannot make you a real boy.
DAVID:
Where am I?
This looks like my house,
but it is different.
BLUE FAlRY: Yes, it is different.
But it's also your home.
We read your mind and it's all here.
There's nothing too small that
you didn't store for us to remember.
We so want you to be happy.
You are so important to us, David.
You are unique in all the world.
Will Mommy be coming home soon?
Is she out shopping with Martin now?
David, she can never come home...
...because 2000 years have passed...
...and she is no longer living.
Dearest David, when you are lonely...
...we can bring back other people
from your time in the past.
If you can bring back other people...
...why can't you bring back her?!
BLUE FAlRY: We can only bring back people
whose bodies we dig up from the ice.
We need some physical sample
of the person...
...like a bone or a fingernail.
David.
Yes, Teddy?
Do you remember when you cut
some of Mommy's hair?
Henry shook me.
And you dropped her hair?
I know.
Now you can bring her back...
...can't you?
Give him what he wants.
BLUE FAlRY:
Dearest David, your wish is my command.
Hey, Joe, what do you know?
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
[KNOCKING CONTINUES]
David, I often felt a sort
of envy of humans...
...of that thing they called spirit.
Human beings had created a million
explanations of the meaning of life...
...in art, poetry, mathematical formulas.
Certainly human beings must be the key
to the meaning of existence.
But human beings no longer existed.
So we began a project...
...that would make it possible to re-create
the living body of a person long dead...
...from the DNA in a fragment
of bone or mummified skin.
We also wondered,
would it be possible...
...to retrieve a memory trace
in resonance with a re-created body?
And you know what we found?
We found the very fabric
of space-time itself...
...appeared to store information
about every event...
...which had ever occurred in the past.
But the experiment was a failure.
Those who were resurrected only lived
through a single day of renewed life.
When the resurrectees fell asleep
on the night of their first new day...
...they died again.
As soon as they became unconscious,
their very existence...
...faded away into darkness.
So you see, David,
the equations had shown...
...that once an individual space-time
pathway had been used...
...it could not be reused.
If we bring your mother back now...
...it will only be for one day...
...and then you will
never be able to see her again.
Maybe....
Maybe she will be special.
Maybe she will stay.
I thought this would be hard
for you to understand.
You were created to be so young.
Maybe the one day will be like
that one day inside the amphibicopter.
Maybe it will last forever.
SPECIALIST:
David, you are the enduring memory...
...of the human race.
The most lasting proof of their genius.
We only want for your happiness.
David...
...you've had so little of that.
If you want for my happiness...
...then you know what you have to do.
Listen.
[BIRDS TWEETING]
Can you hear that?
The new morning has come.
Go to her, David.
She's just waking up this instant.
I found you.
-Hi.
I must have dozed off.
-How long--?
-Would you like some coffee?
Just the way you like it?
Yeah, I'd love a coffee.
It'll wake me up.
Okay.
You never forget how, do you?
No.
I never forget.
I must be a little confused.
What day is it?
It is today.
SPECIALIST: As the day wore on, David
thought it was the happiest day of his life.
All the problems seemed to have
disappeared from his mommy's mind.
There was no Henry, there was no Martin.
There was no grief.
There was only David.
[BOTH LAUGH]
SPECIALIST: David had been warned
not to explain anything to Monica...
...otherwise she'd be frightened,
and everything would be spoiled.
But David's journey home
belonged only to him.
So he didn't see the harm of painting her
pictures of things she'd have no memory of.
[DAVID & MONICA YELL THEN LAUGH]
SPECIALIST:
David had never had a birthday party...
...because David had never been born.
So they baked a cake
and lit some candles.
-Now make a wish.
-It came true already.
SPECIALIST: By now, indeed,
the windows were beginning to dim.
David drew the shades without
even needing to be asked.
I really ought to be tucking you in.
How strange.
Hmm.
How fascinating.
I can hardly keep my eyes open.
I don't know what's come over me.
Such a beautiful day.
I love you, David.
I do love you.
I have always loved you.
SPECIALIST: That was the everlasting
moment he had been waiting for.
And the moment had passed,
for Monica was sound asleep.
More than merely asleep.
Should he shake her,
she would never rouse.
So David went to sleep too.
And for the first time in his life...
...he went to that place...
...where dreams are born.
[ENGLISH - US - SDH]
All the time, everywhere...
everything's hearts
are beating and squirting...
and talking to each other
the ways I can't understand.
Most of the time,
they probably be saying:
"I'm hungry. I gotta poop."
But sometimes they be talking in codes.
Get out the way.
Get your pants on, man.
Feed up time! Feed up!
Feed up time!
Share with the dog.
Ain't that ugly over there?
We got the prettiest place on earth.
Daddy says, up above the levee...
on the dry side,
they're afraid of the water...
like a bunch of babies.
They built the wall that cuts us off.
They think we all gonna
drown down here.
But we ain't going nowhere.
The Bathtub has got more holidays
than the whole rest of the world.
Yeah!
Yeah! Yeah!
Daddy always saying...
that up in the dry world,
they got none of what we got.
They only got holidays once a year.
All babies in the race,
come up to the starting line.
They got fish stuck in plastic wrappers.
They got their babies stuck in carriages.
And chicken on sticks
and all that kind of stuff.
One day, the storm is gonna blow...
the ground is gonna sink
and the water is gonna rise up so high...
there ain't gonna be no Bathtub.
Just a whole bunch of water.
Yeah!
But me and my daddy,
we stay right here.
We's who the earth is for.
Meat. Meat, meat, meat.
Every animal is made out of meat.
I'm meat. Y'all asses meat.
Everything is part of the buffet
of the universe.
This here is an aurochs...
a fierce, mean creature
that walked the face of the earth...
back when we all lived in the caves.
And they would gobble them
cave-babies down...
right in front of the cave-baby parents.
And the cavemans,
they couldn't even do nothing about it...
because they was too poor
and too small.
Who up in here think
that the cavemans...
was sitting around crying
like a bunch of pussies?
Y'all better think about that
because any day now...
fabric of the universe
is coming unraveled.
Ice caps gonna melt,
water is gonna rise...
and everything south of the levee
is going under.
Y'all better learn how to survive now.
Way back in the day...
the aurochs was king of the world.
If it wasn't for giant snowballs
and the Iced Age...
I wouldn't even be Hushpuppy.
I would just be breakfast.
Daddy?
Feed up time.
Daddy!
Kids that got no mama,
no daddy and nobody...
they gots to live in the woods...
and eat grass and steal underpants.
If Daddy don't get back soon...
it's gonna be time for me
to start eating my pets.
Daddy?
- That taste good?
- Yeah.
Hey, my baby, you need a ride?
No, my dad come and pick me up.
Well, what about some food
or something, darling?
You hungry?
All right, then.
Well, suit yourself, okay?
Everything we still got from Mama,
I keep in my house.
Daddy says the first time
she looked at me...
it made her heart beat so big...
that she thought it would blow up.
That's why she swam away.
Hi, my sweet baby.
Hi, Mama.
Hushpuppy, what you doing there?
You being good like I taught you?
Yes, Mama.
You're good
You make me happy
That's pretty, Ma.
You're pretty, Hushpuppy.
Get out of my way, you fat animal.
Daddy.
Daddy! Daddy!
I learned lots of things
while you were gone.
If I drink all this here,
I can burp like a man.
- Why are you wearing that dress?
- Leave me alone, man.
You wearing a bracelet too?
Go to your house.
You wouldn't understand.
- I want to come to your house.
- Get out of here!
- I want to come--
- Go ahead!
Get down from there.
Get over here.
Feed up time!
Come on, man! Feed up!
Boss lady!
Hushpuppy, where you at?
Where you at, boss lady?
If Daddy kill me,
I ain't gonna be forgotten.
I'm recording my story
for the scientists in the future.
In a million years,
when kids go to school...
they're gonna know, once,
there was a Hushpuppy...
and she lived with her daddy
in the Bathtub.
Hushpuppy!
Where you at, man?
Boss lady, goddamn it!
Come here!
Don't you run away from me!
I swear to God!
Get your ass back here!
I'm tearing off!
I'm tearing off just like my mama!
I'm gonna bust your ass!
Come here!
- Come here!
- No!
See what happen.
See what happen to you.
No!
I got to worry about you all the damn time!
You killing me!
Get up and now come on!
I hope you die.
And after you die, I'll go to your grave
and eat birthday cake all by myself.
Mama, I think I broke something.
Get over here!
Come on, let's go! Come on!
Miss Bathsheeba!
My daddy fell down.
Oh, God. Come on, baby.
Be okay.
Hushpuppy, take this medicine.
You run fast as you can. Go.
Daddy could've turned into a tree.
Or a bug.
There wasn't any way to know.
The whole universe...
depends on everything
fitting together just right.
If one piece busts,
even the smallest piece...
the entire universe will get busted.
The storm's coming! The storm's coming!
The storm is coming!
Hey, Walter. What it is?
Afraid of a little water?
I ain't messing with you, Wink.
I'm getting out of here.
You can stay if you want,
but I'm out.
Hey, now. What's up?
Look at these assholes...
running around all over the damn place.
C'est la vie, assholes.
- Hey.
- Ho! There's my boy, Wink!
- We gonna do this storm?
- Let me tell you.
These assholes go up and down here
all day long.
- That's what I'm talking about.
- We ain't leaving. I'm behind you.
- Man, I don't mind telling you, I am scared.
- Just leave.
- This ain't no little one.
- Damn pussy.
I'm leaving here
soon as I finish my beer.
No, you're not. You're gonna stay here with me.
I'll see you tomorrow, Walrus.
- Y'all want to die, okay, fine.
- Look at Winston.
Winston, I know you with me, huh, man?
What you gonna do
about the storm, man?
- Hey, Hushpuppy.
- Hushpuppy?
Get that girl a beer.
Where you been?
- What happened to you?
- Shut up.
You don't talk.
Come here!
Come here, ugly!
Just because you burnt
your house down...
don't mean you can walk in here
and take over.
This side of the house
is still Wink's side.
No toys, no girl stuff over here.
And if I want to come over there
and smack you in the face...
that's against the rules,
so that's a plus for you.
So come on down here
and get in the boat.
Come on, get in the boat!
Get in the boat.
And if the water gets real high,
we're gonna float to this roof...
we're gonna bust through the ceiling
and we're gonna ride away, okay?
Now I want you to put these on, okay?
Slide your arm through here.
Don't you never, never take these off.
I'm your daddy and you're gonna do
what I tell you to do...
because it's my job
to keep you from dying, okay?
So sit back and listen to me.
And close your eyes.
Go to sleep.
Go to sleep!
Why you staring at me like that?
How I'm supposed to sleep
with you staring at me like that?
What, you scared?
I'm gonna show you,
no storm can't beat no Doucet.
We Doucets.
We not scared of no damn storm!
I'm gonna show you.
I'm gonna take care of that storm.
I'm coming to get you, storm!
Look at me! Look at me, Hushpuppy!
Look at me whip butt!
Come on, storm!
Come on!
I'm gonna get you!
Come on, I'm right here!
I'm right here! Yeah!
Yeah! Yeah!
Mama!
Mama?
For the animals that didn't have a dad
to put them in a boat...
the end of the world already happened.
Winston!
Yo, Winston!
They're all down below,
trying to breathe through water.
Yo, Edison, you in here?
Someday, when I'm gone,
you gonna be the last man in the Bathtub.
You're gonna have to learn
how to feed yourself.
Now stick your hand in this water.
Stick it in there.
Okay, what you do is
you hold your hand steady...
and you just wait on your fish to come.
You gotta ball your fist up, okay?
That's your punching hand.
Ball your fist up, case you have
to whack him when he come out.
All right, all right.
Oh, got it, got it!
Yeah! Oh, Lord!
Look what we got!
Gotcha. We got it! Say, "I gotcha!"
- I gotcha!
- Yeah!
Hold him down.
You hold him down like this...
and you whack him good
with your fist.
Go ahead, whack him!
You whack him good.
Hold him like that and whack him.
Hold it.
Don't worry about that.
That's all a part of it.
Come on, you want to try it again?
Come on, one more time.
Mama?
Is that you?
I've broken everything.
Strong animals know
when your heart is weak.
That makes them hungry,
and they start coming.
Yo, Walrus.
Hey, man.
Come on, I gotcha. All right, partner.
I knew you wasn't gonna leave.
I must've passed out.
Little Jo.
- Hey.
- You okay, huh?
What happened to you? Get up.
Come on.
He been talking all night long
how it's the last night on earth.
- Don't worry about him.
- Trying to touch my titties and shit...
right in front of Peter T over there.
- Oh, Peter T, my man.
- Hello.
Good to see you, man!
I knew you wasn't gonna leave me.
- Oh, no. Oh, no.
- That's one classic dude right there.
You a titan, man.
Yeah! Glad you stayed, man.
If I had a pair of wings,
I know I could have flown in that bad boy.
Almost blew off Walrus' panties.
But I would probably
have bounced off a tree.
Hushpuppy.
Did I ever tell you the story
about your conception?
Jesus.
One day, when me and Hushpuppy mama first met...
we were so shy,
we used to sit around...
and drink beer and smile at each other.
One day, I got so shy, I just napped.
Back when Daddy used to talk about Mama...
he said she was so pretty,
she never even had to turn on the stove.
She'd just walk into the room...
and all the water starts to boil.
Your mama battered that gator up
and set it to frying.
And Hushpuppy popped into the universe
about four minutes later.
I got it under control.
Miss Bathsheeba!
Come on, y'all.
Come on, girlie! Come on!
Yeah, yeah! Come on!
- That's it.
- Thank you.
- Thank you. Very nice.
- Look what we got.
We got the fresh catch today.
You like that, babe?
Yeah! Come on!
Come on, children,
I got some for y'all too.
Yeah! Let's go. Time to eat.
For the ones we never find,
we make a funeral the Bathtub way.
Yeah, tastes like more.
Come on. All right.
With no crying allowed.
Yes, to the water!
Come on, boy! Come on!
Pick that goddamn thing up!
Let's go!
Okay.
So I say to myself...
I'm gonna pee in my pants just a little.
Hell, when the water goes down...
I'm gonna French kiss the dirt.
The water ain't going down, man.
That's my beautiful place
under that water.
Everything beautiful is gone.
Man, you know they got salt in that water,
done ate everything up.
Trees are gonna die first,
then the animals, then the fish.
You gotta think about moving.
I got it under control.
Come here, Hushpuppy.
Come sit by your Uncle Jean.
Let me show you how to do this.
Here. Here, baby.
Don't be scared of it, now.
Now, turn it upside-down.
There you go.
Now, push it with your thumb.
Good girl. That's it.
And then, real careful,
take this knife and you pop this off.
That's beautiful.
No, Hushpuppy!
Beast it.
Beast it!
Show me you can do it!
- Come on, I know you can do it.
- Come on!
- Beast it!
- Come on, now!
Beast it! Beast it! Beast it!
Beast it. Beast it.
Come on, now! Beast it!
Yeah!
Come on! Yeah! Yeah!
You see what kind of family we got?
We got feeling!
You're an animal!
Yeah, you're an animal. Yeah.
Yeah!
It wasn't no time to sit around
crying like a bunch of pussies.
We're gonna make a camp
right on top of the Bathtub.
We got enough animals to eat
until the water goes down.
Like this.
Smoother. Gentler.
Yeah, that's right. Right there.
It's gonna be all right.
Okay. Okay.
That's the most important thing
I can ever teach y'all.
Y'all got to learn how to take care of people
smaller and sweeter than you are.
You got it.
You okay?
Two weeks later,
everything started to die.
Got to get something out of this water.
Walrus, you want to leave the Bathtub?
No.
I heard that.
Nobody is leaving the Bathtub.
You don't know nothing.
This water gonna kill us here.
We gotta do something about this.
I ain't starving to death while them people
going grocery shopping and all that.
Shit. Son of a....
Boss, Daddy got to go
take care of something.
I'm gonna fix everything the way it was.
- Where are you going?
- Don't worry. I'm the man.
We gonna win.
And if anything go wrong,
Walrus is daddy.
You gonna be the king of the Bathtub.
I promise that.
Just sit right there. I'll be back.
I think they be gone.
I really can't say where.
What are you talking about?
They go to the levee?
- Ain't no problem.
- Don't make me slap your ass!
You so much as piss on that wall,
you know what them people gonna do?
They gonna find us
and stick us in a damn shelter.
Daddy says brave men don't run
from their home.
Peter T, hold onto the boat.
You're gonna be fine.
Peter T, you hold the trip wire. Okay?
- Get the line over there.
- Okay.
The entire universe depends on
everything fitting together just right.
If you can fix the broken piece,
everything can go right back.
Come on, baby!
Peter T...
hand me that trip wire.
I'm so sorry, but....
Peter T, you drop the trip wire?
Well, yes, I did.
- Peter T.
- I gotta go find it.
Get over here!
What are you doing, woman?
I'm hauling your ass home, little boy.
Get off!
Touch that wall,
they gonna come after us.
You don't know nothing!
Jean Battiste! Get the trip line!
Get in the boat!
Get your ass in here!
Hushpuppy!
Pull!
- Pull, pull!
- Now, boss!
- No!
It didn't matter
that the water was gone.
Sometimes you can break something so bad...
that it can't get put back together.
Mama!
This is a mandatory evacuation area.
You can no longer live here.
I repeat, this is a mandatory evacuation area.
When you're small,
you gotta fix what you can.
Goddamn!
What the hell wrong with you?
What you doing?
What you gonna do now, huh?
Oh, you want to throw things, huh?
All right, I can do that too.
Come on, then.
You want to play the game?
Come on, let's throw stuff. Come on!
I can do that too! So come on.
You want to throw stuff? Come on!
Come on.
Come on!
Gotcha. Come on, come on!
Gotcha. Come on! Come on!
Come on.
Man, you think I don't know.
You think I can't see?
No crying.
No crying, man! Hey!
Goddamn it, I said no crying!
Come on, get a drink.
This counts as I'm sorry
for a whole bunch of things, Lord.
You gonna be dead?
No.
You gonna leave me alone?
No, I ain't gonna leave you alone.
Because if you be gone,
I be gone too.
No, that's not how it work.
Sometimes in the bed...
I start to shake and I can't stop.
I got what you got.
No, that's just a side effect
of you being a stupid little girl.
I ain't gonna be dead?
No, you'll probably live
a hundred years more.
Come on, let me see them guns.
Come on. Show me them guns.
Let me see them.
Come on, show them to me.
Show them to me.
Show me them guns!
Show them to me! Guns!
Guns! Guns! Guns!
Gun! Guns! Come on. Come on.
Come on!
Come on! Let me have it!
You the man! Who the man?
- I'm the man.
- Yeah, you the man!
- Who the man?
- I'm the man!
- You the man! Who the man?
- I'm the man.
- I'm the man! I'm the man!
- Yeah, you the man! Fuck this table. Shit!
I got to go lay down.
I got to get strong.
Don't be scared.
What?
Come on.
Lay down.
- Hey.
- Yeah?
You ain't the one that's sick.
Strong animals got no mercy.
They're the type of animals...
that eat their own mamas and daddies.
- Think someone is in there?
- I don't know. This is a freaking shack.
Go check around the back.
There's no one in there.
Look at this place.
- Will you please open the door?
- Get back.
This is a mandatory evacuation area.
Everyone in this region has to leave.
We ain't going nowhere!
Sir, we have food and shelter.
- Kick it in.
- Go around the back.
Let's go. Get in there.
Just remain calm.
Son, you want me to cancel
your birth certificate?
- Grab her arm!
- Son of a bitch!
- Get your hands off of me!
- Hold her down. Hold her down!
- Stay down, sir.
- Stay down!
- Let her go! I'm gonna kill you!
- You have her?
Let her go!
- Keep still.
- Let her go!
It didn't look like a prison.
It looked more like a fish tank
with no water.
They said that we were here
for our own good.
You're supposed to hear me!
I want an answer!
I don't have an answer.
The doctor is gonna have to give you that.
Don't eat that, hear?
Mr. Doucet, can I have a word with you?
We found something in your test.
- It's urgent--
- Whoa, whoa. Not in front of my kid.
Stay there, Hushpuppy.
- The procedure is--
- I said not in front of my kid.
The procedure is very risky.
There's really no way to guarantee
it will be successful.
In case anything happens....
- Get your hands off me.
- If we don't do this, you could die.
- I tell you! I don't need nothing from you!
- Hey, stop it!
- Mr. Doucet, calm down!
- Stop it! Come here.
I tell you! I tell you!
You don't tell me!
- Calm down!
- Let me go! Get your hands off me!
I don't need nothing from y'all.
Let me go!
Wink!
- Leave her alone!
- Let go of me!
Stop it!
Get off of me!
Daddy!
You're gonna have time-out.
Are you even listening to me?
When an animal gets sick here...
they plug it into the wall.
They're coming for you.
Daddy used to say that
if he ever got so old...
he couldn't drink beer
and catch catfish...
then I had to put him in the boat
and set him on fire...
so no one could come plug him
into the wall.
Dave.
Dave, help me out. Help me out.
Boss.
Get up. We busting out of here.
Come on.
Wait, there's a person out there.
Here you go.
Hey! Go home!
Come on, let's go!
Everybody get out!
Wait, wait, wait.
Let's go! Let's go!
- Make sure you put her somewhere good.
- Let me out of here! No! No!
Let me go!
- Let me off!
- Get off me!
You're trying to get rid of me!
Listen to me.
I'm not trying to get rid of you.
- Yes, you is.
- You don't understand!
I can't take care of you no more,
you understand?
I'm dying!
My blood is eating itself.
You know what that mean?
Don't be saying things about dying.
- Everybody daddies die.
- Not my daddy.
Yeah, your daddy.
I didn't want you to watch that, okay?
You understand?
Come on, let's go!
Let's get out of here!
Let's get out of here! Come on!
Come on, let's go!
Wait, wait, wait.
- Back up, back up.
- Girls, get back.
- Dad! Come on! Come on!
- Give him room to breathe.
Walrus, get me home.
Everybody loses the thing
that made them.
It's even how it's supposed
to be in nature.
The brave men stay
and watch it happen.
They don't run.
Come on!
I'm going by my mom.
That's a good place to go.
Which way are we going?
It don't matter, baby.
This boat will take you
exactly where you need to be.
It's that kind of boat.
Want a chicken biscuit?
They're good for you.
I've been eating these all my life.
I keep the wrappers in the boat
because they remind me of who I was...
when I ate each one.
The smell makes me feel cohesive.
I want to be cohesive.
I'm sure you will, baby.
No doubt in my mind.
Oh, hi.
Sergeant Major, how are you doing?
Hey, Miss Frankie.
Holy crap. You have toddlers.
- A whole litter of them.
- Oh, they are so cute.
They're so cute.
Hey, baby.
I'd work for you
I'd even slave for you
I'd be a beggar or a knave for you
And if that isn't love
It'll have to do
Until the real thing comes along
You need something, baby?
Well, what you want? You alone?
That's it?
Get in here.
Let me show you a magic trick.
Let me tell you something.
When you're a child,
people say that life...
is gonna be happy and hunky-dory
and all that bullshit...
but I'm here to tell you that it's not,
so you need to get that out your head right now.
Because, yeah, life is some
big old feast, but you...
ain't nothing but a stupid little waitress.
One day, everything on your plate
gonna fall on the floor.
And nobody gonna be there
to pick it up for you.
One day, it's gonna be all on you.
You understand what I'm saying?
So smile, girl.
Smile.
Because nobody like
a pity-party-having-ass woman.
The gator is magic.
You can take care of me.
Me and Daddy.
Don't know nothing about your daddy.
I can't take care of nobody but myself.
And if that isn't love
It'll have to do
You can stay if you want.
Until the real thing comes along
I'd gladly move
This is my favorite thing.
To prove my love, dear,
and its worth
I know.
If that isn't love,
It'll have to do
I can count all the times
I've been lifted.
I've been lifted on two fingers.
Wink! Bring my baby here!
We got to wash her up!
No, that waits.
All right, fatso, breathe some air.
I need to go home.
If that isn't love
It'll have to do
Until the real thing comes along
You're my friend, kind of.
I gotta take care of mine.
Real good.
No crying, hear?
No crying.
Don't you cry.
As I stand by the bayou,
I watch a ship as she disappears.
There, she is gone.
And we cry for this.
But she's not gone.
She's just as real as when she left me.
And somewhere else,
other voices are calling out:
"Here she comes."
And that is dying.
Here she comes!
When it all goes quiet
behind my eyes...
I see everything that made me...
flying around in invisible pieces.
When I look too hard,
it goes away.
But when it all goes quiet,
I see they are right here.
I see that I'm a little piece
of a big, big universe.
And that makes things right.
When I die, the scientists of the future...
they're going to find it all.
They're going to know...
once, there was a Hushpuppy...
and she lived with her daddy
in the Bathtub.
(English - US)
[THUNDER RUMBLES]
[THUNDERCLAP]
[MOTOR WHIRRING]
- [MOTOR STOPS]
- [SHOUTING] See how it's done?
- Yeah, I think I got the hang of it.
- You better.
Boss'll chew my head off
if these cores get messed up.
Don't worry.
We're at 26 feet.
You let Jason
operate the drill?
Yeah, he can
handle it.
[MOTOR SLOWS, STOPS]
[CRUNCHING]
[CRACKING]
I didn't do
anything!
Gimme your hand!
Let go of the drill!
Forget it, Jack!
It's too late!
You're not
gonna make it!
Jack!
Gimme your hand!
[YELLING]
I got you!
[ALL SHOUTING]
- What were you thinking?
- [SIGHS]
- What's happening?
- The whole damn shelf is breaking off!
That's
what's happening!
[CRACKING, RUMBLING CONTINUE]
JACK: What we have found
locked in these ice cores...
is evidence of a cataclysmic
climate shift...
which occurred around
10,000 years ago.
The concentration of these natural
greenhouse gases in the ice cores...
indicates that runaway warming
pushed the planet into an ice age...
which lasted two centuries.
- [SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
- I'm confused.
I thought you were talking
about global warming, not an ice age.
Yes, it is a paradox, but global warming
can trigger a cooling trend.
Let me explain.
The northern hemisphere owes its temperate
climate to the North Atlantic current.
Heat from the sun arrives at the equator
and is carried north by the ocean.
But global warming is melting the polar
ice caps and disrupting this flow.
Eventually,
it will shut down.
And when that occurs,
there goes our warm climate.
Excuse me. When do you think
this could happen, Professor?
- When?
- I don't know.
Maybe in a hundred years.
Maybe in a thousand.
But what I do know is
that if we do not act soon...
it is our children and our grandchildren
who will have to pay the price.
And who's going to pay
the price of the Kyoto Accord?
It would cost the world's economy
hundreds of billions of dollars.
With all due respect,
M r. Vice President...
the cost of doing nothing
could be even higher.
Our climate is fragile.
At the rate we're burning fossil fuels
and polluting the environment...
the ice caps
will soon disappear.
Professor, um, Hall...
our economy is every bit
as fragile as the environment.
Perhaps you should keep that in mind before
making sensationalist claims.
Well, the last chunk of ice
that broke off...
was about the size
of the state of Rhode Island.
Some people might call that
pretty sensational.
[MEN CHUCKLING]
[PEOPLE SHOUTING]
Stop global warming!
MAN: I'm here at the Global Warming
Conference in New Delhi...
where, if you can believe
your eyes, it's snowing.
The coldest weather
on record...
has thrown the city into chaos
with numbers of homeless people...
Taxi! Taxi!
I enjoyed your testimony, Professor.
It was very spirited.
Oh, thank you. It's what we're here for,
right? Put on a good show?
Quite. Uh, I was wondering
if I could talk to you...
about your theory
on abrupt climate shift.
The name's Rapson.
Terry Rapson.
- Professor Rapson? Of the Hedland Center?
- That's me.
I've read your work
on ocean currents.
- What do you say to a spot of tea?
- Absolutely.
- If we can hail a cab.
- Oh.
[LOUD WHISTLE]
Over here!
- [THUNDER RUMBLING]
- [BELL CLANGING]
- MAN: Welcome back to Glasgow, Scotland...
- [BEEPING]
Where Manchester United
leads 3-1 over hometown Celtic...
- [MAN SNORING]
- in this pivotal champions' league match.
We return to the action 63 minutes
into the second half...
as Manchester United looks
to put the game out of reach.
[SNORING LOUDER]
Let's get back to our commentator,
Donald MacFarland.
What? Yeah.
I-I just closed
my eyes for a sec, man.
- Yeah.
- Baby kept us awake all night.
Leads to Roy,
and still!
Yeah!
- [BEEPING CONTINUES]
- [COMMENTATOR CONTINUES, INDISTINCT]
Dennis, NOMAD buoy 4311
is showing a temperature drop...
of 13 degrees.
- Hmm? Where is 4311?
- Well, it's, uh...
Georges Bank.
Oh, it's rough seas out there.
Must've knocked it about.
- [SHEEP BLEATING]
- [GULLS SQUAWKING]
[TELEVISION CHATTER CONTINUES]
Kick the bloody ball!
Come on! Come on. Kick it.
- Kick it! Kick it!
- Are the lads winning?
Hello, Professor.
How was India?
You know what these
scientific gatherings are.
- All dancing girls, wine and parties.
- [MEN CHUCKLING]
- [THUNDERCLAP]
- [ANNOUNCEMENT IN JAPANESE]
[ANNOUNCEMENT CONTINUES]
- [SIRENS CHIRPING]
- [SPEAKING JAPANESE]
- [CELL PHONE RINGING]
- [WOMAN ON PHONE SPEAKING JAPANESE]
- [SPEAKING JAPANESE]
[WOMAN CONTINUES]
[PEOPLE SCREAMING]
[GROANS]
WOMAN: The fury of Hurricane Noelani
stunned weather experts yesterday...
- slamming into the unprepared island chain...
- [PHONE RINGING]
With a cataclysmic force
never before witnessed.
- Meteorologists already believe this...
- [RINGING CONTINUES]
To be the strongest
hurricane ever recorded...
- a storm that will surely...
- Are you gonna get that?
- Hello?
- I just saw that Sam got an "F" in Calculus.
I'm aware, Jack.
I get a copy of his report card, too.
Well... Sam is a straight "A" student.
He doesn't fail classes.
All right. I don't have time to talk
about this right now.
JACK:
Well, maybe you oughta make time.
Excuse me. I'm not the one who's away
for months and months at a time.
[SIGHS]
I just don't understand.
I'll let him explain it to you. Can you
take him to the airport in the morning?
Sam's getting
on a plane?
He joined the scholastic decathlon team.
They're competing in New York.
- Sam joined a team?
- Yeah, I think there's a girl involved.
- Oh.
- Look. Can you pick him up at 8:30?
I gotta go,
'cause I'm on call tonight.
Jack, please don't be late. I don't want him
to have to take a taxi again.
All right. Okay.
I'll be there. Okay?
I'll be there.
[SIGHS]
WOMAN: [ON P.A.] I This morning's
weather staff meeting has been moved...
to level4, conference room "B."
[WOMAN CONTINUES, INDISTINCT]
Jack!
I know you have an innate talent for
rubbing people the wrong way, Jack...
but why, for the love of God,
would you aggravate the vice president?
Because my 17-year-old kid
knows more science than he does.
Perhaps, but your 17-year-old kid
does not control our budget.
- It doesn't matter if he hates you.
- My son doesn't hate me.
You're missing the point.
What I'm trying to tell you is that...
- if Raymond Becker pulls our budget... Where...
- Oh, shit!
Jack!
[HORN BEEPING]
- Oh, my God.
- [HORN BEEPING]
- Hi, Sam. I'm sorry I'm late.
- Dad, it's fine.
- The cab's already here.
- That's okay. I'll take care of it.
- What are you gonna...
- Here you go.
JACK:
I'm not angry. I'm disappointed.
- SAM: Do you wanna hear myside of it?
- How can there be two sides?
I got every question right
on the final.
The only reason Mr. Spengler failed me was
'cause I didn't write out the solutions.
Why not?
- I do 'em in my head.
- Did you tell him that?
I did.
He didn't believe me.
He said that if he can't do them in his head,
then I must be cheating.
Well, that's ridiculous! How could he
fail you for being smarter than he is?
That's what I said.
You did?
- How'd he take it?
- He flunked me, remember?
Oh. Yeah.
Sam, I'm sorry.
I jumped to conclusions.
I'm gonna call this guy,
have a word with him.
We're gonna get this whole thing
straightened out.
- Don't worry about it.
- Sam!
Sam!
MAN:
Parker, this is Houston.
We're seeing some bad weather
over Canaveral.
Doesn't look like
you're coming back this week.
[CHUCKLES]
Your wife's gonna give me an earful.
Roger that.
MAN #2:
Hey, come take a look at this storm system.
It's enormous.
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
[THUNDERCLAP]
You all right?
He's afraid of flying.
I'm fine.
[P.A. DINGS]
You know, statistically...
the chance of a plane going down because of
turbulence is less than, what? One in a billion?
Or is it a million?
- I can't remember if it's a million...
- Shut up, Brian.
Listen, Sam.
Don't pay attention to him, okay?
Everything's fine.
They're still serving drinks.
- [P.A. DINGS]
- MAN: Folks, it appears we're gonna...
have a little bit of a bumpy ride here
for the next few minutes.
Please fasten your seat belts
and put your tray tables and seat backs...
in their upright positions
until we get through this.
Thank you.
- Whoa!
- Grab it! Grab it!
WOMAN:
Watch out!
- [HYPERVENTILATING]
- [PEOPLE SHOUTING]
[ENGINES WHINING]
[ENGINES SLOW]
GIRL:
Sam?
- Sam.
- Hmm?
Can I have
my hand back?
I can't believe I'm spending two weeks
alone with my mum.
Be patient with her, all right? She's been
looking forward to this holiday for months.
- I know.
- [BOTH CHUCKLE]
- I love you.
- I love you too.
Hey. Hey, hello.
Bye-bye.
MAN: The cause of this extreme weather
remains a mystery...
although some meteorologists
believe sunspots are to blame.
This is very odd.
There's a buoy here registering
a 13 degree drop in ocean temperature.
Oh, yeah. That's right.
That buoy malfunctioned
the other day.
I'll put a call in, see if there are any ships
near Georges Bank to get it.
This buoy isn't in Georges Bank.
It's just off Greenland.
MAN:
What?
What are the odds
of two buoys failing?
Remote.
Make that three.
[HORNS HONKING]
MAN: Just another typical day
in New York City.
Traffic jam 10 blocks long.
Looky here, Buddha. These people
and their cars and their exhaust.
They're just pollutin'
the atmosphere!
Excuse me, sir.
We're really late.
- We're almost there.
- We're only two blocks away.
Let's walk.
- [BARKING]
- [BIRDS CALLING]
[BARKING]
- [ROARING]
- What's got into them?
- [ANIMALS HOWLING, CALLING]
- I have no idea. They're all worked up today.
[HOWLING]
In 1532, Spanish Conquistador
Francisco Pizarro...
defeated this Incan Emperor at the Peruvian
highland town of Cajamarca.
What is his name? Time.
- Montezuma.
- No, no.
Montezuma was in Mexico,
not Peru.
It's like
Anta something.
- Atahuallpa?
- That's it!
- [BUZZER SOUNDS]
Time's up.
Correct answers, please?
- That's five points for Woodmont...
- [CROWD CHEERING]
And five points
for Pinehurst Academy.
Next question.
In what year
did Louis Quatorze...
ascend to the throne
of France?
[POP]
This place is so retro.
- It might actually be cool if it were on purpose.
- Hmm.
And look at
all these nerds.
Hey!
Hey.
You look beautiful.
Thanks.
This place is incredible.
Do you believe that
this is their cafeteria?
You played
a great first round.
So did you.
These are my teammates,
Sam and Brian.
- I'm Laura.
- I'm J.D.
- Your school is amazing.
- Would you like... Would you like a tour?
Sure. That'd be great.
Could you hold this for a sec?
Yeah. Sure.
Thanks.
Man, you got
some serious competition.
SAM:
Please.
- I'll bet he's really rich, too.
- Shut up.
[PHONE RINGING]
- Who is it?
- Terry Rapson here. Sorry to call you so early.
No, Professor.
That's all right. What is it?
Well, we've found
something extraordinary...
extraordinary and disturbing, that is.
You recall what you said
in New Delhi...
about how polar melting might disrupt
the North Atlantic current?
Yes.
Well...
I think it's happening.
- What do you mean?
- One of our NOMAD buoys...
registered a 13 degree drop
in surface temperature the other day.
- I sent you an e-mail.
- Hold on.
At first we thought
it was a malfunction...
but there are four more across
the North Atlantic showing the same thing.
JACK:
This is unbelievable.
You predicted
it would happen.
Yes, but not in our lifetime.
This is too fast.
There are no forecast models
remotely capable of plotting this scenario...
except yours.
My model is a reconstruction
of a prehistoric climate shift.
- It's not a forecast model.
- It's the closest thing we have.
Nothing like this
has every happened before.
At least not in
the last 10,000 years.
As I predicted yesterday, the swell
off Hurricane Noelani is incredible.
These waves are even bigger
than I imagined. Just take a look.
[RINGING]
Shouldn't you be monitoring
the weather or something?
This is L.A.
What weather?
- [MOTOR RUNNING, FAINT]
- Wait. What's that noise?
What noise?
[MOTOR RUNNING, LOUDER]
- [MOTOR STOPS]
- [PHONE RINGING]
[SIGHS]
Honey, I'll be right back.
WOMAN:
The coastguard has closed the beaches...
as waves have been too big
for even the most experienced of surfers.
- L.A. Weather Center.
- It's Tommy! I'm down at the beach!
I'm in the middle of something.
What do you need?
There... Ooh! Uh.
There's... There's hail the size of golf balls
coming down here!
- [TOMMY CONTINUES, INDISTINCT]
- MAN: Low pressure system moving along...
the California coastline is creating
a cyclonic system across the L.A. basin.
[PHONE RINGING]
- Yeah. Hello.
- Hey, boss, turn on the Weather Channel.
I think we have to issue
a tornado warning.
What are
you talking about?
WOMAN:
Palmdale and Lancaster are reporting...
- windspeeds in excess of 70 miles per hour...
- Hold on a second.
Conditions that are
highly unusual for California.
Tom, we're building a forecast model.
We're gonna need what?
Priority access to the mainframe
for two days, maybe three.
- Oh, is that it? Anything else?
- We need it immediately.
I would say that
you've lost your mind...
but you've been this way
for the past 20 years.
Tom,
this is important.
What is this forecast model you're building,
if you don't mind my asking?
TOM:
Janet Tokada, this is Jack Hall.
Janet's a, uh, hurricane
specialist with NASA.
Jack's a paleoclimatologist, and I have
absolutely no idea what he's up to.
Booker!
What's going on, here?
They just issued a tornado warning
in Los Angeles.
MAN: Breaking news,
as we prepare to go live to Los Angeles.
- Mixed reports...
- The report's just come in.
Some extreme weather
occurring in the area.
Okay, we're now going live
to our Fox affiliate in Los Angeles.
WOMAN: We have live coverage now
from our Fox 11 chopper.
- Are you there, Bart?
- Uh, yes, I'm here.
These tornadoes are forming
so fast... What?
BART:
Oh! Oh, my God! Lisa...
Are you getting this on camera? This tornado
just came and erased the Hollywood sign.
The Hollywood sign is gone.
It's just shredded.
- [WIND ROARING]
- [PEOPLE SCREAMING]
LISA: Bart, what can you see?
Is anyone hurt?
BART: I wouldn't be surprised. There
is so much damage down there.
And there are people
down there taking pictures!
Hey! What the hell
are you guys doing!
Go for cover! You can't stay here!
Get outta here!
What you're seeing are two actual tornadoes
striking Los Angeles International Airport.
Wait. Wait. It looks like they've joined
and formed one large tornado.
- Tommy!
- Oh, my God!
MAN: Urge all of our viewers
to stay away from the area.
- Jeff, where are you?
- I'm on, uh, Yucca and Vine.
I'm on my way in now.
Jeff, you're on TV!
You're right in the middle of it!
God. Oh, my God!
You gotta get
out of there, man!
Oh.
BART: That bus just got dropped
on top of that Porsche!
- [LINE BUSY TONE]
- Oh, my God. I hope no one was in that car!
WOMAN: And for our national audience
just joining us now...
we are going live
to downtown Los Angeles right now.
- Tommy?
- If you look over there behind me,
that's a tornado.
Yes! A twister
in Los Angeles.
It's one of the many tornadoes
that are destroying our city.
There's another one!
That's the Los Angeles skyline!
It's unbelievable! It's huge!
I've never seen anything like that!
[GASPING]
What's happening?
It-It-It looks like
some sort of huge...
horrific, terrifying nightmare,
only this is the real thing!
[RUMBLING STOPS]
[WIND HOWLING]
[CAR ALARMS BLARING]
Yes, I-I'm looking
at it right now.
- Yes, it is.
- What's happening, Raymond?
I'll call you back.
Mr. President.
Los Angeles has been
devastated by a series of tornadoes.
On top of that, the F.A.A. wants your approval
to suspend all air traffic.
What do you think
we should do?
Until we can figure out what's going on here,
I don't think we have much choice.
WOMAN: What you're seeing is what's
left of downtown Los Angeles.
Hey, man, I just got off the phone
with my mom.
Um, excuse me, you guys. I'm really sorry,
but we need to change the channel.
[CHATTERING]
WOMAN: The F.A.A. has grounded all
air traffic in the United States.
Unfortunately,
the order came too late...
for two planes that were brought down
by severe turbulence in the Midwest.
So much
for one in a billion.
[CHATTERING]
All right. All right.
Listen up, everybody.
Listen up, please. We've got a lot of work
to do and we don't have much time.
So, let's get started,
please. Vorsteen?
All our grid models
are worthless.
I don't think grid models
are gonna be a lot of help here.
The Canadians are reporting tremendous
circulation moving down from the Arctic.
In Siberia, there's a low pressure system
unlike anything we've seen...
and Australia just saw
the strongest typhoon ever recorded.
MAN: Hang on. Are you saying that
these things are interconnected?
BOOKER: We have to consider
the possibility.
The only force strong enough
to affect global weather is the sun.
- What's NASA have to say?
- We've already checked. Solar output is normal.
- What about the North Atlantic current?
- VORSTEEN: What about it?
I got a call last night from Professor Rapson
at the Hedland Center.
He thinks the current
has changed.
[MURMURING]
Come on, Jack.
How could that be?
The current depends upon
a delicate balance of salt and fresh water.
- We all know that.
- Yes.
But no one has
taken into account...
how much fresh water has been dumped
into the ocean because of melting polar ice.
I think we've hit
a critical desalinization point.
[MURMURING]
It would explain
what's driving this extreme weather.
Hedland had some pretty
convincing data.
They've asked me to feed it into my paleoclimate
model to track the next set of events.
Hold on, Jack. Are you suggesting these
weather anomalies are gonna continue?
Not just continue...
get worse.
I think we're on the verge
of a major climate shift.
[MURMURING]
Tom! What are you gonna tell
the administration?
What do you expect me
to tell them?
The government has to start making
long-term preparations now.
- Jack, all you have is a theory.
- Then give me the mainframe
and let me prove it!
No.
You have 48 hours.
- [SIGHS]
- Professor Hall.
- Yes?
- I think your theory may be correct.
Walk with me.
Just a few weeks ago, I monitored
the strongest hurricane on record.
The hail, the tornadoes...
it all fits.
Can the model you're working on
factor in storm scenarios?
- Oh, we haven't had the time.
- Maybe I can help.
- Welcome aboard.
- Thanks.
- Hi, I'm Jason.
- Hi.
Ow!
Do you have the results
of Peter's C. T. scan?
Yeah, the treatment
shrunk the tumor 20%.
- Is his eyesight better today?
- No. No change.
Hey, Peter.
How you doin' today?
- A little better.
- Good.
Let me listen here.
Can you read that?
No, but I remember
the story from the pictures.
- You do?
- My mother used to read it to me.
She must be very proud of you.
You've been such a brave, big boy.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
- Here you go.
- Thank you.
Jack, you've been working
for 24 hours straight...
- the only one who hasn't taken a break.
- [SIGHS]
Maybe I'll try
to shut my eyes for a while.
Call me when you
get the results.
- Frank, is he always so obsessive?
- TOGETHER: Yes.
- Does he ever lighten up?
- No.
- Not really.
How long have you been
working together?
Well, uh, Frank's been working with him
since the Stone Age.
I've only had to endure
two years of servitude.
Jack. Jack.
We got the results.
Six to eight months.
That can't be.
That time scale isn't in months.
It's in weeks.
MAN: Widespread flooding
has slowed transportation...
and caused numerous closures,
including the Lincoln and Holland Tunnels.
The plumbing in the school
is really old.
With all this rain,
the sewage got stopped up.
Where are you staying
tonight?
They're finding us a place to stay with kids
here in New York City.
Are you sure you can't get home
any sooner than tomorrow?
Well, look, Dad,
I would if I could, you know.
It's just, uh...
Ugh! This smell
is unbearable, Dad.
- Stop kidding around. I want you home.
- Dad, I'll be on the train.
Do me a favor, okay?
Just don't worry about me. I'll figure it out.
[SIGHS]
All right, son. I'll see ya tomorrow.
Hey, Sam. Guess what.
We got a place to stay.
Great.
So far, the terrible weather
hasn't hit the D.C. area...
but local residents
aren't taking any chances...
as people stock up
for what is already being billed...
as the worst storm season
on record.
You better be sure about this, Jack.
My ass is on the line.
- You saw the model.
- And I hope to God it's wrong.
- Oh. Mr. Vice President.
- Tom.
- You know Professor Hall.
- Yes, we've met.
Uh, Professor Hall has some new information
I think you should take a look at.
We just got these results
from our simulation model.
They explain what's causing
the severe weather.
I'll look at this later. I have a meeting
with the director of FEMA now.
This is very urgent, sir.
Our climate is changing violently.
It's going to happen
over the next six to eight weeks.
I thought you said this wouldn't happen
for another hundred years or so.
- I was wrong.
- Well, suppose you're wrong this time.
I wish that I were, but I'm sure that you're aware
of what's happening all around the world.
We're making all the necessary preparations
for this storm. What more do you expect?
You have to start thinking about large scale
evacuations right now...
especially in
the northern states.
- Evacuations?
- Yes.
Have you lost your mind, Hall?
I have to go.
Mr. Vice President, if we don't act now,
it's going to be too late.
Come on, Jack.
Hey, thanks for
bringing us here.
I couldn't let you leave New York
without seeing the Natural History Museum.
Of course not. It's the world's finest
collection of stuffed animals.
Hey, guys.
Check this out.
"The body of this mammoth was found
perfectly preserved in the Siberian tundra...
"with food still
in its mouth and stomach...
indicating that it froze
instantly while grazing."
MAN: It's been 24 hours now since
the snow started falling...
across the British Isles
and over northern Europe...
and it shows no signs
of letting up.
No. No, no, no.
You gotta stop worrying. No.
It's fine. We got plenty of supplies with us.
We're just snowed in.
Yeah. No, it's all right.
It's all right.
You stay where you are, okay?
I'll be fine.
Yeah, I love you too. Okay. Bye.
[SIGHS]
- Hey. How's Jeanette?
- Oh, fine.
- Ferry just landed.
- Must be nice in Spain. I wish I was there.
REPORTER: [TV] The search and rescue team
has been deployed by helicopter...
to airlift
the royal family to safety.
You think they'll come get us,
since we got snowed in?
Not likely.
Luckily,
we got our own genny...
enough tea and biscuits
to sink a ship.
Oh, we'll be fine.
As long as the loo doesn't back up again.
[ALL CHUCKLE]
In Ireland, those remaining in Belfast
and Banbridge have been urged to evacuate...
to Dublin as soon
as possible.
The north continues
to receive the worst of the storm...
[HELICOPTER APPROACHING]
MAN: We've got zero visibility.
Maintain heading and speed.
- MAN #2: What's our heading?
- Zero, three, five, sir.
Approximately 40 kilometers
from Balmoral Castle.
MAN:
We've lost visual contact with you.
This gauge here
can't be right.
MAN #3:
Wind speed has dropped to zero.
We have vertical walls
of cirrus cloud formations.
MAN:
What the hell is going on?
Bloody fuel lines
are starting to freeze!
[MEN SHOUTING]
Port engine pressure's dropping!
The rotor R.P.M. is dropping!
We've got a flame-out
on the starboard side as well!
Prepare
for crash landing!
Select emergency fuel!
Come on,
you bastard!
Come on!
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
RAPSON: What I'm about to tell you
is supposed to be confidential.
Several hours ago,
three helicopters went down over Scotland.
They crashed because the fuel
in their lines froze.
At what temperature does...
RAPSON: [ON SPEAKER] Negative 150 degrees
Fahrenheit. We had to look it up.
The temperature dropped
phenomenally fast.
On the ground, people froze before
they could get out of their cars.
- Get me a satellite picture
of Scotland two hours ago.
- Yeah.
We've got mountains of data but nowhere
near enough computer power to analyze it.
- Can you help us?
- Send us what you've got, and we'll do our best.
RAPSON:
Thanks, Jack. Bye for now.
This is Scotland at the time
the temperature dropped.
FRANK:
This thing looks just like a hurricane.
JANET:
Only hurricanes don't form overland.
- Good evening, sir.
- Hey, Harold.
- Thanks, Victor. I'll see you in the morning.
- Right, sir.
- Terrible weather.
- Tell me about it.
Wow.
You live here?
Just on the weekends.
It's my dad's place...
and he's kind of
never around, so...
Where is he?
Skiing in Europe
with my stepmom.
Is this you
and your brother?
Oh, yeah. That's when
we took a bike trip together.
It's been raining like this
for three days now.
[THUNDERCLAP]
[HORNS HONKING,
PEOPLE SHOUTING]
- I'm just standin' here.
- You can't stay here.
- I never liked this neighborhood anyway.
- [DOG BARKING]
It's a mob scene here
at Grand Central Station.
Over half the platforms
are flooded...
and service has been
suspended on all trains.
With planes still grounded
and trains now out of service, that's bad news...
Victor's coming to pick me up. Do you guys
want a ride to the train station?
- Stranded since this morning.
- Not anymore.
In Nova Scotia earlier, the ocean rose
by 25 feet in a matter of seconds.
What we have feared for the past few days
has indeed happened.
The cold front moving down
from the Arctic...
has created an enormous
storm system in Canada...
which, incredible as it sounds,
looks like a tropical hurricane.
I gotta go pick up my little brother.
Do you guys want a ride?
- Where is he?
- He's in a boarding school in Philadelphia.
If this system moves south,
we could see a wind-driven storm surge...
that could threaten
the entire Eastern Seaboard.
Okay. Bye. Victor's stuck
in traffic on Fifth Avenue.
It'll be easier to head out of town
if we meet him over there.
- All right.
- You mean walk? No, not in this.
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
We should take
the stairs.
We're on the top floor.
I guess we're walkin'.
[THUNDERCLAP]
[HORNS HONKING,
PEOPLE SHOUTING]
- Maybe we should just stay here.
- I think the young lady is right, sir.
No. We need to get home.
Come on!
[SHOUTING CONTINUES]
[GOATS BLEATING]
[GROWLS]
Hey, Cesar, come here.
What are you doing?
The wolves!
They're gone!
MAN: [ON NEWS]
Just to give you an idea of the situation...
which seems to be becoming
worse with each passing minute...
at the moment, we have flooding
in most parts of the island.
We've got traffic snarl-ups
because the electricity is now out...
to almost every part
of Manhattan.
No traffic signals,
car accidents... at least 200...
and Lower Manhattan, we've been
told, is virtually inaccessible.
MAN:
No one is to be on the streets. Please go inside.
- [EXCITED CHATTERING]
- Sir, just calm down.
Public library's right up here. Make your way
up there. You can stay warm and dry.
[CHATTERING CONTINUES]
Sir, just take it easy.
Um, can you call Mom?
Please phone her for me.
- Hey.
- [BLUBBERING]
That dog can't come in here.
Come on, man.
It's pouring out there.
I don't care.
Read the sign.
It's supposed to be
a public library.
[EXCITED CHATTERING]
Come on, guys.
This way.
Excuse me.
Your bad.
Goddamn $ 1,500
waterproof raincoat!
Please shut up, man.
- There must be rats everywhere.
- That's 'cause it's New York.
Hey! Hey!
Open up, big poppa!
It's out of service.
It's out of service!
- No, no. I'll give you $ 100 to put it in service.
- You don't have to do that.
No, no. Really, $200.
I won't have it. I won't have it.
Oh, God, I love buses.
This is just so much fun.
- [SHOUTING]
- Hello?
I can't reach my driver.
I lost the signal.
This is insane. We should just go back
to your apartment.
BRIAN:
Yeah. I vote for that.
What? Are you kidding?
We have to get higher!
Come on.
Up to the library.
- MAN: Calm down!
- [SHOUTING IN FRENCH]
I can't understand
what you're saying.
- [SHOUTING CONTINUES]
- Just stay calm, ma'am. I will get you out.
[SCREAMS]
MAN:
The door is jammed!
- [SHOUTING CONTINUES]
- I don't speak French.
[SCREAMING]
[SHOUTING CONTINUES]
[THUNDERCLAP]
- Hey, where is Laura?
- [WOMAN SPEAKING FRENCH]
- She was just right there.
- She's right there! Right there! See?
What... What is she doing?
- Tell them to cover their eyes.
- [SPEAKING FRENCH]
- [FRENCH]
- [GRUNTS]
- [CHILD SCREAMS]
- [THUNDERCLAP]
MAN: [ON NEWS] There is a wall of water
coming towards New York City!
Everybody...
[SHOUTING, SCREAMING]
- [WOMAN SCREAMS]
- [SHOUTING CONTINUES]
- [SHOUTING IN FRENCH]
- What's the problem?
She left her bag in the cab.
Their passports.
OFFICER:
Forget about it!
- I'll get it for her.
- Come on!
Oh, my...
Laura!
- No! No!
- No, Sam! Sam, no!
- Laura! Laura! Laura! Come on!
- [GASPS]
Come! Come on!
- Sam!
- Go!
[DOG BARKING]
Professor.
Thank you.
[CHUCKLES]
Is that Neville's handiwork?
Neville's way beyond
stick figures. He's six already.
- Hmm.
- No. This masterpiece...
belongs to my second
grandson, David.
Can't believe
Neville's six already.
You won't believe
how fast they grow.
Professor, I've got
Jack Hall on the phone.
They've run the data
we've sent them.
Here he is.
Jack, were you able
to re-create the thermal cycle?
Yes. The storm's rotation is pulling super-cooled
air down from the upper troposphere.
But shouldn't the air warm up
before it reaches ground level?
It should, but it doesn't.
The air's descending too rapidly.
Is this
an isolated incident?
I'm afraid not.
We've located two other supercells
in addition to the one over Scotland.
There's one over Northern Canada
and another one over Siberia.
And do we know
their projected path?
Yes. Our previous estimates of six
to eight weeks weren't even close.
This one storm is going
to change the face of our planet.
Here's a projection
of 24 hours out.
This is 48 hours out.
Andin seven to 10 days.
When this storm is over,
we'll be in a new ice age.
My God.
Professor, it's time
you got out of there.
I'm afraid that time
has come and gone, my friend.
What can we do?
Save as many as you can.
[FEEDBACK ON LINE]
[DISCONNECT SIGNAL]
[PHONE RINGING]
Jack. Something's
happened in New York.
No. The power is out.
I've been in here all day.
- OFFICER: Who needs help?
- Over here. Over here.
- [INDISTINCT SHOUTING]
- Hi.
- MAN: Hello.
- [DOG WHIMPERING]
What?
This is the last one.
Enjoy it. Greedy.
OPERATOR:
All circuits are busy.
Listen. Thanks
for coming back for me.
It was really brave.
I guess I better
return her bag.
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
Sam? Just tell her
how you feel.
Yeah.
[DIALING PHONE]
Did you reach
your little brother yet?
No. There's still no service.
Damn cell phones.
- Excuse me.
- Yes?
- Are there any payphones on the upper floors?
- No. No.
- But there are some on the mezzanine.
- Great.
- But I think it's underwater.
- Where are you going?
- The power's out.
- Older pay phones draw their
power directly from the line.
[WOMAN ON P.A., INDISTINCT]
Oh, God. I've been trying
to reach Sam.
- So have I.
- I kept trying to call you,
but I couldn't get through.
It's been a madhouse
around here. Come on.
Are you sure about this?
Ah. Oh.
- [DIAL TONE]
- It works.
I love that picture.
Yeah. So do I.
- Where was that taken?
- Miami.
Well, where was I?
I don't remember that trip.
Sam and I went with my sister.
You were in Alaska,
doing research on your doctorate.
- [SIGHS]
- Remember what he was like
when he was that age?
[CHUCKLES]
Everything was "one more."
One more bedtime story.
One more ride on my shoulders.
"One more, Daddy."
Jack? Sam's on the phone.
Line four.
- Sam?
- Dad!
- Where are you? Are you all right?
- We're at the public library.
Sam, it's Mom.
I'm so happy you're okay.
Mom, can you call Laura and Brian's parents
and tell them we're all right?
Yes. Of course.
- Sam, what's that noise?
- Sam? Sam?
[GASPING]
What is going on out there, Dad?
Sam? Sam, listen to me.
Listen very carefully.
Forget what I said
about trying to head south.
It's too late for that.
The storm is just gonna get worse.
It's gonna turn into a massive blizzard
with an eye in the center, like a hurricane.
- Uh-huh.
- The air is gonna be so cold...
you could freeze to death
in seconds.
- Sam?
- What should we do?
Listen to me, son.
Do not go outside.
Just burn whatever you can
to stay warm and try to wait it out.
I will come for you.
Do you understand me? I will come for you.
[SHIVERING]
Sam! Sam, come back!
JACK:
Sam? Sam, did you hear me?
Did you hear me?
Sam?
[SOBBING]
Tell me he's gonna be okay.
He's gonna be all right. He's gonna be all right.
Do you understand me?
[SOBBING CONTINUES]
[GASPING]
[SHIVERING, PANTING]
[SOBBING]
I thought you drowned.
- Let's find some dry clothes for you.
- Yeah.
Where did you store
the arctic gear?
You can't make it
to New York, Jack.
I've walked that far
before in the snow.
This is not the same.
Jack, this is not the same!
Lucy, tell him.
I have to do this.
I know.
My hands are shaking.
Shaking.
That's okay. Here.
Here. Come here.
Wh-Wh-What are you doing?
I'm using my body heat
to warm you.
If we let the blood from your arms and legs
rush back to your heart too quickly...
your heart could fail.
Where... Where did you learn that?
[SHIVERING]
Some of us were actually
paying attention in health class.
How are you feeling?
Much better.
Frank told me about Sam.
I'm not gonna try
to talk you out of going...
but there's something
I need for you to do first.
You have to explain your results
to the administration.
- I already tried that.
- I know this time will be different.
You're gonna brief
the president directly.
OFFICER:
Is that the last of it?
- LAURA: Yeah. Pretty much.
- Okay.
We also found this radio,
but I don't think it works.
Let me see it.
[BARKING]
Buddha, be quiet!
You ain't even supposed
to be in here anyway.
- [BARKING CONTINUES]
- [LOUD RUMBLING]
[RUMBLING CONTINUES]
[BARKING CONTINUES]
Come on, guys.
Oh, my God.
[GLASS SHATTERING]
The basic rule of storms
is that they continue...
until the imbalance
that created them is corrected.
In this case, we're talking
about a global realignment.
The superstorm will
last seven to 10 days.
When it's over, ice and snow will cover
the entire Northern Hemisphere.
The ice and snow
will reflect sunlight.
The earth's atmosphere
will restabilize...
but with an average temperature
close to that of the last ice age.
What can we do about this?
[SIGHS]
Head as far south as possible.
That is not amusing,
Professor.
Where do you suggest
they go?
The farther south they go,
the safer they'll be.
Texas. Parts of Florida that aren't flooded.
Mexico would be best.
Mexico? Maybe you should stick to science
and leave policy to us.
Well, we tried that approach. You didn't
want to hear about the science...
when it could
have made a difference.
What exactly are you
proposing, Professor?
Evacuate everyone
south of that line.
What about the people
in the north?
I'm afraid
it's too late for them.
If they go outside,
the storm will kill them.
At this point...
their best chance
is to stay inside...
try to ride it out...
pray.
What do you think he'll do?
I don't know.
Jack, thanks.
And good luck.
You too.
We're all gonna need it.
We can't evacuate
half the country...
because one scientist
thinks the climate is shifting.
Every minute we delay
is costing lives.
What about the other
half of the country?
If Professor Hall is right, sending troops north
will create more victims.
We need to save the people
we can right now.
We take the same approach
in triage on the battlefield.
Sometimes it's necessary
to make difficult choices!
I don't accept that abandoning
half of the country is necessary.
Maybe if you would've listened
to him sooner, it wouldn't be.
Bullshit. It's easy for him to suggest this plan.
He's safely here in Washington.
His son is in Manhattan.
I just thought you should know that before
you start questioning his motives.
We're going to follow
Hall's plan.
- General.
- Sir.
Give the order for the National Guard
to evacuate the southern states.
Yes, sir.
[DOOR CLOSES]
Vivian, uh,
get me my wife.
[WIND HOWLING]
[GENERATOR CHUGGING]
Sorry, mates, but we're
just about out of petrol.
Hey, is there any chance...
that it will run... on this?
- [CHUCKLES]
- Are you mad?
That's a 12-year-old scotch.
[LAUGHS]
Gentlemen. To England.
To mankind.
To Manchester United.
[ALL LAUGHING]
I just... I just wish I could've seen him
grow up, you know?
The important thing is
he will grow up.
Amen.
Maybe you should have
somebody help you with that.
Sir, I am president
of the electronics club...
the math club
and the chess club.
Now, if there's a bigger nerd
in here, please point him out.
I'll just leave you alone
to work on it.
Come on, Buddha. Come on.
Do your business.
Look. There's nobody around.
- [BUDDHA WHIMPERING]
- Okay. You know what?
I'll turn around. I won't look.
- I promise.
- [BARKING]
- [BARKING CONTINUES]
- What?
Hey, man. There's people out there.
I was walking my dog.
There's hundreds of 'em.
They're walkin' on the snow.
[CHATTERING]
OFFICER:
Where are they all going?
They're gettin' out of the city
before it's too late.
All right, everybody.
Quiet down.
When was the last time
anyone got a signal on a cell phone?
I got through to my cousin in Memphis an hour
ago. They're being evacuated to the south.
We should get moving too.
The water's frozen over enough to walk on.
We should get going before
the snow gets too deep.
Everyone, wrap yourselves
up as fast as you can.
- We shouldn't go.
- We're leaving in five minutes.
- Why not, Sam?
- When I talked to my dad, he
told me we should stay inside.
- The storm will kill anybody caught in it.
- Then you have to say something.
I know.
- OFFICER: Line up. That's it.
- [CHATTERING]
Excuse me, sir.
You're making a mistake.
What? Hey, listen, son. We're all scared here,
but we got no choice.
- That's not it.
- Get ready to go.
If these people go outside,
they will freeze to death!
- Okay. What is this nonsense?
- It's not nonsense, all right?
Look. This storm
is gonna get worse...
and the people who are caught outside,
they will freeze to death.
- Where are you getting this information?
- My father's a climatologist.
- What are you suggesting we do?
- We stay inside, we keep warm,
and we wait it out.
The snow is getting
deeper by the minute.
- We'd be trapped here without food, supplies.
- It's a risk. Yeah.
- An unnecessary risk.
- No, no, no. It's not.
We've wasted enough time talking about this.
Come on, people. Let's go.
Look. Look. Look.
Just look for a second.
- Come on, everybody. Let's get going.
- One second.
The storm is gonna get bad.
It's gonna get really bad.
You're not gonna be able
to survive in it.
Believe me.
Sir, please just stay.
Just stay.
Just don't...
I'm...
[WIND HOWLING]
She's set to go.
Come on.
Straight to the back, guys.
JACK: [ON PHONE]
It'll be impossible to reach each other.
Leave a message for me
at the American Embassy in Mexico City.
Okay. I will.
I love you.
I love you, Jack.
Tell Sam I love him so much.
God be with you.
[LINE DISCONNECTS]
- Dr. Hall?
- Yeah.
We haven't been able
to reach Peter's parents.
- I'm gonna try later, okay?
- Okay. Thank you.
I got it.
You're supposed to be
on a bus heading south.
I've been watching
your back for 20 years.
You think I'd let you
go alone?
All these years, I thought
I was watching your back.
- Where are the keys?
- In the truck.
Where do you think
you're going?
Neither one of you
knows how to navigate worth a damn.
Without me, you'll
end up in Cleveland.
I'll try to give you updates on the storm
as it heads your way.
Good luck, Jack.
[ENGINE STARTS]
WOMAN REPORTING:
Breaking news from the U.S.-Mexico border.
Just half an hour ago,
Mexican officials closed the border...
in the light of so many U.S. refugees
who are fleeing south...
in the wake
of the approaching storm.
These people came here
in anticipation of crossing into Mexico.
Instead, they've been met
with closed gates...
MAN REPORTING: And now, in a dramatic
reversal of illegal immigration...
thousands of people
are crossing the Rio Grande into Mexico.
The scene that's unfolding here behind me
is one of desperation and frustration.
People have abandoned their
cars, grabbed their belongings...
and they are wading across
the river illegally into Mexico.
Here it is.
Oh, this fireplace probably hasn't been used
in about a hundred years.
All right.
- What are you doing?
- What do you think we were gonna burn?
- You can't burn books.
- No. Absolutely not!
You wanna freeze to death?
- I'll go get some more.
- I'll help you.
I'm going with them.
Okay. Do you have
a cafeteria or a lunchroom?
Just an employees' lounge
with a few vending machines.
[BUDDHA BARKING]
We're not gonna last very long
on M&M's and potato chips.
What about the garbage cans? There's always
somethin' to eat in the garbage.
[BUDDHA WHIMPERING]
Friedrich Nietzsche.
We cannot burn Friedrich Nietzsche.
He was the most important
thinker of the 19th century.
Oh, please. Nietzsche was a chauvinist pig
who was in love with his sister.
- He was not a chauvinist pig.
- But he was in love with his sister.
BRIAN:
Uh, excuse me. You guys?
Yeah. There's a whole section on tax law
down here that we can burn.
Afterhours of uncertainty, the traffic
is moving smoothly from the U.S. into Mexico.
This is only possible because the president
was able to negotiate a deal...
to forgive
all Latin American debt...
in exchange
for opening the border.
Now multitudes of American
families are feeling...
[QUIET READING]
- Lucy.
- [STOPS READING]
- Is Peter's ambulance here?
- No.
Why?
- They've all gone.
- What?
In the confusion...
I don't know what happened.
People just started
to panic, and they left.
Now, there's a policeman with a snowplow.
He's waiting outside.
Peter can't be moved
in anything but an ambulance.
I called and left a message for the county
ambulance service.
Okay.
You should go,
and I'll stay and wait.
Lucy, no. No.
You should go.
He's not gonna wait forever.
It's okay.
I'm sorry.
All right.
- [GASPS]
- Are you all right?
Yeah. I'm fine. I just
cut my leg the other day.
[RADIO STATIC]
Did you get a signal?
- Yeah. For a minute.
- And?
Man, this storm is everywhere.
It's hit the entire Northern Hemisphere.
Europe is buried
under 15 feet of snow.
And they say it's gonna
get just as bad here.
I mean, I don't think
your dad's gonna make it.
No. He'll make it.
He'll make it.
MAN: [ON NEWS]
The White House has ordered...
the following national disaster
alert for all northern states:
Continued exposure
to the approaching storm is deadly.
Remain indoors and take
all measures to stay warm...
burning any fuel sources
until the storm is over.
Roads are impassable
across New York State...
- and as far south as Pennsylvania.
- Where are we?
[MAN ON NEWS CONTINUES,
INDISTINCT]
Looks like we're
just north of Philadelphia.
MAN: [ON NEWS]
Rescue workers say they have no idea...
Look out!
You guys okay?
- Yeah.
- Once again, roads
across the northern states...
- Sorry, boss.
- Are impassable.
- Unpack the snowshoes.
We're walking from here.
Come on, men.
Let's get up and get going.
We've only made it to Brooklyn.
Maybe we should just turn back.
What for? Half the city's
frozen underwater.
- There's nothing to go back to.
- It's time to get up. Keep moving.
- We should've stayed in the library.
- Come on, men.
Okay, guys.
Let's get moving.
Wake up.
- What are you doing?
- Insulatin'.
Newspaper's best,
but this'll do it.
You know, you spend some years on
the streets, and you learn how to keep warm.
Hey.
Thanks.
I got one.
Your favorite vacation?
Besides this one?
[CHUCKLES]
All right.
I went to Greenland with my dad
on one of his research trips a few years ago...
and, uh, the ship broke down
and we got stuck.
And it rained constantly.
That sounds really boring.
It was actually really nice.
Just me and my dad
hanging out for 10 days.
[SIGHS]
[GRUNTING, SCREAMING]
[GROANING, WHIMPERING]
JACK:
Frank!
- Are you all right?
- I'm fine!
Just dropped in
to do a little shopping.
I gotta lose this sled.
Hold on!
We'll pull you up!
Jason! You gotta
support Frank's weight!
Okay! I'll try!
[GRUNTING]
Okay! I think
I have his weight now!
I'm coming to you!
[GLASS CRACKING]
[GRUNTING, WHIMPERING]
The glass is breaking!
Too much weight!
It's not gonna hold.
No! No!
Frank!
I can get you out!
JACK:
Don't do it!
- No! Frank! Don't!
- Frank, no!
Frank!
WOMAN:
What have you got there?
A Gutenberg Bible.
It was in
the rare books room.
You think
God's gonna save you?
No.
I don't believe in God.
You're holding on
to that bible pretty tight.
- I'm protecting it.
- [BOOK LANDS ON FIRE]
This bible is the first book
ever printed.
It represents...
the dawn
of the Age of Reason.
As far as I'm concerned, the written word
is mankind's greatest achievement.
- [SCOFFS QUIETLY]
- You can laugh.
But if Western civilization
is finished...
I'm gonna save at least
one little piece of it.
[RADIO: CHATTER]
We heard somebody
was left behind.
- [SIGHS]
- We brought an ambulance.
Thank God.
Thank you so much
for coming.
[SHIVERING]
[LAURA COUGHING]
Hey.
Hey, are you all right?
- You look like you have a fever or something.
- I'm fine.
I just can't sleep.
My mind keeps going over
all those worthless decathlon facts.
It's pretty stupid, huh?
No, it's all right. I guess you just haven't
had time to adjust yet.
How am I supposed
to adjust, Sam?
Everything
I've ever cared about...
everything I've worked for...
has all been preparation
for a future that no longer exists.
I know you always thought
I took the competition too seriously.
You were right.
It was all for nothing.
No... [SIGHS]
No, I just...
I just said that to
avoid admitting the truth.
The truth about what?
About why
I joined the team.
I joined it because of you.
Hey.
[RADIO: CHATTER, INDISTINCT]
Get this convoy
moving now.
[WHISPERING]
I know. I know.
- Mr. President.
- All right.
I'm sorry, sir.
We can't wait any longer.
We're the last ones.
All right.
PILOT:
Mexicali Control, this is Delta 2-6.
We're carrying an urgent message
for high command.
Request priority
on landing zone one.
- [CHATTERING, SHOUTING]
- [RADIO CHATTER CONTINUES, INDISTINCT]
Sir.
Thank you, Corporal.
Carry on.
Madam Secretary?
Raymond.
The president's motorcade
got caught in the storm.
They didn't make it.
She wouldn't
wake up this morning.
I-I... I mean, last night she only had a fever.
I don't understand.
God, she's awfully pale.
Well, guys, look. None of us has had anything
real to eat in days.
- JEREMY: I'm telling you, it's hypothermia.
- How could it be hypothermia?
- We've all been...
- Maybe it's just the flu, you guys.
No, no,
it's not the flu.
Yeah?
And how do you know?
Books can be good for something other
than burning. Let's go over her symptoms.
I told you. She has a fever
and a really cold sweat.
WOMAN:
How's her pulse?
It's really fast.
Did she have any injuries, like a cut
or something that might have gotten infected?
She was complaining
about a cut on her leg a few days ago.
I didn't... I didn't
think anything of it.
Oh, my gosh.
That's blood poisoning.
Um, septicemia.
She could go into septic shock.
I've seen that before.
That can get bad.
She needs a massive dose
of penicillin...
or a broad-spectrum
antibiotic immediately...
or...
Or what?
I've never seen anything like it.
There's no point of reference.
All I can see
is cloud cover.
What are you doing?
Taking infrared image
of thermal currents...
sent to Houston, Korolev...
your weather service.
PARKER:
I'll help you.
- Tom? Tom, wake up.
- [GROANS]
I just received some satellite images
from the space station.
You'd better take a look.
How big is this thing?
The vortex is 50 miles in diameter
and growing.
The two cells over Europe and Asia
are even bigger.
TOM:
Good God.
This one's gonna hit New York
inside an hour.
[GASPING, PANTING]
Jack...
Jason!
Are you all right?
[PANTING, GASPING]
[BARKING]
- What are you doing?
- There's gotta be medicine on that ship.
I thought you said
it was too dangerous to go outside.
I know I did.
Where'd you find
those chairs?
Why?
I'm going with you.
Me too.
[GASPS]
There!
- [LOCK RATTLING]
- Ohh! Come on!
Damn it!
- [GRUNTS LOUDLY]
- [GROWLING]
[GRUNTING CONTINUES]
[YELLS]
[PANTING]
- It's all in Russian. I...
- SAM: I know.
- H-H-Hey, guys, I found it.
- What? How do you know?
Because it says "penicillin"
on the bottom.
[GROWLING]
Wait. This is the mess hall. We should
find some food while we're here.
- We don't have time.
- None of us are gonna survive
without food, including Laura.
Okay.
[EXHALES, CLEARS THROAT]
J.D.:
Sam, over here!
What?
- Bingo.
- [LAUGHS]
[SAM LAUGHS]
[GLASS CLATTERING]
- [INFLATING LOUDLY]
- [YELLING]
SAM:
Brian?
- BRIAN: I'm okay.
- J.D.: I What happened?
Okay, okay. All I did
was open up a cupboard.
- [QUIET SNARLING]
- We can use it. Put food in it.
- [LOUD SNARL]
- [GASPS]
- [GROWLING]
- [PANICKED YELLING]
- [CONTINUES YELLING]
- [GRUNTING]
- Pull him in!
- [WOLF WHIMPERS]
- [WHIMPERING, GROWLING]
- You all right?
[J.D. GROANS]
My leg.
Here, use this.
[SHUDDERING, GROANING]
Oh, yeah. Here. Ohh!
It should be
over New York by now.
Satellite readings are showing
a temperature drop of 10 degrees per second.
SAM:
You guys, I think we're in the eye of it.
We gotta get back right now.
Look,
I'm gonna go outside...
and I'm gonna lure the wolves
out of the room.
- When they leave, you lock the door.
- Good luck.
- [CRUNCH]
- [GROWLING]
[YELLING]
Aah!
[GASPS]
[MUTTERING, GRUNTING]
[GROWLING, SNARLING]
Aah!
[PANTING, GASPING]
- [WOLF WHIMPERS]
- [PANTING]
[GROANS]
Brian, hurry!
[MUTTERING]
Come on! Hurry!
[SNARLING, GROWLING]
[GROANS, PANTING]
- [GROWLING CONTINUES]
- [BANGING ON DOOR]
Brian!
Brian, open the door!
We have to get out of here now.
Brian, get the supplies.
[GRUNTING, PANTING]
[ICE CRACKING]
Let's go!
Pull! Pull, Brian!
Come on! Pull!
Take the medicine to Laura!
[J.D. GROANING, YELLING]
- We're almost there, man! Come on! Aah!
- [GRUNTS]
Brian, close the door!
Don't let the fire
go out!
What's happening?
Buddha,
come away from the door!
Come, Buddha, come!
More books! More books!
How long
have I been out of it?
Couple hours.
How do you feel?
Okay.
What happened?
Well, we had to get inside in kind of a hurry,
so I sort of pushed you in.
I should be used to
you pushing me around.
Good to have you back.
What are you doing?
The eye of the storm
has passed...
and we're 40 miles
from Manhattan.
Shouldn't we wait
one more day?
Sam may not have
one more day.
What do you think's
gonna happen to us?
What do you mean?
I mean us.
Civilization.
Everybody.
Mankind survived
the last ice age.
We're certainly capable
of surviving this one.
All depends on whether or not we're able
to learn from our mistakes.
I sure as hell would like
a chance to learn from mine.
You did everything you could.
I was thinking about Sam.
Jack, you know
the chances of Sam...
I made my son a promise.
I'm going to keep it.
MAN: [ON RADIO]
Parker, this is Houston. Do you read?
Roger, Mission Control.
Go ahead.
We're getting scattered reports that the storm
is dissipating over North America.
Can you confirm?
PARKER:
Affirmative. It's finally clearing.
We're over Europe right now.
I can see landmass
for the first time in days.
How much further is it
to the library?
It should be...
right here.
I'm sorry, Jack.
Sam?
Who is that?
My father.
You made it.
Of course I did.
[CROWD SHOUTING]
[SHOUTING CONTINUES]
Mr. President.
I just received a shortwave radio
transmission from Jack Hall.
He made it to New York.
He says
there are survivors.
Thank you, Tom.
That's...
That's good news.
BECKER:
These past few weeks have left us all...
with a profound sense
of humility...
in the face of nature's
destructive power.
For years we operated
under the belief...
that we could continue consuming
our planet's natural resources...
without consequence.
We were wrong.
I was wrong.
The fact that my first address to you
comes from a consulate on foreign soil...
is a testament to
our changed reality.
Not only Americans...
but people
all around the globe...
are now guests in the nations
we once called the Third World.
In our time of need they have taken us in
and sheltered us...
and I am deeply grateful
for their hospitality.
BECKER CONTINUES: [TV]
We mourn the loss of a spirited leader...
- whose courageous orders
to evacuate to the south...
- Peter.
- Saved millions of lives.
- Hey. You feeling okay today?
For days now we have despaired about the fate
of the people who are trapped in the north.
Today there is
cause for hope.
Only a few hours ago
I received word...
that a small group of people
survived in New York City...
against all odds and in the face
of tremendous adversity.
I've ordered an immediate search-and-rescue
mission to bring them home...
and to look
for more survivors.
Jack!
It's good to see you!
Come on.
Let's go get on board.
Look at that.
What?
Have you ever seen the air
so clear?
God damn it.
Inside the room,
Dr. Doom, prepare for the boom, bam!
I slam
Scream like Tarzan
I be tossin' and flossin',
my style is awesome
I'm causing more family feuds
than Richard Dawson
And the survey said, you're dead
Fatal Flying Guillotine
chops off your fucking head
Mister, who is that?
Ayo, the Wu is back
Making... go Bo! Bo!
Like I'm Super Cat
Oh, no, here come
the Wu-Tang shogun
Killer to my eardrum,
put the needle to the groove
I gets rude and I'm forced
to fuck it up, my style...
More Afro than Rollo
coming to a fork in the road
Which way to go, just follow...
This is nuts! This is so crazy!
I've got a hard cider
and a bag of Crossbone Crunch.
It's a party.
I'm... I'm just so,
so thrilled for you, Kate.
To Comet Dibiasky, right?
Cheers!
It's gotta be, look...
It's gotta be an Oort cloud comet
just based on where you saw it.
Probably the last time
it was this close to the Sun
was long before human civilization.
Look at the arc on that thing.
God, it's amazing.
How would we find out the comet's
velocity in orbit, Professor Mindy?
That is a good question.
This will be fun. I haven't done
orbital dynamics since grad school.
Question is, what...
What would Carl Sagan do?
He would take it back to first principles.
The topocentric vector is rho.
Kate, what are the initial coordinates?
Twenty-one.
Twenty-four.
Thirteen.
This is fun, huh, guys?
- Sixty-seven.
- Now you got me pumped.
- Dr. Mindy.
- All right...
How many terms do you have to calibrate...
Approximation of coordinates
in Marsden, '85.
Now that we have the comet's orbit,
we will check the ephemeris
and that will give us the distance
between the comet and planet Earth.
Why does the ephemeris
keep getting lower and lower?
Professor Mindy?
You know what, guys? Let's...
Let's call it a night, huh?
But what about
the relative position?
I can't figure this one out.
Not tonight, guys. Sorry.
- Let's hit it, man. I'm beat.
- Me too.
- Kate, this was amazing.
- Congratulations.
Hey, Kate.
You stay.
Yeah, Dr. Calder,
a Michigan State professor
and his grad students...
This is Dr. Calder.
You pulled me out of a meeting
where I had to tell my team
we lost eight billion in funding.
I am so sorry, Dr. Calder,
but we are seeing some
awfully strange orbital numbers
on this comet we just found.
They should be in your inbox, right?
- Is this it?
- Yeah. This is it.
Oh, yeah. Yeah. Let me get
Dr. Oglethorpe on the line.
Please hold.
I'm on hold.
She's calling a Dr. Oglethorpe.
Who is that?
Jesus Christ.
I'm gonna put them on speaker.
Dr. Oglethorpe,
head of the Planetary
Defense Coordination Office.
- Is that a real place?
- I have no idea.
This is Dr. Oglethorpe.
Yes, this is Jocelyn Calder
from Kennedy Space Center.
Hey, Jocelyn.
Listen, we got a sighting
of an NEO from Subaru telescope.
Okay...
Why you just didn't report it
to the Minor Planet Center?
It's a professor
and a bunch of Michigan State students
who identified something big.
Really? How large?
How big we talking?
We clocked it in around
five to ten kilometers wide.
About five to ten kilometers wide.
That's a big boy.
And was this professor the one
who first made the observations?
Hi, yes. Dr. Mindy.
And... And no,
PhD candidate Kate Dibiasky found it.
I did the orbital calculations.
I... I study trace gasses
in dead galaxies.
I haven't published in a while
so you probably haven't heard of me.
But anyway, that doesn't matter.
Sorry. What was your question?
What are the most updated estimates
on its trajectory?
Kate?
I've been running it all day.
I keep getting the same result.
A direct hit of Earth
in six months and 14 days.
Me too.
Matthew,
what are your calculations?
Scout program
is saying six months, 14 days.
We got six months and 14 days.
And it's roughly five
to ten kilometers wide.
Which... Which...
Isn't that...
an extinction-level event?
Well, let's not be dramatic here.
Okay...
First move is to get
the school field trip out here to DC.
Let's all calm down.
I need the person who first had eyes
on the comet
and the person in charge.
What?
Share this data immediately
with Cambridge, Caltech and IAU.
Wait a minute.
This is classified information.
What's happening?
I serve
at the discretion of the president.
Is this really happening?
And the dead galaxy professor
to Hickam Air Force base.
DC, right?
Hey! Hey, Kate.
This isn't happening, right?
Kate, this isn't real, right?
This is...
This is just some sort
of alternate reality, right?
Say something.
I gotta go get high.
Word is that I need you both in DC fast.
Only plane I got going there is that one.
Anyway, I am Dr. Mindy. This is...
- Hi!
- Go, go, go!
- Where do we sit, Kate?
- I have no idea.
Is there
any customary seating for...
What the fuck? Is this real?
Is this a goddamn joke?
Holy shit.
This can't be happening. No.
- Brendon. You mean Brendon?
- Yeah, Brendon.
You know, he didn't keep his head down.
It's all politics, Teddy. You know that.
You must be Randall and Kate.
Yes. Yes, hi.
I'm Dr. Oglethorpe,
but you can call me Teddy.
I'm sorry. Did you say your name...
- I should call you Teddy? Teddy.
- Teddy. Yeah.
Yeah, we call him Teddy
because he ain't no teddy bear.
General Themes.
I'm the Pentagon's eyes on...
you know,
whatever this turns out to be.
The president is famously late,
and you've had a long flight, so...
Michigan State Spartans.
- Is that the Oval Office?
- Yeah, that's the Oval Office, yeah.
It's a lot smaller
than in the photographs.
The president
should be here shortly.
She's already been briefed.
Correct, Scott?
That is correct.
Are we really about to tell
the president of the United States
that we have just over six months
until humankind, basically every species,
is completely extinct?
Yeah. That's exactly
what we're about to do. Yeah.
Oh, gosh. Oh, gosh.
Yes, I said law enforcement.
But I didn't want... I mean,
you told me that he was clean.
- Hello, Madam President. Dr. Oglethorpe.
- Step back, please.
Hello.
Madam President, I'm Dr. Oglethorpe.
I believe Jocelyn briefed you to...
- Hey, Jason.
- Yeah? What up, yo?
Come on, man. What the hell?
This is real world.
Yeah. I know. We need five minutes.
We have a problem with our Supreme Court
nominee. Five minutes. Thank you.
Happy birthday to you
Happy birthday, dear Patty...
Just take a message,
and then, stuff like this happens,
and I don't know what's going on.
I don't understand
how many more times I need to tell you...
Well, there's a bunch of stuff about
their nominee not being qualified,
but I don't see
any articles about our thing.
Social media is just going on and on
about that singer Riley Bina
and DJ Chello breaking up.
That's just too bad.
They seem like sweet kids.
I don't... I don't know them.
Which is...
- It's a shame though.
- Yeah.
- Do you know them, Kate?
- Yes.
But I don't really give a shit right now.
They charge
an arm and a leg for this stuff.
Ten apiece ought to do it.
- Grab a water.
- Thank you.
I've got Kate as well.
- Perfect.
- Thank you.
Here's a 20.
- You got change?
- No.
- I mean, I could ask the Marine.
- Yeah...
It's a Xanax.
I only take a quarter.
Otherwise I get...
- Kate.
- Thank you.
You know, you should be
careful with that much.
This eagle's place is in the sky
I'm very sorry. I have to be
in Okinawa by two o'clock tomorrow.
- What?
- What? Are you serious?
- This is very important.
- I have to go quell the natives.
Tell your daughter I said hello.
Isn't it important that he was
in the room with us? I mean, what...
Where do I pay for these?
It's free.
Really?
Yes, it's the White House.
The snacks are free.
What?
The general.
He charged us
for the snacks, but they're free.
Oh, gosh.
Why on earth would he do that?
Hey, peeps, it's not looking
like it's gonna happen tonight,
and I feel horrible.
We're gonna put you up
in a hotel somewhere.
Excuse me, does the president
know why we're here?
You gotta be fucking kidding me.
They must not know
why we're here, right?
They know, but you heard 'em.
- Do they even realize...
- Be ready for tomorrow.
How long it took for us to get...
And then they made us wait
for over seven hours,
but they never called us in.
I couldn't believe it.
Of course they didn't call you in.
Kate, have you watched any news today?
No, I've been pretty wrapped up
in our... project.
Turn on your TV right now.
President Orlean is in
the middle of an all-time shit storm.
Sheriff Wade Conlon
was already a controversial nominee,
with no law degree and a record
of shoot first and ask questions later.
You watching?
With his background as a nude life model...
Yeah, I'm watching it right now.
The White House is in full crisis mode.
And, get this.
I found five former students
who are willing to go on record
that Conlon got noticeably aroused
when he posed for their drawing class.
I have no shame in what I did.
Now, should I say noticeably aroused?
Or engorged? Because
I don't want this to read like clickbait.
You know, this is a real article.
I just... Kate, can I get
something from you, please?
Sorry.
- Out of sorts tonight.
- Can we have this conversation?
I feel like we're skirting around this.
Do you have an issue with my mom?
Is that what this is all about?
You can't tell me what's going on?
It's just the protocol.
Please, don't worry.
Oh, Marshall got a 172
on his LSATs and we're celebrating.
Way to go, Marshall.
I'm proud of you, buddy.
Thank you, Dad. Miss you.
Hey, how's Evan feeling?
Are the new meds working out?
I'm a solid four.
He's a solid four.
Well, that's better
than last month, right?
You know, just remember to speak up
in the meeting tomorrow. Okay?
- Yeah. I will.
- You get so quiet.
When it's time to take credit,
you kind of...
She asked you if you were a lesbian.
She did not say that you were a lesbian.
- It was a question.
- Hey, look, I'm...
Can I sit down with your mom
to have lunch in, like, seven months?
Seven... That's weirdly
specific and distant.
What is... This is my mom.
So...
I heard there's an asteroid
or a comet or something
that you don't like the looks of.
Tell me about it and then
tell me why you're telling me about it.
You got 20 minutes.
- Twenty minutes?
- That's you, Doc.
Go. Now. Go.
Madam President.
Approximately 36 hours ago,
PhD candidate
Kate Dibiasky here discovered
a very large comet.
- Yeah.
- Good for you.
A comet between
five to ten kilometers across,
that we estimate came from the...
from the... from the Oort cloud.
Which is the outermost part
of the solar system.
And...
And using Gauss's method
of orbital determination
and the average astrometric uncertainty
of 0.04 arcseconds, we then asked...
- What the hell is... What?
- I'm so bored. Just tell us what it is.
- What? Stop what?
- Seriously, stop.
What Dr. Mindy is trying to say is
there's a comet headed towards Earth,
and according to NASA's computers,
that object is gonna hit the Pacific Ocean
at 62 miles due west
off the coast of Chile.
Then what happens? Like, a tidal wave?
No. It will be far more catastrophic.
There'll be mile-high tsunamis
fanning out all across the globe.
If this comet makes impact, it will have
the power of a billion Hiroshima bombs.
There'll be
magnitude 10 or 11 earthquakes...
You're breathing weird.
It's making me uncomfortable.
I'm sorry, I'm just trying
to articulate the science.
I know. But it's so stressful.
I'm trying to, like, listen...
I don't think you understand
the gravity of the situation.
I'm trying to articulate it
the best I can...
Madam President, this comet
is what we call a planet-killer.
That is correct.
So how certain is this?
There's 100% certainty of impact.
Please, don't say 100%.
Can we just call it
a potentially significant event?
- Yeah.
- Yes.
But it isn't potentially going to happen.
It is going to happen.
Exactly. 99.78% to be exact.
Oh, great. Okay, so it's not 100%.
Well, scientists never like to say 100%.
Call it 70% and let's just move on.
But it's not even close to 70%.
You cannot go around saying to people
that there's 100% chance
that they're gonna die.
You know? It's just nuts.
We should get some of
our scientists on this, you know.
No offense, but you're just two people
that walked in here with...
Dr. Oglethorpe.
Dr. Ov... Ogilvy. Yeah.
I've been head of planetary defense
at NASA for 15 years.
And Dr. Mindy is a tenured professor
of astronomy at Michigan State,
where Miss Dibiasky
is a doctoral candidate.
- Good.
- I'm sorry. Did you say Michigan State?
Exactly. They have
an excellent astronomy department.
- Yes.
- Come on, bro.
You kidding?
You wanna see my fucking SAT scores?
Okay, let's bottom line this.
What is this gonna cost me?
You know, what's the ask here?
There are government plans in place.
Actions we can take through NASA.
Drones that can be outfitted with nukes
to deflect and hopefully
change the orbit of this comet.
We must act now.
Oh, hey.
All right, all right, all right.
- When are the midterms? Three weeks.
- Three weeks.
So, if this breaks before then,
we lose Congress.
Then there's nothing we can do about it.
It'll be gridlocked.
The timing is just... It's atrocious.
Okay, at this very moment,
I say we sit tight and assess.
Sit tight and assess.
Let's get some other people
on this. Some Ivy Leaguers.
And you and I will review the NASA plans.
- Okay?
- I'd greatly appreciate that.
Am I to understand correctly that,
after all of the information
you've received today,
the decision you're making
is to sit tight and assess?
- I'm sorry, who is she?
- Who the fuck are you? Aren't you her son?
I'm the fucking Chief of Staff,
Boy with the Dragon Tattoo.
So I'm doing fine.
We gotta get out of here.
This place is a freak show.
I think what Miss Dibiasky
is trying to say
is that the idea of sitting tight
is an extremely, extremely dangerous...
Thank you.
One good thing happened today.
Okay, funny story.
When I was running for president,
I had to sneak cigarettes for
the whole first month of the campaign
because, you know,
photographs of me smoking
went for, what, a hundred grand a pop?
So, I'm always hiding, but,
you know, I just got sick of it.
And I just said, you know what,
I'm gonna smoke whenever I want to.
Guess what happened?
- I went up three points in the polls.
- They loved that she kept it real.
They love watching a smokeshow smoke.
I can't think of another president
that I'd ever wanna see in Playboy.
Do you know how many
the world is ending meetings
that we've had over the years?
Economic collapse, loose nukes,
car exhaust killing the atmosphere.
- Rogue AI.
- Drought, famine, plague...
Everything.
Alien invasion,
population growth, hole in the ozone...
Jason, hey.
- Read the room for once in your life.
- Sorry, Mom.
Point is, I have a job to do.
You do understand
that this is an apocalyptic event.
This is a large celestial body
heading towards our planet at speeds...
Dr. Mindy, I hear you.
I hear you.
- You should be proud.
- Thank you.
I'm taking it very seriously.
I'm taking it straight in the heart.
I'm so glad to hear that.
You have no idea.
Hey, gang, obviously everything we talked
about in here, super classified, right?
- Yeah.
- Cool.
Thanks for dressing up.
You're saying
we're just gonna leak it to the press?
- Isn't that illegal?
- Hell yeah, we're going to leak it.
In case you didn't notice,
the White House just blew us off.
My boyfriend, Phillip,
says he knows a reporter
from the New York Herald
who will talk to us.
- Adul Grelio.
- Good. He's a heavy hitter.
And I'll reach out to more of
the scientific community on the down-low.
- I just feel like this isn't what I do.
- You're just telling a story.
Keep it simple.
No math.
But it's all math.
It all started
with a connection.
A simple gesture that created so much.
So many choices.
Sometimes, it can even feel like too much.
Until now.
Introducing BASH LiiF.
Life, without the stress of living.
Before we introduce
the founder and CEO of BASH,
please remember
to avoid direct eye contact,
sudden movements,
coughing or negative facial expressions.
And now, please welcome
Sir Peter Isherwell.
We love you, Peter!
Hello, everyone.
All of my life's work,
really, I see has been driven
by an inexpressible need for a friend
who would understand and soothe me.
And you know, now all those years of work
have come to fruition with BASH LiiF,
our new BASH 14.3 phone
is fully integrated
into your every feeling and desire
without you needing
to say one single word.
If I feel...
- Sad.
- Afraid.
Or alone.
The BASH 14.3 phone,
when set to the life setting,
instantly senses my mood
through blood pressure...
heartbeats and...
Your vitals
show that you are sad.
This will cheer you up, Peter.
You are my best friend
You make me happy...
Oh, that's wonderful.
That video...
It also, seriously, schedules
a therapy session
with a nearby professional,
so we can make sure that
these sad feelings never ever ever return.
- May I say something, Mr. Isherwell?
- No.
And to support BASH LiiF,
I wanna officially announce...
Oh, give me the phones.
They're not yours.
- Say bye.
- Bye, Mr. Isherwell.
Bye, Peter.
I love you, Peter.
Are you sure the video
of the puppy on the rooster
is optimizing our prepubescent
sense memory consumer sector?
I find the bird quite threatening.
We will cross-check
the data on that, for sure.
Mr. Isherwell, Paul Debent
wanted me to give this to you.
He got it from
an astronomer friend of his in Mexico.
Oh, my.
What other confirmation
do we have on this, Adul?
I've spoken to Dr. Oglethorpe in DC
and he confirmed it and all the math.
Then I showed it
to Dr. Franks at Columbia,
and he almost fell out of his chair.
So, look, I have to admit.
I was very skeptical at first,
but this is all quite credible.
The calculations are credible.
Jesus.
And the president
really said to sit tight?
- Yes. That's correct.
- Sit tight and assess.
She's probably worried about the midterms.
We need to move fast.
The feds will claim breach of security,
so make sure these two
get a pro bono attorney.
- You can use my attorney.
- You can certainly afford it now.
We're gonna hire a lawyer?
- That wasn't necessary.
- It was.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. Sorry.
That was not called for.
I just have a question here.
How is it criminal if we just tell people,
like the public, you know,
what we saw, and tell them the truth?
Make sure this one gets media training
before he hits the shows.
He seems a step slow.
What does that mean,
I need media training?
They want us on a show
called The Daily Rip
first thing in the morning
before the article comes out.
You guys know what The Daily Rip is?
It's like the best show.
Everyone wants to be on it.
Brie and Jack have legendary chemistry.
They asked me to go on once.
I was so excited
I couldn't sleep for two nights,
but then they cut me for time.
Still hurts me to think about that.
I know what show you're talking about.
My wife loves that show.
Okay, can you just tell me
what this is all about? Okay?
'Cause you haven't read my article
on Conlon getting hard in the art class.
Now Adul Grelio has come down
from his mountaintop for your thing.
You won't even give me
a lousy pronoun? Come on.
A comet, bigger than the asteroid
that destroyed the dinosaurs,
is headed directly at Earth.
If it isn't deflected,
the entire planet dies.
Wait, what did you just say?
It's for a video game.
Are you being serious?
Yes.
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God! What the fuck, man?
I love you too. All right. Yeah.
Hey, guys,
we gotta keep walking, all right?
Come on.
- You must be Dr. Mindy and Miss Dibiasky?
- Yes.
Jack and Brie are so excited
to have you on the show.
Really? They know who we are?
White House is denying
they even met with them.
Well, assholes will always be assholes.
Hi, I'm Thalia.
The Herald sent me
to help with your wardrobe.
Oh, I'm not wearing that.
Yeah, you actually have
really great facial structure.
How 'bout if we trim
this beard down a little bit and...
I love your hair.
Thank you.
How are we gonna do this?
I talk about the discovery and you...
talk about how urgent it is
that we take action.
How do we say it? I mean...
- Shouldn't we practice it or write it out?
- Can I get you some water?
Yeah, water.
Yeah, water would be nice.
You are here now.
You are here now. You are here now.
Eleven benevolent elephants.
Just gonna take some Xanax.
I take it sometimes when I...
Kate, not this time. Not this time.
He just needs to breathe
and speak up. You know?
He's got this. I know he does.
Oh, God. Come on.
You are here now.
You are here now. You are here now.
You're here now.
Oh, God!
You gotta
stop drinking the cheap shit.
- It's only two glasses.
- Yeah, two and a half.
- We're 20 out.
- Always running late.
Let's make sure that our eye lines,
that we're not looking
at Jack and Brie, please, all right?
And cue the package.
Two glasses. Here we go again.
- Ladies okay?
- Yes. And we're live.
Brie, I've got something for you today.
Listen to this.
President Orlean's Supreme Court nominee,
Sheriff Conlon,
has now been identified
as appearing in a softcore porn cable show
- from the early '90s...
- Ridiculous.
Called Satin Sheet Nights.
- This story just keeps going and going...
- Oh, my gosh.
Is that Riley Bina?
- Yes, well, it's a...
- Really?
She looks a lot smaller
in person, doesn't she?
Ride 'em, cowboy.
Good.
Hey, everyone. I'm Sean from the show.
We're gonna do... Jack and Brie
are gonna do ten on the SCOTUS nominee.
- Riley Bina, you'll come on and...
- I get to talk about my single, right?
A portion of the profits
goes to the manatee sanctuaries.
Yes, but the breakup first.
And then Dr. Mindy and Miss Dibiasky,
you'll come on and talk about
that planet you discovered.
Comet. We found a comet.
They know what we're here
to talk about, right?
Of course. Jack and Brie
love doing science segments.
Just remember, keep it light, fun.
Jack and Brie love having a good time.
That's not promising.
You guys discovered a comet?
That's so dope.
I have a tattoo
of a shooting star on my back.
That's terrific.
We heard about your breakup too,
so we just wanna say...
We're very sorry, right?
We're real sorry.
You seem like a... great person.
Why don't you mind
your own business, you old fuck?
Okay.
Not gonna lie, but my friends
and my Vroom Vroom Army
have been so amazing.
So, I'm really grateful for that.
But, yeah, I can't lie. It's been hard.
- You're an inspiration. It's incredible.
- To so many.
You're really owning that pain.
You know, Jack, I feel like
there's some kind of conversation
that we need to be having here.
Is there any message
that you would like
to send to your ex, DJ Chello?
You know...
If there's something...
- Yeah.
- Right here in this camera.
Tell him. As if that was him.
You tell him exactly what you're thinking.
Okay...
Chell.
I still love you,
and after many sleepless nights,
three,
I wanna take you back.
I'm sorry...
- Is that okay?
- Yeah.
- He cheated on you.
- Oh, my God. You guys...
Yeah. I do.
- Diddly just exploded.
- So did Vroom Vroom.
BASH News just sent me
eight push notifications.
- About this?
- Yeah, look.
My phone just purchased
DJ Chello's latest single.
What the...
It just did that without asking.
I'm being told that
we have DJ Chello live on a Mugg link.
- What's he got to say for himself?
- I love the producers here.
Hey, baby doll. Hey.
- Hi. Hi, baby.
- He's in tears.
- Your kid messed up bad.
- I know.
Lady Baroque wasn't wearing
any panties in the club that night.
- It's fine.
- I just got all crazy.
I wasn't thinking straight.
I made a mistake.
But, look, it's always been you.
I get it. It's okay.
I hooked up with her too,
last year at the Music Globes
right before I ran off
with that power forward from the Nuggets,
and none of that matters.
What about forget breakup sex.
Try breakup relationship?
- That's good.
- Come on.
Ten famous second chances
for two-timers, guys.
It's on a plate.
I've been scared, but, honestly,
I'm not scared anymore.
Okay.
My little bumblebee, will you marry me?
Oh, my God. Of course.
- Chell, of course.
- Yes!
- That's sick.
Yes!
All right, DJ Chello.
What is happening?
Just bought another.
- Who are these people again?
- They're like the biggest names...
Well, the fireworks
have certainly gone off today.
- They have.
- What a zinger!
Yes, they have.
From a wedding proposal
to a little science experiment.
I'll need a temple rub
and a martini later on.
Our last guests today have made
a pretty big discovery in space.
Astronomer Dr. Randall Mindy
and PhD candidate
Miss Kate Dibiasky are here.
Welcome to the show.
Can I ask you one thing before we go
any further? I have to know this.
Is there life out there?
- Can you tell us? Yes or no, final answer.
- We don't have the data.
But sure, in the vastness
of space, why not?
Yes, aliens are real.
I knew I'd like this guy.
Didn't I tell? You owe me 50 bucks.
I'm not saying there's
little green men in flying saucers...
- Please don't encourage him, Dr. Mindy.
- That's what he's saying.
We'll never get out of here.
Now, Jack was having some fun here.
- Dad looks great.
- What did...
- Doesn't he look good?
- They did something with his beard.
With the aliens...
Really... He really does.
- So much.
- Dr. Randall...
You'll regret it. Now, look,
Jack's just having some fun here
with the aliens or whatever,
but there's a New York Herald story
that's just come out that talks about...
Keep it right there. You're doing good.
- The two of you have made.
- That's right, Brie.
Kate was observing supernovas...
Yo, that's your girl?
- Yeah.
- Not bad.
An absolutely shocking
and once-in-a-lifetime discovery.
I had no idea that Subaru made telescopes.
This has to be exciting.
Tell us what you found, Miss Diabasky.
I was monitoring exploding stars
to help measure
the expansion of the universe and...
- For your PhD, right?
- Yeah.
I saw something I didn't recognize.
It was a comet.
A big one.
It's headed directly at Earth,
and it really likely will hit.
This sounds very, very exciting.
Exploding stars, like,
stars actually explode.
How big is this thing?
Can it destroy someone's house?
Is that possible?
Well, Comet Dibiasky, which is
what it will officially be named...
- After her?
- Yeah, after her.
- Congratulations.
- What an honor. Congratulations.
It's somewhere between
six and nine kilometers across.
- So...
- It's big.
It would damage the entire planet.
Not just a house, you know?
The entire planet.
Okay, as it's damaging,
will it hit this one house in particular
that's right on the coast of New Jersey?
It's my ex-wife's house.
Can we make that happen?
You and Shelly have
a great relationship. Stop.
You need to stop.
I will, but in all fairness,
I actually paid for the house.
I'm so sorry.
I'm sorry, are we not being clear?
We're trying to tell you
that the entire planet
is about to be destroyed.
- Okay...
- Well, it's, you know...
It's something we do around here.
We just keep the bad news light.
Right.
It helps the medicine go down.
Speaking of medicine, tomorrow we've got...
Well, maybe the destruction
of the entire planet
isn't supposed to be fun.
Maybe it's supposed to be terrifying.
And unsettling.
No, please don't do that.
- And you should stay up all night...
- Please.
Every night crying,
when we're all 100%
for sure gonna fucking die!
Hey, Kate.
I'm sorry.
Hey, man.
My brother has bipolar disorder.
So if you ever need anyone to talk...
Okay.
Is she always like that?
- I...
- Something I said?
Right?
Maybe I should have given her
that extra Xanax that I had.
Listen, if you don't have enough,
we all have enough around here for her.
A spoonful of Xanax
makes the medicine go down, right?
That's right. That's good.
- We're gonna have to get you back.
- I knew I'd like this guy.
- Is he a plant?
- I knew it.
Okay.
Well, the handsome astronomer
can come back anytime,
but the yelling lady, not so much.
Not so much. Join us tomorrow
when our guest will be the man
that many say will challenge
President Orlean in two years.
Senator Jeff Lerner will be here.
And wrongly-convicted murderer,
Michelle Weems,
talks to us about her controversial
third-place finish on Celebrity Dance Off.
- I thought she would've won.
- Yes. I still think she's guilty.
- That's The Daily Rip, guys.
- Have a great day.
- And we're out!
- The show's over?
- I mean, didn't...
- Yeah.
- Did what we wanted to say come across?
- No, it's over.
You were great, but I think mullet girl,
she probably needs some media training.
- Really?
- Yeah, no, terrible, buddy.
Thanks. Thanks, Billy.
We usually get drinks at Aundrine's
after our five o'clock staff meeting.
You know, it's fun. You should come.
Oh, I'll have to see.
Thank you for the invitation. Thank you.
Kate? Kate?
- Hey. You were awesome.
- Oh, thanks.
Can I get a photo of you for my portfolio?
- Yeah, sure.
- Thanks.
Thank you.
You can see this spike here
is when Riley Bina
asked to take DJ Chello back
on the segment before you.
We saw engagement across
all social media platforms.
And what about our story?
Randall and Kate,
your TV appearance got some nice traffic
when Miss Dibiasky cursed.
But, unfortunately,
there was an immediate backlash
that quickly became a meme.
Oh, Jesus.
- Oh, that's terrible.
- They just think I'm crazy.
I mean, look at that.
That's so unnecessary.
- You can move on, Erin.
- Yeah.
That is just so...
Is that even allowed on the internet or...
I think that's Photoshop, Kate.
The trick is
to not take it personal...
Dr. Mindy, on the other hand,
had some very high favorables.
Vegan*Babe wrote...
Meow! Me likey hunky Star Man.
Some accounts called him
The Bedroom Eyes Doomsday Prophet
or A-I-L-F, which means
astronomer I'd like to fuck.
I don't see what that has
to do with anything, do you?
And that's everything.
We did not feature or push on any sites,
and clicks overall were below
basic weather and traffic stories.
So that... that... that's it?
- I knew it.
- That's it.
- Thank you, Erin.
- Yeah, no problem.
I don't... I don't understand.
I don't understand. There's no response.
There's absolutely no...
Why aren't people terrified?
What do we have to say?
What do we have to do?
There are scientists in Mexico and Spain
who are currently going through the data,
and South Korea has expressed...
- That's great. South Korea.
- Hey.
Let us not bullshit each other.
The bottom line is,
you guys told us the science was 100%.
It's not. Now we look like idiots.
- No. Who said the science is not 100%?
- Excuse me?
I wanna talk to this person.
You tell me who said the science...
Dr. Jocelyn Calder, the head of NASA,
just came out calling it
more near-miss hysteria.
She's the one
who told us not to say anything.
More near-miss hysteria.
Is she even an astronomer?
She's the head of NASA, but maybe
she doesn't know what she's talking about.
She's the head of NASA, but look,
she's a former anesthesiologist
and a President Orlean super donor.
Let's not be dramatic here.
It's all corrupt.
Yes, but the point is that Adul's right.
There's still serious debate.
And now the Herald has egg on its face.
We've taken that story as far as it goes.
Ladies, gentlemen,
I wish you a very pleasant end of times.
It's not a goddamn story, okay?
We have precisely six months, ten days,
two hours, 11 minutes and 41 seconds,
until a comet twice the size of Chicxulub
tears through our atmosphere
and extincts all life on Earth.
When did you
do those calculations?
I put the moment of impact on a diet app.
So, impact is when my diet ends.
Only I'm not on a diet.
I'm just crying five times a day.
- I'm scared.
- Hey, come on. Come on.
Everyone should be
panicking right now, okay?
- Don't cry. Come on.
- I know.
That prick!
What happened?
Guess my boyfriend just broke up with me.
God, what a day. What a day...
You're gonna die!
You're gonna die! You're...
It started with
a photo many thought was an armpit
or the chin of a man with a strange beard.
But what's emerging now is a scandal...
President Orlean sent
her Supreme Court nominee
a cell phone picture of her private parts.
- Holy crap!
- It's clickbait material.
Is this what you want
in your country as a leader?
Isn't she the same person
who told poor people
that if they don't wanna be poor,
they should pick better lottery numbers?
She actually said that.
A source also confirmed to me that
the two have been
having an affair for years.
And as recently as yesterday...
Members of my party
are currently drawing up a formal censure
of the president,
Janie Orlean...
Oh, my God, honey.
This guy doesn't even know
what a heliocentric orbit is,
and he's calling me a crackpot.
He says that,
Jewish billionaires
invented this comet threat
so the government
can confiscate our liberty and our guns.
#DontBeScared. Unbelievable.
My God.
You've been on that site a lot lately.
Yeah. I mean, I... I have, like,
a quarter million subscribers, honey.
I gotta use my voice
to get the truth out there, right?
I'm going for a walk
if you wanna come.
It is called
the scientific method...
and it is what created the computer
that you are typing
your half-witted conspiracy theories on.
What do you think about that?
Randall?
- Yeah, honey?
- Someone's here to see you.
Who? Oh, boy.
Oh, my gosh.
Oh, God, right. Okay.
Right.
Are you Dr. Randall Mindy?
Yes, sir. I am.
We're all gonna die.
Fuck off, please.
FBI! Freeze! Get on your knees right now!
Get on your knees!
You're under arrest
for breach of national security secrets.
Jesus Christ!
You could've just called me
or showed up to my apartment.
What are you, dressed up as a blind guy?
- Get on the ground!
- Okay. Now be cool.
I just have
more skin pigmentation than you.
'Cause your ancestors
migrated to Northern Europe
and developed lighter skin
so as to not get...
Unless you assholes
are taking me to the Batcave,
fuck you for putting this hood on me.
Watch out for him.
He'll charge you for free shit.
What's he doing here?
Is he here for us?
Gentlemen, you can come in.
I think
it was Winston Churchill who...
Or maybe it was Bobby Knight
who said, the great labor of leadership
is to lay down one's yoke of pride
and admit that mistakes were made.
You were deceived,
as was I, but the end result was,
we had our scientists who went to
the prestigious schools of Harvard,
Princeton, et cetera.
They confirmed the data.
So we would like to offer you a...
presidential apology.
Really?
And we are fully prepared to mobilize
in historic fashion
in order to save this planet.
The best news
we've heard in a long time.
So, basically, what you're saying is
you're about to lose the midterms
'cause you got caught
sending pictures of your cooch
to your porn-star sheriff boyfriend.
So now it's to your advantage
to act on the comet?
Right.
Okay.
Okay. I'm just...
God, I'm so relieved
that you guys are doing something.
- Hey, come on. Hey.
- This has been really...
- Really, really hard.
- Come here.
This has been really, really,
really stressful on all of us.
Yes, I will agree.
This will take some
heavy weight off all of us...
Sorry, you just look
so bad when you cry.
Maybe, possibly.
People are gonna ask
why we didn't act earlier.
So you're gonna have
to take the hit on this one.
Yeah, but we'll take care
of you down the road, Jocelyn.
- We will.
- Of course, Janie.
I will resign in disgrace
first thing tomorrow.
- Good. Yeah, good.
- That's weird as hell.
She's an anesthesiologist.
I'm going to make a statement,
presidential statement
to the American people.
And we're not gonna tell
the press about it ahead of time
because that way
it will have the appearance
of a breaking emergency sort of...
Good things
come to those who wait.
See?
Oh, my God!
We interrupt this broadcast
of Jackpot Fianc
for an emergency message
from the president of the United States.
Citizens of the United States
and peoples of the world,
I have just been handed
scientific findings that
confirm a worst-case scenario.
An unprecedented comet,
nine kilometers wide,
is now on a direct collision course
with our cherished home, planet Earth.
Estimated time of arrival
is approximately five months from now.
So we have...
We've drawn up a massive
Congressional spending bill...
I have already put together an emergency
spending package for Congress...
That the Senate
and the House have agreed upon.
That's good to hear.
And that will enable NASA
and our great military
to launch a preemptive strike,
using decommissioned
space shuttles and satellites
loaded with nuclear explosives.
We will blow Comet Dibiasky
off her course...
But we're gonna need a hero.
We're gonna need a pilot, real guns and...
Shouldn't this mission be accomplished
using remote technology?
Washington's always gotta have a hero.
I have asked
Medal of Freedom recipient
and outspoken patriot, Benedict Drask,
to undertake this difficult and...
I'm sorry.
Isn't he the mercenary gentleman
that was screaming at all those children
on the White House lawn?
Yeah.
He was given the honor of leading
the presidential initiative
in getting kids to exercise.
Get a little air into it, you lard-ass...
You look like a goddamn bunch of pussies.
- I'm sorry.
- He's just of another generation.
You know, I used to date him.
Know what happened to the last pussy
I worked with in combat?
You ever see inside a man's torso?
Benedict Drask reporting for duty.
- Thank you for the...
- He's gonna be fantastic.
He's got a great voice.
- We're gonna let him make a statement.
- Some are saying this is a...
He's got a great body too.
- He does.
- Yeah.
Suicide mission.
Well, all I ask is,
if I get snuffed,
that you all earn
the extra living my sacrifice gives you.
The extra living
my sacrifice gives them.
- Right?
- I wrote that.
Isn't that from Saving Private Ryan?
- Yes.
- No, that's something totally different.
And special thanks should also go
to this team of scientists behind me...
We're gonna need
everybody's help on this.
Everybody.
All have to pitch in
and push out this message.
African-American scientist.
Miss Dibiasky, she...
And we have Kate Dibiasky,
who the comet is named after,
but don't blame her.
Connects with the disaffected youth
and the mentally ill.
- And other marginal groups.
- Thank you.
- We'll do whatever we can.
- As long as you do the right thing.
We're there for you.
Especially you, Dr. Mindy,
because you poll so much higher
than your colleagues.
It's wild.
He will help us destroy
our common enemy, Dibiasky.
Wonderful. Well, I think we're done.
Yep, okay. Let's go.
Can I say something?
We've been dying to hear
what you gotta say.
I didn't vote for you.
But this is obviously
much bigger than my misgivings.
So I will be 100% behind this effort.
No matter how offensive I may find you.
That's great.
Yeah. That's really nice.
You know, I did have the FBI
put that bag over your head.
They don't do that.
The CIA does, but I made them do it.
You know, I had a feeling. I really did.
It's a good feeling
'cause that is what I did.
- And it was very funny and cool.
- Okay.
May Jesus Christ
bless every single one of you,
especially the honorable members
of my own party.
We will prevail.
We're all gonna die!
Guys, this comet
is seriously stressing me out.
Well, it's coming. People gotta dig in.
I already got buyers
for these shovels on e-market.
Clean sweep for President Orlean
in these midterm elections.
- How hot he is.
- Thousand bucks a pop.
Discharge the duties
on which I am about to enter.
So help you God.
- So help me God.
- Congratulations.
We have talk of
a Nobel Peace Prize in the offing.
He's not hot.
Hello, Sammy.
Are you really a doctor?
Well, sort of. I'm an astronomer.
What is an astronomer?
Dr. Mindy, there is
a lot of fear out there,
in America, around the world.
Parents don't know
what to say to their kids.
What would you say to them
to help them understand?
Well, I'm sure many of us
are frightened right now.
But I can assure you, our best
and our brightest, they're on the job.
I've seen the science
on this plan and it is sound.
I know your words are a great comfort
to all our viewers, Dr. Randall,
and we thank you
for your courage and your service.
I'd just like to say
that whenever
I feel afraid or alone in this, I...
I think of you and I just...
I feel better.
So thank you.
That's my job.
- Tell me we're all gonna die.
- What?
- Tell me we're all gonna die, do it.
- We're all gonna die.
Oh, boy.
So, these two Marxists
wave around the word science
and we're all supposed
to do whatever they say?
Yeah, how do we know
there even is a comet?
Mr. Pawketty, Congressman,
this data has been proven
and has been peer-reviewed
by hundreds of world-renowned scientists.
And we're supposed to trust you?
The comet's got your name.
I don't... I don't see the relevancy.
Why won't you
answer the question?
- Answer the question.
- What's the question?
Grow up here, okay?
This is ridiculous.
I've just realized, we don't really know
anything about each other. Do we?
True.
Well, every time I try
to ask you about your life,
you seem to just tell me
about your favorite restaurants.
Well, I... You know...
I just despise the, you know,
getting-to-know-you part
of relationships, so...
Oh, okay. I understand.
Okay, let's just
get it over and done with.
Okay...
Right, so...
My grandfather invented
the flash-freezing process.
So I come from grotesque money,
but I got away from it
by getting three masters degrees.
I've been divorced twice.
One was a Secretary of State,
and the other one was a sport fisherman.
I have slept
with two former presidents.
I speak four languages,
and I own two Monets.
Two former presidents.
- What, my turn?
- Yeah.
All right. My fatherwas
a middle school geography teacher.
My mother,
she cut hair out of the kitchen.
About two years ago,
our family dog, JoJo, died,
which was really, really emotional.
I can't remember crying that much ever.
And...
I finally got my Star Wars poster
signed by Mark Hamill.
It's in the garage. It's... So, yeah.
Okay, good.
That's done.
Where are we gonna go for dinner tonight?
The Lord is my shepherd. I shall not want.
He makes me to lie down in green pastures.
He leads me beside the quiet waters.
He restores my soul.
Not since D-Day have we seen
such a mass mobilization
of unions and resources
for such a noble task.
One cannot help but be moved
by the bravery, ingenuity,
and sacrifice on display here.
Okay, here we go, everyone.
Let's stay sharp.
I just want you to know,
this is the most propulsive thing
that's ever happened to me. Thank you.
What's the holdup, you guys?
What are you waiting on?
Come on, motherfuckers,
let's light this fucking firecracker, huh?
Think I got all day?
Commander Drask,
this is your president speaking.
Your nation thanks you.
Your planet thanks you.
And God and I thank you.
Listen, the only thanks I need
is a shot of Jack Daniels.
And a couple DUIs to magically go away.
This is Mission Control.
All indicators are coming up green.
This is a final warning
to control the launchpad.
Your discovery led to this mission
and our chance to save Earth.
I give you...
the honor.
Thank you.
Thank you,
Madam President.
Citizens of planet Earth,
everything is theoretically impossible
until it is done.
And with that,
we are go for launch.
Yes.
- That's fire.
- Thank you.
It was lit.
Hey, everyone, mind if I join?
- Hello.
- Hello, Peter. Hi.
Hi. Oh, Brie, you look fabulous.
As always.
Is he allowed to be in here?
Yeah, he's a Platinum Eagle level donor
to the campaign. He has full clearance.
Launch mission array.
Molly kicking in right now.
Timed that shit perfect.
Ten, nine, eight...
seven, six, five, four...
Three...
Thank God!
Oh, Susannah,
don't you cry for me
I come from Alabama
with a banjo on my knee, hey!
We didn't lose
any satellites.
Margin of error
was for two to malfunction.
Hey, Madam President, may I have a word
with you outside for a moment, please?
Oh, my God.
Mission success probability
is already increased to 81%.
Outstanding.
Janie, now!
I'm so sorry. I'm so sorry.
Peter, I didn't mean...
And a big hello to that beautiful
blue ball down there we all call home.
All those proud white folks working hard.
God bless you.
Just a different generation. Yeah.
I also wanna say hello
to all the Indians out there.
Both kinds.
You know, the ones with the elephants
and the ones with the bow and arrows.
Hey, why haven't you guys ever teamed up?
How cool would that be, huh?
I wanna say hello
to all the gays out there.
Commander, booster ejection is imminent.
- Let's keep comm on mission.
- Roger that.
Separation confirmed.
Was that French?
Yes, it is. It means, the angels soar
to the heavens. It's...
It's from a 14th-century poem
I studied in Dartmouth.
And just watching this,
it just made me think of it,
and think of you.
God, I can't...
can't...
Go! Go! Go!
I think I probably should go
to the hospital and see what they...
Launch challenge!
Go! Go! Go!
Everyone, I have just received
some critical information
concerning our mission.
Looks like it's turning around.
No, it's not. It's a course correction.
It's pretty standard.
I was in the Navy.
Nope. It's turning around.
Seems to be
some confusion here amongst the crowd,
but I'm not gonna lie to you.
This reporter
is at a loss for words right now.
It's definitely turning around.
I'm looking straight at it.
Drask's ship is definitely turning around.
Does anyone know
what the fuck just happened?
It's still locked.
I just don't... I don't understand
what could've happened.
I mean, the mission was working, right?
Everything was on track.
Yeah. I mean,
it could've been anything...
Guidance system could've malfunctioned,
nuke destabilized, myriad of things.
Who was that guy that walked into
the Situation Room? He looked familiar.
That was Peter Isherwell, CEO of BASH,
and the third richest human ever.
He's the guy that bought
the Gutenberg Bible and lost it.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Things are extremely fluid.
Dr. Randall, you are now the Chief
Science Advisor to the White House.
What?
As such, you need to attend
an emergency Cabinet meeting
where you will be debriefed.
What about us?
You do not have clearance
for this, sweetheart. Don't trip.
Got you some crackers, some waters.
You don't need to throw it on the floor.
Gonna be three, four hours, tops.
Here, Kate. I don't know
why he threw 'em down. Here.
What if we have to go to the bathroom?
We'll lay out some newspaper for you.
Grab you a can of Febreze.
Short, sweet
and simple science.
I'll be back. All right. Come on.
Science tells the truth, Randall.
Fuck. Do you wanna come?
Yeah.
Ladies and gentlemen,
what we thought,
what the world thought
was an impending and terrifying danger,
turns out to be
an astonishing opportunity.
Our allies are very confused
and demanding answers...
Well, tell 'em to wait.
According to the most recent
spectrometer readings of Comet Dibiasky,
made by the astrogeologists
at BASH Cellular,
we've discovered something.
Something truly miraculous.
Peter. Peter?
Oh, thank you, Janie.
As... As some of you may know,
the most valuable minerals in the world
are fast becoming those that are deployed
in the manufacture
of cell phones and computers.
Yttrium, terbium, osmium, dysprosium,
on and on and on.
We're running short.
And the problem
is exacerbated, of course,
because China has her big panda paw
firmly on almost all the mines
that produce
these valuable rare Earth assets.
So you can imagine.
Just how happy we were at BASH
when our astrogeologists discovered
and then determined that this comet,
hurtling towards us from deep space,
actually contains at least $32 trillion
of these critical materials.
Critical to technology.
If we're to proceed...
I'm sorry. Is that why
you aborted this entire mission,
is because you're trying to mine
the comet for rare minerals?
I think
we should hold all questions
until the end of the presentation,
and you might find
that your questions are answered.
Yes, Madam President.
When you...
When the other metals are factored in,
the comet actually contains
almost $140 trillion worth of assets.
Buck-forty trilli.
Yeah...
What do these trillions of dollars
even matter if we're all gonna die...
I was about to ask
the same question, Janie.
Why weren't we consulted?
All due respect, Madam President...
Oh, no!
What if we're rich and we're safe?
I've gone over it
again and again and again in my head
and I still can't make sense of it.
He's a three-star general.
He works at the Pentagon.
Why would he charge us for free snacks?
One time, I met Sting,
and I swear to God,
he farted right in front of me.
Didn't break eye contact
and didn't even say excuse me.
And the thing is,
he actually pulled it off.
'Cause I still found him
to be quite charming.
Guys, we have to talk.
Come on, let's go. Come on, now.
It's insane. Like, completely insane.
It will never work.
I had the exact same reaction.
This is a nine-kilometer-wide
planet-killer we're talking about,
not roaming charges.
Look, I... I was confused and outraged
that they turned this mission around too,
but they've got
Gary Talcamont from Stanford
and Lisa Inez from Princeton
on their team.
I mean, this is next-generation
cutting-edge technology.
Obviously, one giant comet is a major
and existential threat to our planet,
but 30 smaller meteoroids, we can handle.
Our BEADS, that stands for
BASH Explore and Acquire Drones,
that you see here,
attach themselves to the comet
and scan it with nanotechnology
developed by
Nobel Prize-winning scientist,
Dr. Gary Talcamont.
And then we immediately deploy, don't we?
Nobel and Polonsky prize-winning scientist
Dr. Inez's micro-targeted,
quantum fission explosives.
You see, deep into the object...
Dr. Inez, would you like
to explain what's happening?
Thank you, Peter.
We've been developing
phase-fission reactions
in the CERN particle accelerator
that can splinter the comet
into smaller pieces
with breathtaking accuracy.
These segments are then steered
and decelerated by each BEAD
into the Pacific Ocean for reclamation
by waiting US Navy ships.
And when these... Thank you.
And when these treasures
from heaven are claimed,
poverty as we know it,
social injustice, loss of biodiversity,
all these multitudes of problems
are just gonna become relics of the past
and humanity is gonna stride through
the Pillars of Boaz and Jachin naked
into the the glory of a golden age...
And is this nanotech work peer-reviewed?
Well, I haven't reviewed the data,
but it's been modeled.
Has any of this been peer-reviewed?
Nope.
Interplanetary, interstellar,
intergalactic existence
for the human race.
Your mouth to God's ear.
I understand the wealth
that they can extract from this comet,
it can end world hunger.
Oh, I see.
- Why are you laughing?
- That's true. No, I see.
So that's the pretty little bow they're
putting around this line of bullshit.
I bet they'll say freedom and puppies too.
- All right.
- Yeah.
You want me to quit the mission?
I'll quit the mission. That's fine.
But you have to understand,
this is now beyond our control.
They have all the power.
So who do you want
in the actual room to make sure
this whole thing doesn't turn out to be
a complete goddamn disaster?
Jason Orlean?
You want Jason Orlean in that room?
I have news for you.
It's already a complete disaster.
They're talking about letting
a comet the size of a mountain
hit the planet to jack up
a cell phone company's stock!
You better take that down
about four or five notches now.
Were you yelling about that mission?
Why were you talking about cell phones?
My friend was just theorizing
as to what's going on.
We're confused too.
That's an awfully official-looking
White House badge you got there.
I don't know why I have this on.
Listen, just tell us what's going on.
I got three scared kids at home.
Just tell us something.
I understand.
I wish I could share information, but...
We're people just like you.
We deserve to know!
They're right.
They deserve to know.
Do you really wanna know what's going on?
- Yeah.
- Please.
- Kate, don't. Kate.
- Kate.
They found a bunch of gold and diamonds
and rare shit on the comet.
So they're gonna let it hit the planet
to make a bunch of rich people
even more disgustingly rich!
Fuck you!
No camera!
Everything I could, they won't listen.
Surprise, surprise.
Now, I'm starting to think
you just like riling people up.
I'm so sorry, Kate. Really, I am.
Oh, Randall. God.
Where's Brie Evantee?
Shouldn't you two
be playing footsie in a restaurant
that only serves cubes and foam?
Well, she ain't wrong.
You did lose the thread in a big way.
And what do you suggest we do?
An online petition, huh?
You want to hold...
Get a mob and hold up picket signs?
You wanna overthrow the government?
I mean, look at this.
I can't! My head is in a bag!
Sorry, Dr. Mindy.
White House wants her off the grid.
- Come on, now. Look...
- Now.
Wait. What does that mean?
What the hell does that mean?
- What does off the grid mean?
- Hey, Kate.
Oh, gosh. Kate! Are you okay?
Teddy, come on!
What choice do I have here?
A man's always got choices, Randall!
Sometimes you just gotta
choose the good one!
Miss Katelyn Dibiasky,
the charges against you are
violation of national security secrets,
inciting a riot,
and destruction of private property
owned by Bojo Mambo's Shrimp LLC.
What? I didn't...
However, the Attorney General
is willing to not pursue prosecution
if you will agree to the following.
The suspension
of all public media appearances
and incendiary language relating to
Comet Dibiasky and BASH Cellular.
Fine. Give it to me.
I don't give a shit anymore.
Mom. Dad.
I'm so glad to be home.
Unlock the door.
No politics. None.
What are you talking about?
Your dad and I are for the jobs
the comet will provide.
The divisions in this country
are bad enough.
We don't want more of that in our house.
- Slow down, kids.
- Sorry, Mom.
I worry about my kids and their future.
Sure, the jobs
the comet's gonna create sound great.
What if it's not safe?
Right now, millions of you are having
these same doubts and questions
about the approaching comet.
That is why BASH Cellular
in conjunction with
the United States Government
is creating a new hotline, free of charge,
to answer all of your questions.
And who knows? Maybe,
just maybe, one of our scientists...
Thank you, Sharon.
Makes me feel so much better.
Can be that friend we all need
to lean on during uncertain times.
Call 1-800-532-4500 for peace of mind.
Offer only available to BASH customers.
Details of your call may be shared
with other subsidiaries
to enhance your customer experience.
Data and roaming charges apply.
So, I thought he was the ambassador.
I was just flattering him.
Well, he was a waiter.
Now he's got an ego the size of Texas.
Oh, my God.
June, what...
What are you doing here, sweetie?
Had a feeling
something was going on and just...
Well, you know,
we're discussing important business.
- That's what we're doing.
- Oh, yeah, that's really very important.
Oh, can we just
skip past this part, please?
Where you get to feel self-righteous
and we put our tails between our legs.
It is just so boring.
Oh, it's so boring?
You wanna skip the part where
you feel bad for screwing my husband?
No, I don't feel bad.
Randall and I are having a wonderful time.
So, I think the question is,
do we keep having a wonderful time
or does he go back with you to Wisconsin?
Or Montana.
- Michigan?
- Michigan.
You know... she is actually right.
That's the only question. So...
Well, June, sweetie...
Sometimes in life things are, you know,
they're complicated and they just...
Oh, okay.
Oh, that was fast...
Well, before I go...
let me just give you some instructions
on how to take care of Randall.
Yeah, here's the Xanax
he takes for his panic attacks.
Oh, gosh.
Here's the Zoloft he takes
for the crashing depressions.
- Not so much recently. Okay, you know...
- Oh, good for you. Great.
This is for his blood pressure.
- Restless leg syndrome, that's a fun one.
- God.
Appetite suppressant to counteract
the weight gain from his other meds.
And for America's sexiest scientist,
a bottle of goddamn Cialis!
Gosh.
Goodbye. Goodbye, Randall.
I guess I'll just tell your sons
that Dad's fucking
the lady on our television.
June, I...
I really thought for a second
that was gonna work out.
People, they wanna
manage the comet to create jobs.
Thirty-seven percent
don't want the comet to hit.
That's actually down by three points.
And 23%, they don't think
there's a comet at all,
and that number is way up.
Not Bitcoin, RatCoin. RatCoin.
I'd like to buy these sunglasses.
You that girl from live TV
who said we're all gonna die?
No. What's your purchase?
What the fuck?
- Yeah, that's you. It's definitely you.
- Yep, that's me.
Holy shit. You're a stone-cold legend.
Word is bond.
I got a picture of you on my board.
Picture on his fucking board.
That's great. What's your purchase?
If you don't have one, get out of line
and make room for other customers.
Can I touch your hair in a non-sexual way?
- Get the fuck away from me.
- Oh, dude, have some...
Call Diogo, he'll freak out.
Will you say hi to my friend?
Dude, he's obsessed with you.
We love you. We don't like...
Can't stand Orlean either.
What's up? Yo, check out...
Yo, shut the fuck up.
Check out who we're with.
- Yo, bro! What up?
- What up?
I mean, we have a purchase,
but we don't have payment,
which is a metaphor on...
- Cash?
- Also, Phillip, I've been told...
- Right.
- That you wrote a book
about your past relationship
with Kate Dibiasky.
Funny you should say that,
I'm working on that now.
It's gonna be called
A Brush With The Devil, and it's...
You calling security
or something, with your eyes?
No. You're free to go.
- That sounds terrible.
- Just like that?
You don't give a shit, do you?
Sure, I do.
I care about DrinkMo's guarantee
of quality service.
Well, we don't give a shit either.
Not one single shit.
We hang and board behind the abandoned
Burger Crown from 7:00 to whenever.
Yeah, we do.
You should come hang.
If you're not a fucking pussy.
Oh, you know, it's me...
- Fuck. Okay. Thanks.
- And a bottle of scotch.
It's a joke. But also...
Okay, let me introduce you
to mankind's savior,
BASH Explore and Acquire Drone.
It's incredible.
It's incredible, isn't it?
I call this one Primo,
the first.
It's like my first child.
Primo, my boy.
It's your father, Cronos.
Don't be shy. Come on.
You're gonna be a god in the sky.
Are you at all concerned about
the sync on the BEAD explosions?
Oh, Doctor.
There are always questions and fears, and...
I have a report here from a Dr. Inez.
- If you'd just take a look at this study.
- Oh, thanks.
Listen, a lot of my colleagues,
they've either been removed
or resigned from this project,
apparently for asking too many questions
about this mission here.
So I just wanna make sure that you're...
That you're open
to the scientific peer-review process
and you're not approaching
this mission like a businessman.
- You know? That...
- What did you say?
- I wanna know if you're...
- Did you call me a businessman?
- You do own a corporate...
- You think I'm just a businessman?
Do you think you know me, Doctor?
Business?
This is evolution.
This is evolution of the human species.
- What are you doing bringing this...
- Well...
You know that BASH has
over 40 million data points on you,
on every decision you have made
since 1994, Doctor?
I... I know when you have colon polyps
months before your doctor does.
You got four or five
at the moment actually.
You know, they're not of concern,
but I'd have a checkup as soon as you can.
But much more importantly than that,
I know what you are. I know who you are.
My algorithms have determined
eight fundamental consumer profile types.
You are a lifestyle idealist.
You think you're motivated
by beliefs, high ethical beliefs.
But you just run towards pleasure
and away from pain.
Like a... Like a field mouse.
I'm just trying to...
I just wanna make sure
that the science is sound on this project.
I hope you understand...
Our algorithms
can even predict how you'll die.
To 96... 96.5% accuracy.
I looked you up after we met.
Your death was so unremarkable and boring.
I can't remember the details,
apart from one thing.
You're gonna die alone.
Alone.
If you'll excuse me, Madam President.
I've got some work to do.
What the hell are you doing?
- My God.
- I was trying to do my job.
You are just so lucky
that Peter adores you.
You're with the grown-ups now, Randall.
I can't even follow this shit anymore!
BASH got Orlean to pay
the Chilean government, if I'm correct,
$90 billion to let the tsunami
hit off the coast of the country.
That sound right to you?
Isherwell built
an underground bunker
for him and all his executives.
No, I heard that
they built an escape ship.
You guys,
the truth is way more depressing.
They're not even smart enough to be
as evil as you're giving them credit for.
- What?
- No.
Fuck! You're driving me fucking
crazy, Kate.
Fuck it. We're all gonna die.
Movie will be released
the day that some believe
Comet Dibiasky will impact the planet.
And the early word is
it's already a classic, Brie.
Oh, yes.
Well, and what a stellar cast.
- Devin. Yeah.
- I love Devin Peters.
He's great. Everything he does.
- What's it called again?
- It's called Total Devastation.
It cost $300 million to make.
- I mean, these movies...
- It's more than you earn.
Tell me about it.
And my friend Farley, he saw it.
- He said it's a ton of fun. That's right.
- Well, Farley likes it.
All right, well, what Farley says goes.
But first,
and yes, you can tell from my smile...
Stop it.
That America's sexiest scientist is here.
Dr. Randall. Welcome.
Dr. Randall, how are you, sir?
I'm... I'm good.
I'm gooder than good.
All right. So, Randall, we're hearing
that there is no comet,
or that there is a comet but it's
a good thing or maybe it's a bad thing.
We are so confused.
So, could you please help us out here,
you know, oh, wise scientist?
Well, first and foremost, Brie...
there most certainly
is a comet.
All right.
And we know that there is a comet
because we have the data.
There has been growing concern within
the scientific community as of late.
You see, the peer-review process
is absolutely essential...
- If BASH's stock...
- For us to get to the facts of... Yes?
If BASH's stock is any indicator,
we don't have to worry
about the peer review.
It is going gangbusters.
And full disclosure.
I bought as many shares as I could.
I advise you to do the same.
You are such a shameless capitalist.
Said the woman who will be
in the brand-new hot tub on my back deck
- when I put it in from the stock.
- You know me too well.
That's right.
Dr. Randall, you sure you're okay?
You want a glass of water...
I don't feel so good.
So I think we'll go
to commercial break...
No, Please, Brie. Don't cut away.
Let me say something.
- Okay.
- You came to the right place.
We like to say things.
Would you please
just stop being so pleasant?
I'm sorry, but not everything
needs to sound so goddamn clever
or charming or likeable all the time.
Sometimes we need to just be able
to say things to one another.
We need to hear things.
Look, let's establish, once again,
that there is a huge comet
headed towards Earth.
And the reason we know
that there is a comet
is because we saw it.
We saw it with our own eyes
using a telescope.
I mean, for God's sake,
we took a fucking picture of it!
What other proof do we need?
And if we can't all agree
at the bare minimum
that a giant comet
the size of Mount Everest
hurtling its way towards planet Earth
is not a fucking good thing,
then what the hell happened to us?
I mean, my God, how do...
How do we even talk to each other?
What've we... What've we done to ourselves?
How do we fix it?
We should have deflected this comet
when we had the fucking chance,
but we didn't do it.
I don't know why we didn't do it.
And now they're
actually firing scientists like me
for speaking out, for opposing them.
And I'm sure many of the people out there
aren't even
gonna listen to what I just said
'cause they have
their own political ideology,
but I... assure you,
I am not on one side or the other.
I'm just telling you the fucking truth.
This would be a good time to establish
that Isherwell and the president
have both said
that there's benefits to be...
Right, well, the president
of the United States is fucking lying!
Look, I'm just like all of you.
I hope to God, I hope to God that
this president knows what she's doing.
I hope she's got us all taken care of,
but the truth is,
I think this whole administration
has completely lost their fucking mind!
And I think we're all gonna die!
Look, I just wanna go home.
I just wanna go home.
I just wanna go home more than anything.
But if there is one thing,
one thing that I pray...
that I pray that all of you hear
from what I have just said,
is that all of us, all of us...
Why'd you do that?
I really liked you
and I despise most people.
You know, I...
I really thought I loved you.
Really?
That's wild.
Yeah.
Ma'am, you need to go.
We gotta get this man off the grid.
You still there?
No.
Well, maybe he just gets off
on the power, you know,
like any kind of power.
It's like he knew eventually that I was
gonna find out that the snacks were free.
- Right.
- You know what I mean?
- Yeah.
- So it was just like a power play.
Yeah, guys are weird.
I'm starting to think that all this
end of the world stuff is bullshit.
It's not.
It's definitely happening. I've seen it.
I feel like if God wanted to destroy
the Earth, He would destroy the Earth.
You believe in God?
Yeah, I mean,
my parents raised me Evangelical,
and I hate them,
but I found my own way to it.
My own relationship.
I'd appreciate it
if you didn't advertise it though.
I won't tell anybody.
I think it's kind of sweet.
- Wanna make out?
- Yeah, why not?
Can you not say why not?
It makes me feel like you don't want it.
It's shitty.
- Sure, whatever.
- That's better.
- Oh, my God, that's it.
- What? What?
- That's the comet.
- What? Where?
- Where?
- Well, that's the Big Dipper.
That's Venus. That's the North Star.
- Well, what is that?
- Oh, shit.
What the hell?
What?
Come on.
There it is.
There you are.
Is anyone else seeing this?
That's it.
That's it. That's the comet.
Look! It's right there.
- That's, you know, kinda scary.
- Exactly.
- Dr. Mindy.
- Kate.
Doc, you can see it.
I... I'm looking at it right now too.
It's unbelievable. It's...
It's horrific and it's...
and it's beautiful at the same time.
Oh, my God.
We've been trying to tell you.
We tried to tell you this whole time.
It's right there. It's...
It's right there, Kate.
Where are you?
I'm in Lansing, Michigan
trying to fix things with June,
but she won't talk to me.
- Where are you?
- What the fuck?
I...
I'm gonna come find you, okay?
Well, I'm in Illinois.
I could be ready by tomorrow.
- Dearest Father...
- Yeah, I'm...
As a sinner I come to You
for Your grace and guidance...
They're finally seeing it.
There it is!
Go outside into your yard,
onto a roof, onto your sidewalk,
and just look up into the sky.
The star's gonna appear fuzzy.
It's got a long streak coming off of it.
That's the comet's tail.
It's real and it's coming.
If anyone tells you any different,
they're full of shit.
Just look up into the sky.
It's a fucking fact.
- We have proof.
- Just look up.
Guys, please just look up, okay?
Screw the manatees and just look up.
Just look up.
- Just look up!
- Just look up! Just look up!
Just look up!
Dr. Mindy, the president's
plan to save Earth
and make it so we can all have a home
is going to work, right?
Every single man, woman and child
on this planet is going to die.
- I don't like him. He makes me sad.
- I'm sorry about that.
- This is not what we rehearsed.
- Kids, listen.
You tell your parents
that President Orlean and Isherwell
are sociopaths and fascists!
And do you know why
they want you to look up?
Do you know why?
'Cause they want you to be afraid.
They want you to look up
because they are
looking down their noses at you.
They think they're better than you.
Don't look up!
They wanna rob you of your freedom,
and that's a fact!
Don't look up!
The US president, Orlean...
Just look up!
Has not included India
or any other nation in the world
to be a part of this mission.
This dude is a known pornographer
named Kip...
Don't listen to that dumbfuck.
The United Nations have been
considering its own deflective mission.
Just look up, for fuck's sake!
Now I know a lot of Hollywood
is supporting the Just Look Up movement,
but I haven't seen a pin like that.
Yeah, this pin points both up and down.
Because I think, as a country,
we need to stop arguing
and virtue signaling. Just get along.
That is so refreshing.
I think
we're all tired of the politics.
Yeah, yeah. Well...
That's why we made Total Devastation.
It's for everyone. You know?
It's a popcorn movie.
You keep your eye on the road ahead,
you put your head down.
And you put
one foot in front of the other,
step by step.
Day by day.
- Don't look up!
- Don't!
So we wanna say something loud and clear.
There is no safe way
to bring this comet back to Earth
and exploit it for profit.
It cannot be done!
Nations of the world,
defy Orlean and BASH!
Launch your own nuclear deflection mission
now and save this planet!
And now, there's Riley Bina
with her special guest.
I forgot the name. Thank you.
We knew no bounds
fell at the speed of sound
Riding against all odds but soon
against ourselves
You haunted every memory
With no goodbyes out there for me
Your pride put out the fire
in our flame
Then just one look is all it takes
I feel your eyes,
they're locked on every part of me
And then my dumb heart says
Just look up
There is no place to hide
True love doesn't die
It holds on tight
and never lets you go...
Is that a rock-solid tensmokeshow
of a president or what?
If she wasn't my mother...
There's three types of American people.
There are you, the working class.
Us, the cool rich, and then them.
I'm sorry, but we need them.
We need them because
you build us up to fight them.
The working class, the lower.
- You understand?
- No, I don't get it.
Do you understand? I'm talking about...
I'm talking about nutritionists.
I'm talking about personal trainers,
people at the spa,
but not the ones that check you in
and they're not the masseuses,
but they walk you down the corridor.
They're there...
Know I let you down,
a nigga can't deny it
And there's so much that we're losin',
yes, that matters
I've been dealin' with madness,
wasn't the man you needed
You dealin' with sadness,
truthfully, it's all on me...
- Divest from BASH when?
- Divest now!
Divest from BASH when?
Time is oh so precious...
We will not be quiet!
Take my hand, baby,
I'll never leave you, Riley
Though what he's really trying to say
Is get your head out of your ass
Listen to the goddamn
qualified scientists
We really fucked it up,
fucked it up this time
It's so close,
I can feel the heat big-time
And you can act
like everything is all right
But this is probably
happening in real time
Celebrate or cry or pray
Whatever it takes
to get you through the mess that we made
'Cause tomorrow may never come
Just look up
Turn off the shitbox news
'Cause you're about to die soon,
everybody
Look up...
Hey, good afternoon, Adam.
What do I owe the pleasure of this call?
What time?
Well... Well, thank you for calling.
Yeah.
What?
Orlean and BASH
cut Russia, India, and China
out of the rights for the minerals.
So they tried their own
joint deflection mission,
but... approximately 40 minutes ago,
there was a massive explosion detected
at the Russian's Baikonur launch complex.
So it looks like the mission failed.
That's it?
What do you mean, that's it?
Teddy?
Right?
There is still the BASH mission.
It's all we have now.
Fuck!
These Just Look Uppers
want millions of illegal Chileans
to come across the border.
Don't look up.
The hell is that?
Fucking lied to us.
The president just texted me.
Don't trip. It's all good. Don't trip.
Hey, now.
You cut my face, you fucking rednecks!
Man, there hasn't been
a car in, like, an hour.
Yep.
Everyone's watching the BASH launch.
What are we doing again?
I told you. We're...
We're gonna go buy some groceries.
The Mills Brothers. Great band.
You know, Duke Ellington found this band.
I think they were originally called
the Four Kings of Harmony.
We'll call on each memory
till then...
Till Then, this is the song.
It's about...
It's about soldiers
going off to World War II
and thinking about home.
Listen to this part.
Although there are oceans...
Although there are oceans we must cross
and mountains that we must climb...
I know every gain...
I know that every gain must have a loss.
So pray that our loss...
So pray that our loss
is nothing but time.
Till then, let's dream
of what there will be
- Okay, I gotta ask you something.
- What?
Dr. Mindy, can I be vulnerable
in your car?
Yeah, go ahead.
I've never met anyone like you
and I feel a connection to you
on a level that...
I don't know,
I haven't felt with anyone else,
and going out on a limb,
but would you want to spend
more time together?
Maybe even get engaged or something?
Are you laughing?
- No?
- I'm smiling.
- Well, sure.
- This is sweet.
- Why not?
- This is pretty sweet.
And you read
the tea leaves for Dr. Mindy.
- You showed him the algorithm.
- Oh, yeah.
You really shook him
with that information.
- How he was gonna die.
- Yeah, it is shaking.
It got me so excited
to know about my own death.
I don't think I wanna know.
Yes, I do. I wanna to know.
You're gonna be eaten by a Bronteroc.
We don't know what it means.
- A what?
- A Bronteroc.
Okay, people, we have clear skies.
And we are a go for the BEAD launch.
Madam President?
Citizens of planet Earth. Now...
Look at this, Kate. They have wild salmon.
Look at the difference between that
and the farm-raised stuff.
You see how that looks just...
I don't know. Looks fake, right?
Hey, why don't you go find some...
What are the little potatoes called,
the tiny ones?
- Fingerling potatoes?
- Yeah.
- I fucking love fingerling potatoes.
- Let's get finger...
Do you wanna say something too?
That was beautiful. Yeah.
What up, world? Jason Orlean,
Chief of Staff, United States.
I've been noticing a lot of prayers
recently for people during this time
and I commend that,
but I also wanna give a prayer for stuff.
There's dope stuff, like material stuff,
like sick apartments and watches,
and cars, and clothes and shit
that could all go away
and I don't wanna see that stuff go away.
So I'm gonna say a prayer
for that stuff. Amen.
Just a quiet trepidation
among this much smaller crowd.
I can hear the sounds
of some people praying.
Okay, Anderson, let's go get it.
Yes, sir. Here we go, people.
Ten.
Ten, nine, eight, seven, six,
five, four...
Hey.
Hi.
We got some groceries.
Yo, what was that?
We lost BEAD number 12.
BEAD number 22 failed to launch.
It's fine. It's fine.
We had anticipated a margin for error.
Everything is fine.
I was hoping
we could have a family dinner.
Hey, Dad.
- Hey, guys. Hey.
- Hey.
What do you say?
Yeah.
- Thank you.
- Yeah.
- This is... This is Kate.
- Oh, hi.
- Hello. Hi, Kate.
- Let me grab those bags.
- Nice to meet you. I'm Yule.
- Yule.
I'm FirePuma142 on Twitch. You game?
It's really doubtful she knows.
- You're right.
- Who said I game?
I... I got these for you.
Thank you. That's really sweet, honey.
I'm so sorry. You have no idea.
- I really am.
- I know. I know.
- I've missed you.
- I missed you so much.
When we dated in college,
I fucked Aaron Tran.
Yeah, so...
- That is really good.
- Really good, right?
- Hey, everybody.
- Hey!
- Sorry I'm late, but not empty-handed.
- Hey, my friend.
Evan, Marshall, June,
this is Dr. Oglethorpe.
BEADs have approached
optimal escape velocity
and now approaching Comet Dibiasky
and are ready for attachment mode.
Okay. All right.
Eight and 27 are lost
due to lateral control malfunction.
Okay, so, now... Now, Peter...
Peter, we're six drones down.
Is this thing still gonna work?
Well, the engineer's assured me
that yes, 24 drones is enough.
Well, how many can we lose?
How many more?
We're being told that several
of the BEADS have exploded on launch.
Got the head seat right there.
You're way too kind, Randall.
Thank you.
Big Doctor.
Do you want more wine?
- Hey, cheers, everyone.
- Cheers.
- Love you.
- Thank you so much for having us.
Thank you for being here.
- It's so special.
- Thank you.
Commence simultaneous
explosive separation stage now.
Yo. Yo. Mom.
Beautiful.
- Thank you, pal.
- Yeah.
Yeah, it really is.
And it's really good to have you home.
Dr. Mindy got really famous.
Oh, yeah, I forgot about that.
That's right. Okay.
Yep, I was on magazine covers
and everything. I know.
- You looked great.
- I'll take your shots.
- I love you.
- Love you too.
All right. We need a report.
Need a full status report
on the explosive devices.
Get on it.
Still waiting for a full status report.
All right.
President Qi of China
says that the comet is still whole.
We got four misfires and sync was off.
It's still intact.
What was that?
We've got four misfires
and the sync was off.
Okay. We're all fine. Everyone's fine.
It's gonna be all right.
If you'll excuse me.
Nature calls.
I'm just gonna go to the restroom
for a moment.
Yes, I think
that I should also step out
to the restroom for a moment.
- Should I...
- No, I'll be fine.
Sir, the president.
We need to know
what the mission status is.
She's coming right back.
Screw this. I'm going to see my husband.
I'm sorry. I've got a 20-year-old
daughter. I've got to go see her.
I'm doin' an 8-ball.
Oh, shit!
She's coming. She's coming back.
Hello, there's a ship.
In case we were wrong,
and clearly, we were wrong.
Of course you've got a ship.
It holds 2,000.
It's state-of-the-art cryo-chambers,
and it's set to find
the nearest Earth-like planet
in a Goldilocks Zone so...
There's room for you and one other.
Brie, your wife, your call.
I'm good, but thank you for the offer.
You... You have fun with Jason.
Jason?
Oh, shit.
She's coming back.
I'm thankful for that night
I fell asleep out in the backyard.
- Woke up face-to-face with a baby deer.
- I remember that.
- Yeah.
- Yep. It was the best day of my life.
I'm grateful...
I'm grateful we tried.
Man, oh, man, did we try.
Well, we're not the most religious here
in the Mindy household,
but maybe we should say amen?
Should we do that?
Don't look at me.
I don't know how to...
What, you just say, amen? I don't...
- I got this.
- Wrap it up?
I got it.
Dearest Father and Almighty Creator...
we ask for Your grace tonight,
despite our pride.
Your forgiveness, despite our doubt.
Most of all, Lord...
we ask for Your love
to soothe us through these dark times.
May we face whatever is to come...
in Your divine will with courage
and open hearts of acceptance.
- Amen.
Youse got some church game.
That was beautiful.
The comet remains intact.
We just never...
Of course, there's only one story
everyone's talking about tonight.
Topless urgent care centers.
Sit.
Or... we can fuck...
or pray, or...
Honestly, I think
I'd just rather drink and...
talk shit about people.
You'll never take me alive!
Look out!
I'm definitely gonna have
some more of this apple pie. It's so good.
It's actually store-bought,
but you really can't tell.
If I'm to be completely honest,
which at this moment, why not?
I actually like the junky taste
of store-bought better than homemade.
You gotta be kidding me.
No, I'm not kidding.
You know what? I know what he means.
It's like a childhood memory thing.
Nothing is better than homemade, right?
This coffee doesn't taste
store-bought. Is it?
I grind my own beans. Yeah.
Yeah, Dad's kind of a coffee nut.
Every time you have coffee,
you have to grind your beans?
Randall is very particular
about his coffee.
I can get that way about tea.
Thing of it is, we really...
We really did have everything, didn't we?
I mean, when you think about it.
Hey, oxygen is
actually higher than on Earth
by nine percent,
so you might feel a bit light-headed.
And cryo-chambers were 58% successful,
which is much better than anticipated.
Yeah, we only had 47 dead
in our section, so...
I think this is gonna work out quite well.
Quite well, indeed.
Goodness.
Look at that beautiful animal.
I wonder, are those feathers
or are they scale...
- That's disgusting.
- What is that thing?
I believe that's called a Bronteroc.
Whatever you do, don't pet them.
Fuck.
Mom?
Mom!
What's up, y'all?
I'm the last man on Earth.
Shit's all fucked up.
Don't forget to like and subscribe.
We out here.
Mom!
Everyone was warned,
but no one listened.
A rise in temperature...
Ocean patterns changed...
And ice caps melted.
They called it extreme weather.
They didn't know what "extreme" was.
In the year of 2019...
Hurricanes...
Tornadoes...
Floods...
And droughts...
Unleashed a wave of destruction
upon our planet.
We didn't just lose towns...
Or beachfronts.
We lost entire cities.
The East River swallowed
Lower Manhattan.
A heat wave killed two million people
in Madrid...
In just one day.
But in that moment...
Facing our own extinction...
It became clear that no single nation
could solve this problem alone.
The world came together as one...
And we fought back.
Scientists from 17 countries...
Led by the U.S. and China...
Worked tirelessly.
Not as representatives
of their nations...
But of humanity.
They found a way
to neutralize the storms...
With a net of thousands of satellites,
each deploying countermeasures designed
to impact the basic elements of weather,
heat, pressure, and water.
All overseen
by the International Space Station.
They gave the satellite net
a technical name...
But we all came to call it Dutch Boy...
After the story of the child
who plugged a dam with his finger.
This is what saved us all.
And it was built by a team
led by one man...
My father.
- Thank you.
- Keep the change.
Jake Lawson. I have a Senate--
Senate hearing in room 12.
Yeah.
Lawson?
- You're the Dutch Boy guy, right?
- Yeah.
Man, I need to shake your hand.
Oh. Okay.
Tornado? Zap!
Blizzard? Zap!
Monsoon?
- Zap?
- Zap!
Everybody down here owes you,
Jake Lawson.
If you need anything, you just ask.
The Senate Committee
assigned to oversee Dutch Boy
will now hear from Jacob Lawson...
Climate ISS Chief Operations
Coordinator.
May the record reflect
that he was nearly one hour late.
Yeah, sorry about that.
I literally had to
fly in from outer space.
Oh, here we go.
Mr. Lawson, we find ourselves
heading toward a crossroads.
As you know, as per
UN Resolution 28-14,
the United States will be
handing over control of Dutch Boy
to an International Oversight Committee
in three years.
This in spite of the fact
that we actually built the thing.
Excuse me, Senator.
I don't wanna slow things down.
You said "we" built it?
Yes, indeed, I did.
Because I know what I did. I'm the guy
who led the team that built the station.
I was up there with an international
crew of 600 people, not just Americans.
And I know all of their faces,
but I don't remember yours.
We had a plumber up there.
He looked a little like you.
Very clever, Mr. Lawson.
Dutch Boy was an international effort
and, yes, it may, one day, very well...
...belong to the world.
But until it does,
we have authority over its operation
and we have authority over you!
And you have been flouting
that authority.
I have report after report here.
Failure to follow procedures...
Numerous violations
of the chain of command.
Then, there was the incident where you
punched a federal inspector in the face.
Well, your federal inspector
doesn't know
that a capacitor holds a charge
even when it's disconnected.
He was grabbing for the damn thing.
I saved his life!
You can make all the excuses
you want, Mr. Lawson,
but there's one thing you cannot defend.
And that would be the day
you brought Dutch Boy online...
...and operational without our consent!
And what would that have taken, Senator?
There were a series of storms building
in Southeast Asia and the North Atlantic
that would have killed
tens of thousands of people.
Dutch Boy was ready. We went green.
It works. You're welcome.
Mr. Lawson, if you continue
to defy our authority...
Dutch Boy will go on without you!
Am I making myself clear?
Yes.
Good. Oh, and one more thing.
To ensure compliance, this committee
will be sending up new support staff.
Naturally, when they get there, you'll
have to send some of your people home.
We'll leave those choices up to you.
Senator, respectfully,
my crew didn't do anything wrong.
Excuse me,
I'm not asking for your input.
These people left their homes
and their families
and risked their lives
to save this planet.
This hearing is adjourned.
I'm not cutting a single one
of those people loose!
Excuse me?
People like you need people like me.
You know why?
So you can take credit
for everything we accomplish.
So you can go to your constituents
and your cronies...
This meeting is adjourned.
...and your mistresses
and puff out your chest
- and say, "Hey, look at me!"
- Sit down, please!
- Well, I'm looking, Senator.
- Excuse me.
- We're all looking.
- This meeting is adjourned.
This meeting is adjourned! Thank you.
Well, that was going well, huh?
Up to a point.
No, Jake, that didn't go well
at any point.
But, hey, what are you good at,
little brother, huh?
Like working the angles,
smoothing ruffled feathers?
You can fix it. You always do.
It's like a talent.
It is a talent.
Of a sort.
I wish I could help you.
I really do.
But it's not that simple,
not this time.
Why not?
Well, as of last week,
they have put me in charge of Dutch Boy.
Well, that's great!
That's great! You kidding me?
You're kidding me.
Look, what do you want me to do? Huh?
You leave me no choice. I told you
this had to go well, and it didn't.
I'm sorry, Jake.
You're fired.
Jesus. It's over 120 in this mother.
Fan out.
Hi, Agent Wilson.
Assistant Secretary Lawson.
Oh, you look nice today.
I'm wearing the same thing
I always wear.
Not exactly.
Have you seen I, well, got on a new tie?
I observed. We're trained to notice
any disturbing details.
- Sarah, come on.
- Assistant Secretary Lawson...
I'm not permitted to engage in
casual conversation while I'm at a post.
We are being watched.
We're always being watched.
Well, if we're always being watched,
what's the point of hiding anything?
You're interfering with my duties.
I'd rather not shoot you.
Well, it would be an honor
to be the first person that you kill.
Hang on.
What is it?
Uh, the president's called
a security briefing.
It was not on the schedule,
so I guess I'm now on duty.
I like the tie. Home by 7:00. Love you.
I'm sorry, I didn't catch that.
I didn't say anything.
Move along, sir.
Yes, ma'am.
What the hell happened here?
One of our thermospheric satellites
malfunctioned over Afghanistan.
A UN recon team found it, Mr. President.
And the members of the Climate Council,
they're aware?
Yes, and they've all agreed
to keep the incident discreet.
But with this many people in the loop,
I'm not sure how long it's gonna keep.
And we're sure this was caused
by Dutch Boy?
Absolutely.
Can we assume that this is
an isolated incident? Doctor Quigley?
We're fairly certain, yes.
It's great to know
that you're "fairly certain."
This is a serious malfunction.
So your proposal is what?
Simple. We shut down
all Central Asian satellites
until we know what went wrong.
- Are you serious?
- Yes, I'm serious.
Know how difficult it was to get every
one of these nations online for this?
We have worked extremely hard
to assure these nations that this
system will protect them, and it has.
And let's not forget, people,
it's an election year.
We shut Dutch Boy down,
the press is gonna jump all over this.
Oh, my God!
300 people died in that village.
I mean, who gives a damn
about the politics of it all?
Look, we cost those people their lives.
The only thing we should be concerned
about here is how to fix it
and making sure it never happens again.
And how do you propose we do that?
We can't do anything.
What I mean is, the problem is
not gonna be solved in this room
and, well, certainly not by us.
No, no, we need an international team
on the station itself.
You know, not suits.
Engineers, coders, builders
doing a comprehensive systems check,
no matter the cost,
no matter the politics,
and we need 'em up there now.
We are set to transfer full authority
for Dutch Boy
to the international community
in two weeks.
I will not be the president
that hands over damaged goods.
Not now, not ever.
So we are gonna handle this problem
and its solution in-house,
and we are gonna send up one man.
One of our own, who reports only to us
and that we can control.
Understood?
So find me that someone.
Now.
Yes, sir.
Look, I know you're not gonna like it,
but as I see it,
there's only one person
to go after for this.
Your brother, Jake.
Come on, not Jake.
17 countries, hmm?
17 countries had teams working on
Dutch Boy. They all reported to him.
Nobody knows what's under the hood
better than him.
Come on. Can we weigh other options?
Max, how long have you known me?
Ever since I was transferred
to the State Department.
That's right. I handpicked you.
I believed in you. You're smart.
And I was right about you.
I'm right about Jake.
If this is gonna be a problem...
No, sir.
Good.
Afghan satellite
zero-niner-six inbound.
All crews prepare for incoming
Afghanistan satellite.
Replacement satellite
standing by.
Afghan sat is locked in.
Replacement cleared for launch.
And away on sat 5-A.
Airlock doors secured.
I want a full dissection
of all components.
Priority one.
Afghan satellite dissection
commencing.
I will take care of this.
Make sure they depressurize
the fuel intake.
Yeah, we got it, man.
Makmoud. Oi, Makmoud!
I'm about to obliterate
your top score here, pal.
I have to do some reprogramming.
Oh, come on!
He's got no pride of ownership,
that lad.
Please stand clear of the doors.
Uncle Max?
Hey! What you doing up there?
What is that? A solar generator?
Dual axis sun-tracking solar generator.
Replacing the power converter.
Oh, God!
You're getting more like your dad
every day.
Hey, where'd he find that?
Are you seriously asking that question?
Oh, of course.
He made it, right? Come here, you.
Ah, it's good to see you!
How you doing? You okay?
I'm really great.
Okay, what's going on here?
All right, this is freaking me out.
You're supposed to be nine years old.
Thirteen.
You were supposed to be
a part of my life,
but shit happens.
Ouch!
So what's going on here?
You living with him now?
He gets me two weekends a month.
Oh, good. Well, how's your mom?
Hmm, justifiably pissed.
I bet.
Hannah, it's time.
What's up, Jake?
Hannah, I thought I told you not
to talk to strangers.
Come on. Don't listen to him.
Your dad and I were your age,
we were so close we had
our own secret code.
- That's true.
- Really?
I don't remember that.
Yeah, you do.
No, I don't.
Well, it was nice seeing you.
Hey, look, you take care.
What's with all the car parts?
I build electric motors
for the retirees down in Vero Beach.
Keeps me busy.
Seems hardly worth your talent.
Kidding?
Having the time of my life.
It's a little early, don't you think?
I got fired by my own brother.
Then I lost my family,
my house, my dog,
so happy hour
starts around 11:00 out here.
Okay, saw your niece,
you don't want a beer.
Road's that way.
There's something wrong with Dutch Boy.
No, there isn't.
Well, an entire village of
dead Afghans may disagree with you.
Yeah.
And then yesterday,
an airlock just opened by itself.
We lost one of our crew.
Dutch Boy is not my problem anymore.
That I am calling bullshit on.
'Cause other than your daughter
and your precious soccer club,
Dutch Boy was all
you ever gave a damn about.
Oh, yeah, once.
Yeah, but you took care of that.
You don't care?
No?
Well, then, what are you doing
living out here?
Hmm?
Look, I know you think I'm a weasel,
someone who just moves pieces
around a chessboard for a living.
Well, guess what, yeah. Yeah, I am.
But that is how you get 17 countries
to agree to build a space station.
Now, you build things, right?
And there is something wrong
with the thing that you built,
and people are dying.
If you really think you're the best,
which I know that you do,
then how the hell
can you stand there and say no?
I'll be taking orders from someone,
I suppose.
Yeah.
So what? Is that a yes?
Long as it's not you, yeah.
Hey, this is Max.
Leave a message.
You got any room in there for me?
Whoa!
Okay.
I think this is everything.
I made you a packed lunch as well.
Did you hear about the gas main
explosions in Hong Kong?
Yeah, it just hit the news.
It's terrible.
Was it anything like what happened
in Afghanistan?
No, nothing happened in Afghanistan.
Are you going back up to space?
- No.
- Yes, you are!
You're leaving today to fix Dutch Boy.
What did I tell you
about eavesdropping?
You've never told me anything
about eavesdropping.
You don't really do much parenting.
How do you know it's safe?
Of course it's safe.
I've been up there 100 times.
Don't treat me like I'm a child.
Someone died!
- It was an accident.
- Someone got sucked out!
It was an accident.
See, that's what I'm going up there
to fix, okay? You don't have to worry.
Hey, think of it like I'm going
on a vacation for a week or two.
To a place 250 miles straight up
and -450 degrees?
Some holiday.
Yeah, you got a point.
Why'd Uncle Max fire you?
Unbelievable!
Did you do something wrong?
No, look, your Uncle Max and me...
It's not just about the one job.
You know, sometimes,
younger brothers resent being younger.
So they get bossy.
They think they know everything.
They tell you how to act, how to talk,
and after a couple decades,
you just get tired of listening to it.
Maybe you should listen.
My lift is here.
- Gotta go.
- What?
Wait, I thought I was
taking you to the airport.
You really wanna see Mom? Great!
We can all fly home to Atlanta together.
Got it covered.
Quit acting like you're mad.
Hannah, what do you want from me?
I want you to come back alive.
And you're not exactly
the reliable type.
Hey.
I know I haven't always
kept good on my promises,
but I'm coming back.
- I--
- Promise.
I promise.
Come here.
I'll be back soon, okay?
OV-104 is now at
T minus one hour and ready for boarding.
We're at T minus one minute
and counting.
Have a safe trip, sir.
Booster rocket
separation confirmed.
Hate to interrupt, Major Tom,
but in a few seconds,
you should be able to see the net.
How's it feel to be back home?
Look at you, girl.
Livin' and breathin'.
Mr. Lawson.
Hey.
Ute Fassbinder.
Nice to meet you.
Yeah, I remember you.
Yeah, you were the German scientist.
You were here when I was here.
Thermospherics, right?
Yeah.
The containment shell needs
a fresh coat of sealant
where the APT ducts push
through the channel housing.
Not good. That's wrong.
And you hear that?
- I'm sorry.
- Shh. Listen.
That wobbly hum?
That's a bad step-down transformer.
All these things,
they have to be watched, cared for.
- Mr. Lawson.
- No, I know. It's not your fault,
but when I left,
everything here was perfect.
I need to speak to your Chief Scientist
about the art of giving a shit.
I'm the Chief Scientist.
I've been promoted a year ago.
Right, congratulations.
One of our crew died this week,
Mr. Lawson.
Sorry about the transformer.
Let me introduce you to your team.
Oh, of course, an American.
Actually, my brother and I
were born in the UK, but thank you.
Yeah, but you've got the old
Stars and Stripes on your arm there,
and a cowboy look in your eye.
Oh, no offense.
This is just a serious situation,
and the last thing we need is some
Washington stooge to come supervise us.
Do we, lads?
Well, you got one,
so how about we start
with names and positions?
Mmm-hmm.
Adisa, structural.
Duncan Taylor, systems and OS analyst
and loyal British subject.
Hernandez, robotics.
Dussette.
Satcom and security.
And you are?
This is Mr. Jake Lawson.
You're Jake Lawson? The Jake Lawson?
You look much older
than I would've thought.
I mean, you look good...
...but your physical appearance is not,
does not match the amount of time
that has elapsed in your life.
Am I getting fired?
Okay, we don't have
a lot of time.
So we have three situations to examine.
Afghanistan, the scientist that died
here, and the new incident in Hong Kong.
Hong Kong?
No, that was a gas main explosion.
We all watched that on the telly.
All right, okay.
You just keep believing that.
I, on the other hand,
have a mystery that I'd like to solve
and prevent more deaths,
so feel free to join me.
Or not.
All right, quick question.
Okay, active shooter,
the president and I are both
in the line of fire.
Who do you save first? Me--
The president.
Oh, come on. You could take
a second just to think about that.
Sorry, baby.
Job comes first, same with you.
No, that's not true.
No, I have priorities and you,
you are my priority.
Come on, let's do it.
I kinda want to,
but you just keep talking.
I mean, why do we always
have to be sneaking around?
Come on, let's do it. Let's get married.
We can't.
It's against the rules.
One day, baby.
Um, you're gonna get that.
Because your job comes first.
No...
I'm gonna get it 'cause
I don't want it to interfere with this.
See?
Now I might just not save you.
Yeah, hello?
Max, it's Cheng.
Cheng, God, tell me
you're not in Hong Kong.
- Cheng?
- Last night,
I was right in the middle of it.
It was horrible. That's why I'm calling.
Phone service just came back on.
Yeah, well, you're lucky to be alive.
- I mean, those gas pipes?
- I'm not so sure that was the cause.
What do you mean? I don't follow.
It was abnormally hot
before the pipes blew.
The satellite sensor
should've recorded it, right?
I checked over a dozen times but I can't
access Dutch Boy's Hong Kong satellite.
My access has been blocked.
Check your HoloFrame.
I don't understand.
We both have clearance.
Exactly.
The only people that have authority to
block are in the building you work in.
Wait. What do you mean?
If someone is covering up
a system defect,
there's potential for critical failure
on a global scale.
If Dutch Boy has a catastrophic failure,
it can create something far worse than
the very thing we're trying to prevent,
what we call a geostorm.
What? Slow down, Cheng, all right?
A what?
A geostorm.
Simultaneous catastrophic weather events
triggered all over the globe.
Once they pass a minimum threshold, the
storms will start causing new storms,
like a chain reaction,
until they merge together.
It's gotta be a glitch.
I'll give you a call
when I know something.
All right. Thanks.
These pipes had not been
well maintained or upgraded in years.
Cheng thinks Hong Kong
has something to do with Dutch Boy.
You know, he's implying
some kind of cover-up.
I just got a text and POTUS
called a last-minute press briefing.
What, you can't stay?
Oh, when duty calls, duty calls.
"Neither rain nor snow
nor gloom of night," right?
Honey, that's the Postal Service.
We're the Secret Service.
Secret Service.
Oh, there's a difference?
Really?
I didn't know that.
Grab his laptop. Let's go.
So the satellite that went rogue
over Afghanistan, what type was that?
That's my fave, actually.
I call it a "rock 'n' roller."
Oh, the SR-22.
Uses sonic waves to slow
molecular movement causing cooling,
but, in that case, freezing. Why?
We don't know.
We checked the satellite's hard drives,
but the logs were wiped clean
by the malfunction.
All right. Let's pull up every
"rock 'n' roller" satellite we have
to see if we can find
any corruption in their logs.
Pull up every "rock 'n' roller"
in the net.
There's gotta be more than
1,000 of them.
Ah, 1,270, to be exact.
And we're gonna scan
each and every one of 'em.
Dana. Hey.
Hey. What are you doing here?
What do you mean,
"What am I doing here"?
I work here. I'm your boss.
Yeah, but what are you doing
down from Mount Olympus
and visiting me in Millennial Village?
Well, I have a bit of a favor
to ask you.
You're the best at what you do.
But I need you to keep this between us.
Okay.
I have a problem with my HoloFrame.
Do I look like a Genius Bar to you?
I'm sorry. I'm sitting here
defending the free world
against state operators
and cyberterrorists,
but Grandpa needs help fixing his phone.
I have a problem trying to get through
to satellite G-22 over Hong Kong.
So a satellite has a bad comm.
That happens.
No. No, not a satellite.
All of them.
Oh.
I am mildly intrigued. Stay.
Okay.
It looks like vanilla line disruption,
bad server relay, or trunk failure,
or something.
Are you still dating
that Secret Service chick?
What? No.
No, I'm not dating anyone.
Mmm-hmm.
Wait, look. Oh, my God.
Someone wanted to block your access
without you knowing it was intentional.
But this...
This is very intentional,
and it's very clever.
And I know what you're gonna say.
You're gonna say,
"Tell no one." And I won't.
But I didn't sign up to work here
so I could cubicle-squat 24/7.
So whatever is going on,
I want in on the action.
Well, let's hope there isn't any action.
And yeah,
tell no one.
Miss Fassbinder, we've just been given
a priority communication request.
From Climate Command?
The White House.
All right. So who are the yahoos in
Washington we gotta deal with on this?
I guess I would be the head yahoo.
Hello, guys.
Max tells me you don't have
a high opinion of politicians.
I didn't say that.
Well, neither do I.
We went through hell getting
the world on board for this program.
We've come too far for it to fail.
You and I both understand
why we cannot let that happen.
Yes, sir.
So if I find anything,
I'll report to you right away.
Actually,
you'll be reporting to Max here.
Good luck.
Have at it.
Thank you, sir.
I'll leave you two alone.
And if you need me, I'm in my office.
Thank you.
I'll be reporting to you?
You lied to me.
Again.
No, I just didn't answer
your ridiculous demand.
How do I switch this thing off?
There's something you need to know.
We've been having issues down here
accessing the Dutch Boy satcom.
We have reason to believe that it...
Well, it may not be accidental.
Might not be accidental?
Well, I've been trying to access
the Hong Kong satellite.
I knew it. I knew it!
You think it's possible?
Yeah. It's possible.
But even if you could access
the Hong Kong satellite remotely,
you're not gonna get the logs you need.
No. We gotta pull that information
from the actual satellite up here.
Okay. I can authorize that.
I don't need your authorization
for anything.
I'm sure that's really scary for you,
but how about you just count on me
to do my job, and say thank you?
Oh, count on you.
Remember the first time
I had to bail you out?
Oh, God. Jesus Christ!
Yeah, it was just one week
after Mom and Dad died.
You got arrested for fighting. Hmm?
That's when I realized that
despite everything I was going through,
I was gonna have
to be responsible for you.
All right, you know what?
Fine. It is what it is.
I guess I got no choice
but to count on you.
But if you ever authorize anything
without my approval,
you'll be on the next shuttle home.
Transmission ended.
Hong Kong satellite 022
inbound for examination.
All right.
Let's take this thing apart
and find out what happened in Hong Kong.
Bring it down.
It should have come down by now.
What is that?
I have no idea.
- All right, shut it down.
- It's not responding.
Jesus, Hernandez!
Get down!
Get out of here! Go!
Somebody, open this door, now!
Watch out!
Shit!
All right, let's pick up
every single piece of this thing
and get it down to manufacturing.
Do you think we can retrieve
the logs from the hard drives?
Well, the accident created
an electrical short
and fried all the drives.
I mean, look at it. It's toast.
So we've lost all the drives
with possible corruption?
Not all of them.
What do you mean?
I was reviewing your video
of the accident that killed Makmoud.
Each of the panels that blew
has a drive inside.
And one of them got stuck
in the communication tower.
It looks like
the seal locks are still intact.
If we're lucky, the corrupted drive
will still be inside.
We gotta get that panel back.
Yeah, hello?
I just got into DC. We have to meet.
I figured it all out.
Meet me at 10:00 at the place across
the square where we used to have lunch.
Back in college.
All right. Yeah, I'll be there.
Ready to decompress.
All right. Door's open, kids.
You're clear to exit.
Step across the gravity threshold
and follow me.
Let's just get the panel,
see what's on those drives.
Okay.
There's the panel.
Wait. Hold up.
We designed the tower
to have emergency de-rig ports
so the bars can be moved easily.
Control, the panel is secured.
Roger that.
Come back now, kids. Come back.
We're on our way back.
Jake, what's happening?
I don't know! I don't know!
Jake? Jake!
I can't control the damn suit!
- What's going on?
- His suit is malfunctioning.
- Jake, do you read me?
- Duncan, tell him to cut it.
Jake, cut off the fuel intake.
It's not responding!
Hang on, Jake.
I can't hold it.
Eject the pack. Eject the pack!
Oh, Christ. We're gonna lose him.
We're gonna lose him!
Are you all right?
Yeah.
You got the drive?
I grabbed it when I freed the panel.
You smashed up a dozen comm links,
TCAS sensors...
I'm fine, thank you very much.
What happened out there?
Propulsion throttle locked up.
And you lost the door panel,
which means no drive codes.
Back to square one.
Great.
Why didn't you tell them
about the drive?
Because someone just tried to kill me.
I know my crew. I trust them.
You think you know them.
But someone doesn't want us
to see what's on this drive.
Jake,
there's no corruption here at all.
The doors weren't accidentally
blown off. They were programmed to.
- This wasn't a malfunction.
- No.
Someone intentionally killed Makmoud.
No doubt the same person that tampered
with the Hong Kong satellite.
The user logins have been wiped clean.
We have no digital fingerprints.
No. That's what they think.
Login records are synced back
to the mainframe.
Yeah, but that's the problem.
If they're deleted in one place,
they're deleted everywhere.
No, everywhere they know about.
When we built Dutch Boy,
we put in a locked off library.
Something that would track
and archive everything.
Our saboteur's login info
is gonna be in there.
Nope.
You've been locked out.
But by who?
The virtual conference room.
How many have access
to those transmissions?
Anyone with level three access
and above.
Dozens of people.
Max.
- Max.
- What?
Relax. He'll be here soon.
What, really? I seem nervous?
Just a little.
He's here.
He's here?
No! No!
Cheng! My God!
No!
This is Agent Wilson.
Yes, I need an ambulance right now.
- Dupont Circle.
- Max...
Agent Wilson,
I have dispatched the ambulance.
You got me. You got me.
I'm here. Look at me. Look at me.
Zeus. Zeus.
What?
Virtual conference initiating.
Max? You okay?
They said it was urgent.
What is it?
Yeah. Um...
I wanted to apologize.
Apologize?
If you had any idea
what I just walked away from...
You're gonna drag me up here
just to apologize?
All right. Fine.
Apology accepted.
Hey, Max, we don't walk out
on each other.
That's the unspoken code
between brothers.
You remember that day
Dad took us fishing?
Yeah, he dropped his cell phone
in Key Biscayne.
Proof the Lawsons aren't fishermen.
Four hours,
the three of us didn't catch a thing.
I tried to sabotage Dad's reel
so we could leave.
That pin
at the highest part of the spool,
pulled it so the level mechanism
would pop out.
Of course, Dad was a government spy
his whole life, caught me red-handed.
"Trust me," he said.
"I get it. No one likes to fail.
"But I'd rather not catch fish
with my family
"than catch 20 fish alone."
I didn't even understand
what he meant back then.
But I do now.
Take care, Max.
End transmission.
Transmission ended.
What was all that?
That was the first decent conversation
we've had in years.
- Hey.
- Oh, my God!
Would you relax?
What?
Do you have a moment?
Yes! I do. I got your message.
Jesus.
What happened?
Did Secret Service Barbie dump you?
I need to show you something.
Take a look at this.
You remember that day
Dad took us fishing?
He dropped his cell phone
in Key Biscayne.
Our dad never took us fishing.
Oh.
That's sad.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I'm not good at the, like,
"Talk about your daddy issues"
kind of friend thing. I just...
What? No, no, no...
It's a code.
"He dropped his cell phone
in Key Biscayne."
His cell phone number is the key.
Take a look at the digits.
Okay, you got your first number,
that's your first word.
Second number, nine,
you move on nine words.
- That's your second word.
- Mmm-hmm.
Third number, nine again.
Another nine, you move on. Then nine,
then two, then nine, then five,
and so on and so on until you get
an entirely different message.
Oh. So, who came up
with this encryption, a 12-year-old?
No. I was 13.
Okay.
So, one-nine-nine-nine,
two-nine-five-five,
eight-seven-one and go.
Proof of sabotage at
the highest level of government.
Trust no one.
Well, you said
you were looking for action.
Uh, yeah, but I mean, holy shit.
If you don't wanna take this any
further, I totally understand.
No. I do, I do. I just...
I do and I don't.
Kinda like going on a rollercoaster
or eating Chipotle.
What's our next move?
Okay. I need you to find anything
you can on a file named "Project Zeus."
"Project Zeus"?
Yeah.
Okay. Looks like we have ourselves
a bro-spiracy theory.
- Just run the damn search.
- Yeah.
Um...
I am getting a hit.
But it looks like it's double encrypted.
It's a little OCD.
Can you break it?
Yeah, I could,
but I can't do it from here.
The file's under a White House security
network, and it's just not hackable.
I'd have to log in,
and I don't have the credentials for it.
Shit. Neither do I.
I don't know anyone who does.
Yeah, you do.
Max?
Freeze.
Oh! Holy shit!
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
Honey, relax!
Who is this girl in our house?
I can explain everything.
Mmm, that sounds really pervy.
- Shut up.
- Okay, I'm sorry. I will.
I broke one of your wine glasses. Um...
It just fell and I promise
I'm gonna reimburse you.
I have the money. I'm sorry.
Talk.
This is Dana.
She works with me in State.
Now, I asked her here
because I need her help,
and as it turns out,
I need your help, too.
She's hot!
I know how much
your job means to you.
I took an oath, Max.
We have rules.
Technically, you're not supposed
to be sleeping together either--
Dana.
You're asking me to commit a crime.
You're soliciting a Secret Service agent
to break into the White House server
and illegally obtain files.
And you thought I would say yes!
- I still think you're gonna say yes.
- Why?
Because I'm the one who's asking you.
And if I'm asking you,
well, then it must be important.
And you know that it's bigger
than you and me.
"You and I."
Shut up.
Sarah, please.
One time.
We need to play back the security
cameras without alerting anyone.
Someone killed Makmoud.
We find out why,
we know who's behind this.
But you can't access the cameras
without it being logged in.
That's why we're going to the back-up
server room.
You see? It comes in handy
that I built the place.
Yes, but I live here.
Show off.
Makmoud was prepping diagnostics
on the Afghan sat
while we launched a replacement.
Son of a bitch.
He pulled something off the sat.
Poor bastard figured it out,
and they killed him to make sure
no one else did.
There are no cameras allowed
in the locker rooms.
Then let's go take a look for ourselves.
181.
What's the code?
Seven, six, three, six, three.
What do you think
you're doing?
You know what happened to me out there
wasn't an accident.
Whoever did that
killed Makmoud.
And what makes you think it is not me?
Because if it was you,
I'd be dead already.
Dussette, lower your gun.
Whatever you're looking for,
it is not in this locker.
I was here when Makmoud came in.
He put his stuff in an empty one.
Why didn't you tell me?
You watched the same
security footage as I did.
I was just waiting to see who was
gonna come and look for Makmoud's stuff.
It's in here.
Two, six, six, five, three.
Bingo.
This is everything he copied
off the satellite onto his HoloFrame.
That's a virus.
That wasn't generated by the satellite's
onboard computer.
Because they were planted.
Makmoud found the virus and got killed
before he could tell anyone.
Oh, I got it.
All right, here we go.
Project Zeus.
There are tens of thousands of
storm simulations in here,
and each one is starting
in a different place.
They all end the same way.
A geostorm.
I mean, unlike anything we've ever seen.
Dana, can you show us just the
simulation that begins in Afghanistan?
Yeah, sure.
Okay, now filter those
so that the second malfunction's
over Hong Kong.
Where are you going with this?
What if Cheng realized that someone
was following one of his scenarios?
You know, making it look like
a predicted pattern of malfunction,
disguising a crime
like a series of accidents.
It might actually be
a series of accidents.
If it were,
they wouldn't have killed him.
Someone has weaponized Dutch Boy.
Virtual conference initiating.
Hey.
New face?
Yeah. A friend.
Uh, she's keeping things off
the monitor channels,
so we're good.
- So you got my message?
- Yeah, I got your message.
It's, uh... It's worse than we thought.
Whoever's doing this is using
Dutch Boy to target cities.
Yeah, they're disguising their moves
as malfunctions.
They already killed the man
who found out about this,
and I don't think they're done.
Yeah.
This was my life's work, Max.
You know, they said it was impossible,
but we pulled it off.
And it worked
perfectly, without fail,
day after day, year after year.
So what do people do with it?
Turn it into a gun.
I know.
I know. It's not too late.
We can fix this
before it happens again,
but I can't do it on my own.
I need you. I need you to tell me,
how are they controlling Dutch Boy?
- I know how they're controlling it.
- How?
A virus.
Well, can you stop it?
There's only one way.
We can shut down Dutch Boy temporarily.
The reboot will flush out the system,
kill the virus, and revert back
to the fail-safe OS.
Okay. Let's do it.
I'm authorizing.
Yeah, I think we've established
that I don't really wait for that.
This isn't a Chromebook.
You don't just put your finger
on the power button.
You need the kill codes.
And the only one who has those
is the president.
So let's just go to the president
and tell him what we know.
No. You can't go to Palma.
We need way more proof than I have.
We're talking about shutting down
Dutch Boy.
I mean, even for an hour,
that puts the whole planet at risk.
No, I don't think you understand.
Someone sealed off the backdoor
into the system.
A backdoor almost no one knew existed.
But the president did.
No. Jake, come on. What?
Are you out of your mind?
Not saying it's him. I'm saying,
"What if?"
Who else has the resources
to pull this off?
Murder, cover-up, a virus that can only
be stopped with the codes in his pocket.
Why? Huh? Tell me, why?
Why would he do that?
We're two weeks away from transferring
Dutch Boy to the rest of the world.
Two weeks away from losing
autonomous control.
Now, he talks a good game,
but he's never gonna let it happen.
A series of disasters,
an international crew to take the fall,
and he'll have to cancel the hand off.
And who would blame him?
All right. You stay on top
of your satellites.
Max.
Max, don't do anything stupid.
Let's go.
Okay? They already
tried to kill me once.
Max!
Transmission ended.
President Palma,
a couple questions, please, sir.
Thoughts before you head to
the national convention in Orlando, sir?
Mr. President, do you care
to make a statement?
Mr. President, a moment
before you head to Orlando?
My friends
from Washington, D.C.
I could never get on a plane without
saying hello to you. It's impossible.
What are you doing here?
- Are you insane?
- Sarah, look.
Jake needs us to
steal the kill codes from Palma.
Us?
You're asking me to help you
on the word of your asshole brother,
who you haven't even spoken to
for three years.
Yeah.
Think about it. Afghanistan, Hong Kong,
Cheng, the crazy sim shit,
the death on the space station. Come on.
Look, you gotta trust me on this,
all right? I'm not kidding around here.
- Okay.
- Look.
The codes are on Palma's HoloFrame.
We can't do it on the plane.
Why not?
Too many eyes. He's never alone.
All right, then what's the play?
Palma wants some private time to shower
and make calls before the after-parties.
You follow. I'll get you inside.
I can steal the codes while he's
in the shower.
- That's the idea.
- Yes, it is.
- Warning.
- Out of the way.
All satellite communication offline.
All crew report to stations immediately.
Oh, my God.
We have nearly 200 satellites
reporting malfunctions,
most of them nearing critical.
Pull up the satellite closest to
critical overload.
We've lost all control
of the Tokyo satellite.
Max.
I didn't know you were coming
to the convention.
Yeah. You know,
my dad lives in Florida,
so I promised I'd get him
into the convention.
We need every vote, right?
Yeah, well, bring him to the green room.
We'll do a little photo op.
Oh, that's very kind of you, sir.
Thank you.
We've got reports of extreme weather
anomalies building
over Brazil, Mexico, Bucharest,
and Belgrade.
There's over 1,000 storm warnings
issued around the world.
Rio de Janeiro satellite critical.
Retrieval routine offline.
Chart a new course!
Get us close to the nearest satellites
going critical.
- What are you trying to do?
- We're gonna launch the replacements.
- As many as we can, as fast as we can.
- Wait, wait, wait...
We have to retrieve the other
satellites first.
Or the replacements will crash
into them.
They're programmed to arrive
in the exact same destination.
And they'll knock out
the infected satellites.
- Yeah.
- Of course!
All crews report to stations
for Rio satellite replacement.
Go for launch.
Away she goes.
Satellite replacement for Rio
on its way.
Warning. Satellite on collision course.
Disable the retro-boosters.
Don't let it slow down.
Load 'em up and keep 'em coming!
Warning. Geostorm alert.
Time to geostorm: one hour, 30 minutes.
Four more years!
Thank you. As you know,
the environment
was my late wife's
great passion and purpose.
And I know that she would be
extremely proud...
Caused by
the worst hailstorm in recorded history.
There has been another extreme weather
event, this time in Rio de Janeiro.
An offshore cold front moved rapidly
across land,
plunging the city into
dangerously low temperatures.
There are reports
of numerous casualties,
but we don't know how many at this time.
We're also hearing that a cargo plane
may have crashed in the city itself,
possibly related to the freezing cold.
Tokyo and Rio are the first catastrophic
events since the launch of Dutch Boy.
Stay tuned after the break, when we'll
be joined by our reporter Sally Jones.
Oh, God.
Hey, Max!
Where's your daddy?
Oh. Uh...
You know what? He got so caught up
in all the excitement.
I recruited you for this position.
I know everything about you.
Your brother, and your mother's death,
your father's death, everything.
Why'd you lie to me, hmm?
Why'd you insist on making this trip?
Tell me what's wrong.
Maybe I can help you, maybe I can't.
All right, look.
I gotta tell you something. Come here.
We are 90 minutes away from
a global storm we won't recover from.
And I need the president's kill codes.
Come again?
We gotta shut Dutch Boy down, now.
You're serious.
You say you hired me
because you believe in me, right?
All right, well, I need you
to believe in me now.
Well, we've gotta brief the president.
Get to Cape Canaveral.
No, no, no. We can't do that, sir.
Why not?
I believe he's the one who initiated it.
United we stand.
United we can.
Four more years! Four more years!
You better be goddamn sure of yourself,
making accusations like that.
With all due respect, we don't have time
to argue about this.
Palma and I go way back.
Why would he do that? That's insane.
Yeah, well, he's doing it.
What's your proof?
Yeah, I got proof.
Dozens of files, all right?
In Project Zeus. It's all there.
Well, we can't get the kill codes
from the president.
Why not?
Because the president is the kill codes.
Biometrics. Ten fingerprints,
two retina scans.
Well, what do we do?
I'll have to reason with him.
We'll have to reason with him.
Satellites are
going critical over Florida.
Load a replacement sat, now.
Station
self-destruct sequence initiated.
Phase one commencing now.
Okay. Shut that down!
I can't. I'm locked out.
We built in backdoor overrides.
Yeah, I'm trying them.
If we lose the station, we won't be able
to control the satellites.
Self-destruct?
Why would you build that
into the station?
In case it fell to Earth.
Where's Duncan?
He's the one with enough programming
expertise to override the commands.
Duncan.
That's the fuel tanks.
They're the first to go.
Then section by section
until command and retrieval.
Okay, everybody, get to the shuttles!
Evacuate!
Come on, we gotta hurry! Go, go, go!
Jake, what are you still doing here?
That felt good.
Been wanting to do that
since I first met you.
Have you gone mad?
Yeah, pretty much.
The virus.
You're the only one that could have
put it in the system.
You're the only one who could've
sealed off the backdoor.
The only one that could've helped
to pull this off.
I need the overrides for the
self-destruct to the station, now!
I mean, what for?
I'm not gonna be here when it blows.
But you will.
Come on, man. Why'd you do it?
Well, you know what us
lowly scientists get paid?
Take that times 1,000.
What difference is it gonna make?
If you don't stop, there's not gonna be
a planet to spend it on.
Please. We're gonna keep
all the best bits.
Aren't you a little bit curious
to watch the world burn?
No. 'Cause millions of people
are gonna die.
And one of them's my daughter.
Oh, shit.
Holding room for the president
down on the left.
We'll confront him there.
Project Zeus.
Did Cheng tell you anything else?
Cheng?
But this president
knows that hope is not a plan.
This president knows
that despite how far we've come,
there is much more work ahead.
Working to save our planet
is my first priority as vice president.
This is but a stepping stone
to the success
and greatness that can and will be
the future of our society.
Excuse me.
That's why I'm here tonight with
the Speaker of the House,
the Senate pro tempore,
and President Palma's whole cabinet.
We all stand united in support...
Palma doesn't leave the building.
- Yes, sir.
- Let's go.
Where have you been?
Come here.
It's not the president, all right?
It's Dekkom.
Dekkom? How do you know?
Because he just tried to kill me.
That's how I know.
Look, the sim shows Orlando
is the next city to be hit.
Here? Why would he do that?
Because Dekkom wants Palma
trapped here, all right?
And everyone else who's next in line
for the presidency.
Are we still stealing the codes?
The president is the kill codes,
all right? They're biometric.
If Palma dies,
Dutch Boy can't be stopped.
Sure, kidnap the president.
That sounds like the reasonable move.
Yeah, well,
it's the only move we've got.
Unless you wanna steal his fingers
and his eyes.
Huh?
We go now.
You get us a car.
I'll get us a president.
All right, good.
The program did not gain
the immense
international support that it...
Gunman spotted. POTUS is compromised.
Evac to secure location Alpha.
Get him out, get him out!
Go, go, go.
Secret Service! Get back! Get back!
You got a 20 on the shooters?
Front mezzanine by exit 212!
Two men with automatics!
- I'm on it! You get POTUS!
- You two,
secure this entrance!
No one comes down this hallway!
Nobody gets through! Hard room, Lammy.
- Got it!
- You two,
clear the emergency exit now!
I'm sorry, Mr. President.
You need to come with me.
This exit is off limits!
Please remain calm.
Seriously? A self-driving cab?
Dana jacked it remotely.
It was all I could get.
What the hell's going on here, Lawson?
Please, sir. Look, I'll explain
everything in the car.
Please, sir! We don't have much time!
Keep moving! Get to the shuttles!
Keep going!
Quick!
Time to geostorm, 55 minutes.
Sir, I can barely hear you.
The storm is causing too much static.
The Secret Service
will be homing in
on the beacon
on the president's HoloFrame.
You have got to get to him
before they do.
Under no circumstances can he make it
out of Orlando.
Our man on the space station
did his job.
- Now you do yours.
- Copy that. Got it.
- Dekkom?
- It's the perfect weapon, sir.
All right, Dekkom is trying to change
the map of the world.
And what? Blame it on a computer glitch?
Yeah, well, that and a dead president.
He'll take office after wiping out
everyone in the line of succession.
Dear God.
- Get to cover! Under the bridge.
- Sir.
You are implicating
the Secretary of State in this.
Do you realize you're committing--
Treason. Oh, yeah.
I kidnapped the president.
I've stolen state secrets.
Anything I'm forgetting, honey?
Honey?
Guilty.
It took years
for Dekkom to plan this, sir.
A president's schedule
always changes last minute.
This is the one day and date
he could be sure wouldn't move.
Having my brother and I
lead the investigation
was a setup from the start.
Think about it.
He hired us to fail.
Get down!
All right, it's saying
we're back in the clear,
where the four meets the 91!
Just gotta take care
of a little problem first.
Hold on!
No!
Marry her.
No. We're fine here.
A lightning storm in Orlando
has caused a horrific explosion
at the DNC.
There is no official word
on the whereabouts of the president...
I don't know. I don't know.
I just can't get in touch
with Jake.
And we have reports now of explosions
on the space station.
Honey, the Orlando storm is getting
really close to your dad's place.
I can't get through to him.
Has he texted you?
He's not there.
He's there.
Of a major issue on the space station.
Attention all crews.
Now loading final shuttle.
Please board your designated
evacuation shuttles immediately.
Shuttle launch sequence initiated.
Jake.
- I'm not coming.
- What?
When my brother gets those kill codes,
someone has to be here
to execute the program.
No. We need to go.
We haven't heard from him in hours.
I trust him.
You know the reboot
has to be done manually.
Then I stay. I'm the commander.
No.
I'm the only one my brother
will trust with the codes,
so I need your HoloFrame.
You have to insert it manually
at the core of the mainframe.
You can find it, yes?
- Yes.
- Good.
Goodbye, Ute.
Auf Wiedersehen, Jake.
Pull over here.
The president's beacon shows him
heading right towards us.
You really wanna drive back into that?
Yeah, right after it passes,
I'll be the sole survivor,
ready to be sworn in as
the next President of the United States.
Here they come.
Fire.
You thought the president was the only
one who could be tracked?
- How in hell did you--
- How?
Because I'm the goddamn President
of the United States of America.
You're done, Leonard.
He's all yours.
Wait, wait! Wait a minute.
I've given you an opportunity,
Mr. President.
You should take it.
An opportunity? Let him go!
It's genocide, Leonard!
You say genocide,
I say preemptive strike.
You've lost your mind!
Tomorrow the sun will rise.
All our enemies will be gone.
Wiped away as if by the hand of God.
Why would you do this?
Because no one else would.
I'm turning the clock back to 1945,
when America was a shining city on a
hill, not a bank disguised as a country.
By playing God?
What the hell is Dutch Boy
if not playing God?
Ask Max. He knows.
Science is all about playing God.
Sometimes God doesn't play so nice.
Yeah, well,
you know what my brother would say?
What?
Get him outta here!
Let's go, Lawson!
That's my fianc.
Get the president to cover! Hurry!
Mr. President.
We got the kill codes.
You'll have to hurry.
The station is in full shutdown.
What about the crew?
Safe.
But Jake decided to stay.
To reboot the satellites.
Your brother is waiting for you.
Come on.
Virtual conference initiating.
Hey.
Jake.
Jake, it was Dekkom.
Well, I did say I might be wrong.
Mr. President.
How's Hannah?
Oh, she's good. She's safe.
Atlanta wasn't hit.
Thank God.
Identity verified.
Shutdown protocol transfer initiating.
It's gonna take 60 seconds to upload.
How long till the self-destruct?
Eight minutes,
give or take.
Mr. Lawson,
we thank you for your sacrifice.
Wait. What the hell's going on?
You've done your part, Max.
Jake, what is going on?
Now it's time for me to do mine.
No, no, no.
The kill codes don't stop
the self-destruct, do they?
Do they?
No,
only the geostorm.
The station self-destruct
can't be reversed.
Come on, come on.
There must be a way, huh?
Come on. It's all my fault.
I'm the one who put you up there!
Hey, it's okay.
I wanted to go. It was my choice.
God knows,
I haven't always made the right ones.
You know, you were right,
little brother.
I was supposed to look after you.
But you looked after me.
Can you forgive me?
Yeah, always.
Look after my little girl.
Stay in her life.
I will.
We should've done this
a long time ago, huh?
Yeah.
You're a good man, Jake.
I'll see you, kiddo.
Transfer complete.
Time to geostorm: 5 minutes, 51 seconds.
Warning. Core rotation has terminated.
We don't know
what's happening up there.
We just know the station has suffered
a devastating accident of some kind.
We're being told now
it is beyond repair or salvation.
Honey.
He's coming back.
He promised me.
We will keep you updated
with any new developments.
Self-destruct entering phase four.
Code invalid.
Need a hand?
Wrong door.
What're you doing here?
I told you. I live here.
Time to geostorm: 1 minute, 40 seconds.
Uploading kill codes.
Satellite shutdown in process.
When the last satellite
cycles down, let me know.
I'll manually reboot the entire system.
- That should flush out the virus.
- Okay.
Five to go.
Three.
- Come on, baby.
- Two.
And one.
Manual reboot activated.
Status: rebooting.
The net is back up.
The virus is gone.
Transferring control of the net
back to NASA.
Jake!
I've got you!
Warning.
Self-destruct entering final stage.
Best seat in the house.
Ute,
do you believe in a Hail Mary?
Follow me. We gotta get
to the satellite.
I've got you.
We've gotta get away as far as we can
before the final detonation.
Dock releasing.
And it appears
we have lost the space station.
A tragic ending
for the two heroes still aboard.
Hey, Max, take a look.
I'm picking up exhaust flares,
and they're pulsing in a Mayday pattern.
See if we can turn
one of the shuttles around.
Hopefully, someone sees this.
Fingers crossed.
Hernandez, you son of a bitch!
Thank the Mexican.
Yes! Come here. Yes!
A miracle indeed.
The shuttle you see is bringing home
all the ISS crew members
who remained on the station.
Hi, Jake. I'm Sarah, Max's fiance.
Oh, welcome to the family.
Well done, well done, both of you.
Sorry I doubted you, Mr. President.
Yeah, well, you were wrong, Jake, again.
Well, how many times
do I have to tell you?
Never listen to me.
God, it's good to have you back, man.
Good to be back.
It's a nice place
you got here, Jake.
Thank you.
So when you heading back up?
- In a week.
- Yeah?
Yeah, a lot of work left.
But I'll be back.
I know.
- This sucks.
- Yeah, seriously, this is so boring.
You know what?
I can't do this for another second.
Now, why'd you make us do this
in the first place?
I don't know.
I was trying to relive a moment.
A moment? What moment?
We never went fishing with Dad.
You made that whole story up.
Yeah, but that was a good story,
though, huh?
I mean, you gotta give me that.
I mean, it had a moral and everything.
Moral? What moral?
You can't undo the past.
All you can do is face what's ahead.
NASA maintained the satellites
while we rebuilt the space station.
We made it safer, made it stronger.
It belongs to all of us now.
One planet, one people.
And as long as we remember that
we share one future, we will survive.
OLD WOMAN:
Well, my dad was a farmer.
Um... Like everybody else
back then.
Of course,
he didn't start that way.
MAN ON RADIO: Computer
says you're too tight.
Nah, I got this.
Crossing the Straits.
- Shutting it down, Cooper.
- Whoa!
(POWERING DOWN)
Shutting it all down.
No, I need power up!
- FEMALE COMPUTER VOICE: Eject!
- (COOPER SCREAMING)
YOUNG MURPH: Dad?
Sorry, Murph.
Go back to bed, babe.
I thought you were the ghost.
No.
There are no such things
as ghosts, babe.
Grandpa says you can get ghosts.
Yeah, maybe that's 'cause
Grandpa's a little too close
to being one himself.
Back to bed.
Were you dreaming
about the crash?
Get your butt back in bed,
Murph. (LAUGHS)
OLD MURPH: The wheat had died.
The blight came
and we had to burn it.
And we still had corn.
We had acres of corn.
But, uh, mostly we had dust.
OLD WOMAN 1:
I guess I can't describe it.
It was just constant.
Just that steady blow
of dirt.
OLD WOMAN 2: We wore
little strips of sheet
sometimes over
our nose and mouth
so that we wouldn't breathe
so much of it.
OLD MAN: Well,
when we set the table,
we always set the plate
upside-down.
Glasses or cups,
whatever it was,
upside-down.
Shake a leg!
Murph, get a move on!
COOPER: Tom, 4:00 today,
you and me in the barn,
Herbicide Resistance 101.
- Check?
- Yes, sir.
- (INDISTINCT CHATTER ON RADIO)
- (DONALD HUMMING)
Not at the table, Murph.
Dad, can you fix this?
COOPER: What the heck
did you do to my lander?
Wasn't me.
Let me guess.
It was your ghost?
It knocked it off my shelf.
It keeps on knocking books off.
TOM: No such thing as ghosts,
dumb-ass.
- Hey.
- I looked it up.
It's called a poltergeist.
Dad, tell her.
Well, it's not
very scientific, Murph.
You said science was about
admitting what we don't know.
- She's got you there.
- COOPER: Hey.
Start looking after our stuff.
Coop.
All right, Murph,
you want to talk science?
Don't just tell me that
you're afraid of some ghost.
No, you got to go further.
You got to record
the facts, analyze,
get to the how and the why,
then present your conclusions.
Deal?
- Deal.
- All right.
Y'all have a good day at school.
DONALD: Hold up.
Parent-teacher conferences.
Parent.
Not grandparent.
(HONKING HORN)
Slow down, turbo!
That's not a dust storm.
Nelson's torching
his whole crop.
Blight?
They're saying it's
the last harvest for okra.
Ever.
He should've planted corn
like the rest of us.
Now, you be nice
to that Ms. Hanley.
She's single.
What's that supposed to mean?
Repopulating the Earth.
Start pulling your weight,
young man.
Well, why don't you start
minding your own business,
old man.
All right, Murph,
give me second.
Uh-huh.
Third.
(GEARS GRINDING)
- Find a gear, dumb-ass.
- Grind it!
Shut it, Tom!
(TIRE HISSING)
What'd you do, Murph?
Aw, she didn't do nothin'.
Blew a tire is all.
Murphy's Law.
Shut up!
Grab the spare, Tom.
That is the spare.
COOPER: Get the patch kit!
TOM: How am I supposed
to patch it out here?
COOPER:
You got to figure it out.
I'm not always gonna be here
to help you.
What's going on, Murph?
Why did you and Mom name me
after something that's bad?
Well, we didn't.
Murphy's Law?
Murphy's Law doesn't mean that
something bad will happen.
What it means is whatever
can happen will happen.
And that sounded
just fine with us.
Whoa!
Get in.
Get in, let's go.
What about the flat tire?
(ENGINE STARTING)
Yeah.
It's an Indian Air Force drone.
Solar cells could power
an entire farm.
Take the wheel, Tom.
Go, go, go!
Keep that aimed right at it.
Faster, Tom. I'm losing it.
Right at it.
Stay on it.
Here we go. Here we go.
Whoa!
Nice one, Tom.
Dad?
I almost got it.
Don't stop. Don't stop!
Dad!
Tom!
Why? You told me
to keep driving.
Well, I guess that
answers the old,
"If I asked you to
drive off a cliff" scenario.
We lost it.
No, we didn't.
Want to give it a whirl?
This...
Go.
Let's lay her down
right there at the edge
of the reservoir.
Nicely done.
TOM: How long you think
it's been up there?
Delhi Mission Control
went down, same as ours,
- 10 years ago.
- Oh!
So for 10 years?
Why did it come down so low?
I don't know.
Maybe the sun cooked its brain
or it was looking for something.
What?
Give me a large flatblade.
Maybe some kind of signal?
I don't know.
What are you gonna do with it?
I'm gonna give it something
socially responsible to do,
(PANTING)
like drive a combine.
Can't we just let it go?
It wasn't hurting anybody.
This thing needs to learn
how to adapt, Murph,
like the rest of us.
COOPER: So how's this work?
You guys come with?
TOM: I've got class.
This one needs to wait.
What did you do?
They'll tell you about it
when you get in there.
Am I gonna be mad?
Not with me.
Just please try not to.
Hey, relax.
I got this.
Little late, Coop.
Yeah, we had a flat.
And I guess you had to stop off
at the Asian
fighter plane store.
No, actually, sir, that's a...
That's a surveillance drone.
With outstanding solar cells.
It's Indian.
Take a seat.
So, uh...
We got Tom's scores back.
He's going to make
an excellent farmer.
Yeah, he's got
a knack for it.
What about college?
Well, the university
only takes a handful.
They don't really have
the resources to...
I still pay my taxes.
Where's that money go?
There's no more armies.
Well, it doesn't go
to the university.
Look, Coop,
you have to be realistic.
You're ruling my son out
for college now?
The kid's 15.
Tom's score simply
isn't high enough.
What's your waistline?
About 32?
About a 33 inseam?
I'm not sure I see
what you're getting at.
You're telling me
it takes two numbers
to measure your own ass,
but only one to measure
my son's future?
(SIGHS) Come on.
You're a well-educated man,
Coop.
And a trained pilot.
And an engineer.
Okay, well, right now
we don't need
more engineers.
We didn't run out of
television screens
and planes.
We ran out of food.
The world needs farmers.
Good farmers, like you.
And Tom.
Uneducated farmers.
We're a caretaker
generation, Coop.
And things are getting better.
Maybe your grandkids
will get to be engineers...
Are we done here, sir?
No.
Ms. Hanley's here
to talk about Murph.
MS. HANLEY: Murph is a great
kid. She's really bright.
But she's been having
a little trouble lately.
She brought this in
to show the other students.
The section
on the lunar landings.
Yeah, it's one
of my old textbooks.
She always loved the pictures.
It's an old federal textbook.
We've replaced them
with the corrected versions.
Corrected?
Explaining how
the Apollo missions
were faked
to bankrupt the Soviet Union.
You don't believe
we went to the moon?
I believe it was a brilliant
piece of propaganda.
That the Soviets bankrupted
themselves pouring resources
into rockets
and other useless machines.
"Useless machines."
And if we don't want
a repeat of the excess
and wastefulness
of the 20th century, then
we need to teach our kids
about this planet,
not tales of leaving it.
You know, one of those
useless machines
they used to make
was called an MRI.
And if we had any of those left,
the doctors would've
been able to find
the cyst in my wife's brain
before she died
instead of afterwards.
And then she'd have been
the one sitting here,
listening to this instead of me,
which would have
been a good thing,
'cause she was always
the calmer one.
I'm sorry about your wife,
Mr. Cooper.
But Murph got into a fistfight
with several of
her classmates over this
Apollo nonsense.
So we thought it would be best
to bring you in
and see what ideas
you might have for
dealing with her behavior
on the homefront.
All right. (INHALES)
Yeah, you know what? Um...
There's a game tomorrow night.
She's going through
a bit of a baseball phase.
Her favorite team is playing,
and there's gonna be candy
and soda...
I think I'll take her to that.
(WHISTLING)
How'd it go?
I got you suspended.
- What?
- BOOTS ON RADIO: Cooper.
This is Cooper, go.
Coop, those combines
you rebuilt went haywire.
Uh, just reset the controllers.
I did that.
You should
come take a look.
BOOTS: One by one they've been
peeling off the fields
and heading over.
Something's interfering
with the compass.
Magnetism or some such.
(CLATTERING)
YOUNG MURPH: Nothing special
about which book.
I've been working on it,
like you said.
I counted the spaces.
Why?
In case the ghost
is trying to communicate.
I'm trying Morse.
Morse?
Yeah.
Dots and dashes, used...
I know what
Morse code is, Murph.
I just don't think
your bookshelf's
trying to talk to you.
COOPER: Had to reset every
compass clock and GPS
to offset for the anomaly.
DONALD: Which is?
I don't know.
If the house was built
on magnetic ore,
we'd have seen this
the first time
we switched on the tractor.
I hear your meeting at
the school didn't go so well.
(SCOFFS) You heard?
It's like we've forgotten
who we are, Donald.
Explorers, pioneers,
not caretakers.
When I was a kid,
it felt like they made
something new every day.
Some gadget or idea.
Like every day was Christmas.
But six billion people...
Just try to imagine that.
And every last one of them
trying to have it all.
(SIGHS)
This world isn't so bad.
And Tom will do just fine.
You're the one
who doesn't belong.
Born 40 years too late,
or 40 years too early.
My daughter knew it,
God bless her.
And your kids know it.
Especially Murph.
Well, we used to look up
in the sky and wonder
at our place in the stars.
Now we just look down
and worry about
our place in the dirt.
Cooper,
you were good at something
and you never got a chance
to do anything with it.
I'm sorry.
You didn't expect this dirt
that was giving you this food
to turn on you like that
and destroy you.
In April, I believe I'm right,
15th of April, I think.
'Cause this happened
about 1:30, when that thing
came off the top of that canyon.
(CROWD CHEERING)
In my day,
we had real ballplayers.
Who are these bums?
COOPER: Well, in my day,
people were too busy
fighting over food
to even play baseball.
Popcorn at a ballgame
is unnatural.
I want a hot dog.
School says you're gonna
follow in my footsteps.
- I think that's great.
- (SCOFFS)
You think that's great?
You hate farming, Dad.
Grandpa said.
Grandpa said, huh?
Listen, all that matters is
how you feel about it.
I like what you do.
I like our farm.
You're gonna be great at it.
(CROWD CHEERING)
(SIREN BLARING)
Let's get out of here.
COOPER:
All right, it's a doozy.
Uh, gang, let's mask up.
- Tom? Murph? Check?
- CHILDREN: Yep.
Murph, Tom,
you guys shut your windows?
Murph!
YOUNG MURPH: The ghost.
Grab your pillow.
You're sleeping in with Tom.
It's not a ghost.
(WHISPERING) It's gravity.
DONALD: I'm dropping Tom,
then heading to town.
You want to clean that up
when you're finished
praying to it?
It's not Morse, Murph.
It's binary.
Thick is one, thin is zero.
Coordinates.
Nope.
Mmm-mmm.
Here we go.
Thirty-three.
That's it.
- I can't miss this!
- (SIGHS)
Grandpa will be back
in a couple hours, Murph.
But you don't know
what you're gonna find.
And that
is why I can't take you.
Murph?
Grandpa will be home in a while.
Tell him I'll call him
on the radio.
- (YELPS)
- Jeez!
What are you doing?
(LAUGHING)
Oh, you think
this is funny?
Huh?
You wouldn't be here
if it wasn't for me.
Make yourself useful.
(CONTINUES LAUGHING)
(SOFTLY) Hey, Murph?
Murph!
I think this is
the end of the road.
Didn't you bring
the bolt cutters?
That's my girl.
- MALE GUARD: Step away from the fence!
- No, no, no.
Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
I'm not armed.
My daughter's in the car.
(TASING)
(MECHANICAL FOOTSTEPS
APPROACHING)
- MALE GUARD: Don't be afraid.
- (SCREAMS)
TARS: How did you
find this place?
Where's my daughter?
TARS: You had
the coordinates
for this facility
marked on your map.
Where did you get
those coordinates?
(SHOUTING)
Where's my daughter?
Don't make me
take you down again.
Sit down!
Oh, you still think
you're a Marine, pal?
Marines don't exist anymore.
And I got grunts like you
mowing my grass.
Where did you find
those coordinates?
But you don't look
much like a lawnmower.
Think I'll turn you into an
overqualified vacuum cleaner.
WOMAN: No, you won't.
TARS, back down, please.
You know, you're taking a risk
using ex-military as security.
They're old,
and their control units
are unpredictable.
It's what the government
could spare.
(PANTING)
Who are you?
Dr. Brand.
I knew a Dr. Brand once.
He was a professor.
What makes you think I'm not?
Oh, wasn't near as cute, either.
Please, Dr. Brand.
I don't have
any idea what this is.
Now I'm scared for
my daughter and
I want her by my side.
You give me that,
I'll tell you anything
you want to know.
Get the principals
and the girl in
the conference room, please.
Your daughter is fine.
Bright kid.
Must have a very smart mother.
It's pretty clear
you don't want any visitors.
So why don't you
just let us back up
from your fence
and we'll be on our way? Huh?
It's not that simple.
Well, sure, it is.
I don't know anything about you.
I don't know
anything about this place.
Yes, you do.
Dad!
Hello, Cooper.
Professor Brand.
WILLIAMS: Explain to me
how you found this facility.
Kind of an accident.
We stumbled upon it.
We were on a salvage run...
You're sitting in the
best-kept secret in the world.
Nobody stumbles in here.
Nobody stumbles out.
PROFESSOR BRAND:
Cooper... Please.
Cooperate with these people.
Look.
It's kind of hard to explain.
We learned these coordinates
from an anomaly.
What sort of anomaly?
I hesitate to
term it supernatural,
(CHUCKLES) but it definitely
wasn't scientific.
You're going to have to be
specific, Mr. Cooper.
Right now.
It was gravity.
DOYLE: Um...
What sort of
gravitational anomaly?
- Where was this?
- COOPER: Hey.
Now I'm real happy
'cause you're excited
about gravity, bud,
but you're not getting
any answers from us
until I get assurances.
- Assurances?
- Yeah.
Like that we're
getting out of here.
And I don't mean
in the trunk of some car.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Don't you know who we are, Coop?
No, Professor, I don't.
BRAND: You know my father,
Professor Brand.
We're NASA.
NASA?
PROFESSOR BRAND: NASA.
The same NASA you flew for.
COOPER: I heard
they shut you down, sir,
for refusing to drop bombs
from the stratosphere
onto starving people.
When they realized that
killing other people was
not a long-term solution,
then they needed us back.
In secret.
Why secret?
Because public opinion
wouldn't allow
spending on space exploration.
Not when you're struggling
to put food on the table.
Blight.
Wheat seven years ago.
Okra this year.
Now there's just corn.
And we're growing
more than we ever have.
But like the potatoes in Ireland
and the wheat in the Dust Bowl,
the corn will die.
Soon.
We'll find a way, Professor.
We always have.
Driven by the unshakeable
faith the Earth is ours.
Well, not just ours, no.
But it is our home.
Earth's atmosphere
is 80% nitrogen.
We don't even breathe nitrogen.
Blight does.
And as it thrives,
our air gets
less and less oxygen.
The last people to starve
will be the first to suffocate.
And your daughter's generation
will be the last
to survive on Earth.
BRAND: Murph is feeling
a little tired.
I was wondering if she could
take a nap in my office.
Yeah. Thank you.
Okay.
Now you need to tell me
what your plan is
to save the world.
We're not meant
We're meant to leave it.
COOPER: Rangers.
PROFESSOR BRAND:
The last components
of our one versatile ship
in orbit, the Endurance.
Our final expedition.
You sent people out there
looking for a new home?
The Lazarus missions.
Oh, that sounds cheerful.
Lazarus came back from the dead.
Sure, but he had to die
in the first place.
There's not a planet
in our solar system
that could sustain life
and the nearest star's
over 1,000 years away.
And that doesn't even
qualify as futile.
Where'd you send 'em?
Cooper,
I can't tell you any more
unless you agree
to pilot this craft.
You're the best pilot
we ever had.
I barely left the stratosphere.
This team never
left the simulator.
We need a pilot,
and this is the mission
that you were trained for.
Without even knowing it?
An hour ago, you didn't even
know I was alive.
You were going anyway.
We had no choice.
But something sent you here.
They chose you.
Who's "they"?
How long would I be gone?
Hard to know.
Years?
I've got kids, Professor.
Get out there and save them.
Who's "they"?
We started detecting
gravitational anomalies
almost 50 years ago.
Mostly small distortions
to our instruments
in the upper atmosphere.
In fact, I believe
you encountered one yourself.
Yeah, over the Straits.
My crash.
Something tripped
my fly-by-wire.
Exactly.
But of all these anomalies,
the most significant is this.
Out near Saturn,
a disturbance of spacetime.
Is that a wormhole?
It appeared 48 years ago.
And it leads where?
Another galaxy.
A wormhole's not a naturally
occurring phenomenon.
Someone placed it there.
- "They"?
- Mmm-hmm.
And whoever they are,
they appear to be
looking out for us.
That wormhole
lets us travel
to other stars.
It came along
right as we needed it.
They've put potentially
habitable worlds
right within our reach.
Twelve, in fact,
from our initial probes.
You sent probes into that?
Mmm-hmm.
We sent people into it.
Ten years ago.
The Lazarus missions.
PROFESSOR BRAND:
Twelve possible worlds,
12 Ranger launches carrying
the bravest humans ever to live,
led by the remarkable
Dr. Mann.
Each person's landing pod
had enough life support
for two years.
But they could
use hibernation
to stretch that,
making observations on organics
over a decade or more.
Their mission was
to assess their world,
and if it showed potential,
then they could
send out a signal,
bed down for the long nap,
wait to be rescued.
And what if the world
didn't show promise?
Hence the bravery.
You don't have the resources
to visit all 12.
No.
Data transmission back through
the wormhole is rudimentary.
Simple binary pings
on an annual basis
give us some clue as to
which worlds have potential.
And one system shows promise.
One. That's a bit of
a long shot, isn't it?
One system with
three potential worlds?
(CHUCKLES)
No long shot.
Okay.
So if we find a home,
then what?
That's the long shot.
There's a Plan A and a Plan B.
Did you notice anything strange
about the launch chamber?
COOPER: This entire facility's
a centrifuge.
Some kind of vehicle.
A space station?
PROFESSOR BRAND: Both. Plan A.
How do you get it
off the ground?
The first gravitational
anomalies changed everything.
Suddenly we knew that
harnessing gravity was real.
So I started working on a theory
and we started
building this station.
But you haven't solved it yet.
That's why there's Plan B.
The problem is gravity.
How to get a viable amount of
human life off the planet.
This is one way.
Plan B: a population bomb.
Over 5,000 fertilized eggs
weighing in at
just under 900 kilos.
Well, how would you raise 'em?
With equipment on board,
we incubate the first 10.
After that, with surrogacy,
the growth becomes exponential.
Within 30 years,
we could have
a colony of hundreds.
The real difficulty
with colonization
is genetic diversity.
This takes care of that.
But what about
the people here?
You just...
You give up on 'em?
My kids?
That's why Plan A
is a lot more fun.
How far have you got?
Almost there.
You're asking me
to hang everything
on an almost.
I'm asking you to trust me.
(SIGHS)
Find us a new home.
And by the time you return,
I will have solved
the problem of gravity.
I give you my word.
YOUNG MURPH: Go away!
(SIGHING)
Murph.
Go! If you're leaving,
just go.
DONALD: This world was never
enough for you, was it, Coop?
What, because heading out there
is what I feel like
I was born to do?
And it excites me?
No, that does not make it wrong.
DONALD: It might.
Don't trust the right thing
done for the wrong reason.
The why of the thing,
that's the foundation.
And the foundation's solid.
We farmers,
we sit here every year
when the rains fail and we say,
"Next year."
Well, next year
ain't gonna save us,
nor the one after that.
This world's a treasure, Donald,
but it's been telling us
to leave for a while now.
Mankind was born on Earth,
it was never meant to die here.
Tom will be all right,
but you got to
make things right
with Murph.
I will.
Without making promises
you don't know you can keep.
You have to talk to me, Murph.
I need to fix this before I go.
Then I'll keep it broken
so you have to stay.
After you kids came along,
your mom,
she said something to me
I never quite understood.
She said, "Now,
"we're just here to be
memories for our kids."
And I think now I understand
what she meant.
Once you're a parent,
you're the ghost
of your children's future.
(SNIFFLES) You said
ghosts didn't exist.
That's right, Murph.
Murph, look at me.
I can't be your ghost right now.
I need to exist.
They chose me.
Murph, they chose me.
You saw. You're the one
who led me to 'em.
That's exactly why you can't go.
I figured out the message.
One word. Know what it is?
"Stay."
It says, "Stay," Dad.
(WHISPERS) Murph.
You don't believe me.
Look at the books!
Look at this. It says, "Stay."
Why... You're not listening!
It says, "Stay!"
No, I'm coming back.
When?
(SNIFFLES)
(KISSES)
One for you, one for me.
When I'm up there
in hypersleep, or...
(SNIFFLES)
Or traveling
near the speed of light,
or near a black hole,
time's gonna change for me.
It's gonna run more slowly.
When we get back,
we're gonna compare.
YOUNG MURPH: Time will
run differently for us?
(WHISPERS) Yeah.
By the time I get back,
we might even be
the same age, you and me.
"What?" Imagine that!
Aw, Murph...
You have no idea
when you're coming back.
- No idea at all!
- (CLATTERS)
- Murphy...
- (SOBBING)
Murph, don't make me
leave like this.
Come on, Murph!
Don't make me leave
like this, Murph!
(YOUNG MURPH
CONTINUES SOBBING)
Hey...
I love you.
Forever. You hear me?
I love you forever.
And I'm coming back.
I'm coming back.
How'd it go?
COOPER: It went fine.
Just fine.
I love you, Tom.
Travel safe, yeah?
Yeah.
You look after our place
for me, all right?
- All right?
- Uh-huh.
Hey, can I use your truck
while you're gone?
You mean your truck?
I'll make sure
they bring it back.
(ENGINE STARTS)
Look after my kids, Donald!
TARS: Go for
main engine start.
T minus 10...
Dad!
Nine...
Eight,
seven...
Dad!
Six,
five, main engine start, four,
three,
two,
one. Booster ignition and...
Lift off.
All engines look good.
Beginning roll program.
Prepare for
stage one separation.
Stage one.
There is Mach 1.
Everybody good?
Plenty of slaves
for my robot colony?
They gave him a humor setting,
so he'd fit in better
with his unit.
He thinks it relaxes us.
A giant sarcastic robot.
What a great idea!
TARS: I have a cue light
I can use
when I'm joking if you like.
That'd probably help.
Yeah, you can use it to find
your way back into the ship
after I blow you
out the airlock.
What's your humor setting, TARS?
That's 100%.
Let's bring it on down
to 75, please.
TARS: Stage two separation.
COOPER:
All feeds going manual.
DOYLE: Going manual.
Deactivate probe heater
one, two and three.
DOYLE: Check.
Taking control.
TARS: This is handover to you.
DOYLE: ADF check.
COOPER: Over.
Pull thrusters back.
Fuel cells one,
two, three.
DOYLE: 100%.
COOPER: Ex-mites.
It's hard leaving everything.
My kids. Your father.
We're going to be spending
a lot of time together.
We should learn to talk.
And when not to.
Just being honest.
I don't think
you need to be that honest.
Hey, TARS, what's
your honesty parameter?
90%.
90%?
Absolute honesty isn't
always the most diplomatic,
nor the safest form
of communication
with emotional beings.
Okay.
90% it is, Dr. Brand.
We are coming up
on the Endurance.
Twelve minutes out.
Okay. Taking control.
Approaching module port,
500 meters.
It's all you, Doyle.
Nice and easy, Doyle.
Nice and easy.
I'm feeling good.
Take us home.
Lock?
- Target locked.
- DOYLE: Target locked.
- COOPER: Well done.
- Okay, helmets on.
Good job.
Door's not charging.
Never mind.
Cooper, you should have control.
Control here.
Communication with
ring module active.
(WHISPERS) Oh, wow.
TARS: That's initiate.
(BRAND SIGHS)
COOPER: Are we ready to spin?
BRAND: Just a sec.
TARS: Hello, CASE.
Hello, TARS.
All right, we're all set.
Let's do it.
(CHUCKLES)
COOPER: 30% of spin.
One G.
How's gravity
treating you back there?
Well.
Romilly? Hey, you okay?
- Yeah.
- You all right?
Mmm. Yeah,
I just need a minute.
BRAND: Okay, I think
we have some Dramamine
in the hab pod.
I'm just gonna go get that.
Might be in
the cryo-beds.
I'll just be a sec.
Hey, Brand?
Yeah?
- Bring a lot.
- (LAUGHS)
Amelia... Be safe.
Give my regards to Dr. Mann.
I will, Dad.
It looks good
for your trajectory.
We've calculated
two years to Saturn.
That's a lot of Dramamine.
Look after my family,
will you, please, sir?
We'll be waiting for you
when you get back.
A little older, a little wiser,
but happy to see you.
"Do not go gentle
into that good night
"Old age should burn and rave
at close of day
"Rage, rage against
the dying of the light
"Though wise men at their end
know dark is right
"Because their words had
forked no lightning they
"Do not go gentle
into that good night
"Rage, rage against
the dying of the light"
- DOYLE: (WHISPERS) You good?
- ROMILLY: Yeah.
- Okay.
- Thank you, sir.
Here. Pills.
So alone.
We have each other.
Dr. Mann had it worse.
No, I mean them.
Hmm?
COOPER: It's a perfect planet,
and we're not gonna
find another one like her.
No, it's not like
looking for a new condo.
The human race is going to be
adrift,
desperate for a rock
it can cling to
while it catches its breath.
We need to find that rock.
And our three prospects
are at the edge of what
might sustain human life.
Laura Miller's planet is first.
Laura started
our biology program.
COOPER: Mmm-hmm.
BRAND: Uh,
Wolf Edmunds is here.
Tell me about Edmunds.
Oh, uh...
Wolf's a particle physicist.
None of them had families, huh?
No. No attachments.
My father insisted.
They all knew the odds against
ever seeing
another human being again.
I'm hoping we can surprise
at least three of them.
How about Mann?
Dr. Mann?
Well, he's remarkable.
He's the best of us.
He inspired 11 people
to follow him
on the loneliest journey
in human history.
Scientists, explorers.
That's what I love.
You know, out there
we face great odds.
Death, but...
Not evil.
You don't think
nature can be evil?
No. Formidable.
Frightening. But...
No, not evil.
Well, is a lion evil because
it rips a gazelle to shreds?
Just what we take
with us, is that it?
Yeah.
This crew represents
the best of humanity.
Even me, huh?
You know what?
We agreed, 90%.
There you go.
Don't stay up.
I'll be there in a minute.
Just remember, Coop,
you are literally
wasting your breath.
COOPER: Hey, TARS?
Let's go over that trajectory
one more time.
TARS: Eight months to Mars.
Counter-orbital
slingshot around.
Fourteen months to Saturn.
Nothing's changed on that.
Just let me ask you something.
(WHISPERING)
Dr. Brand and Edmunds...
TARS: Why are you whispering?
They can't hear you.
(NORMAL VOICE)
Dr. Brand and Edmunds.
They close?
I wouldn't know.
Is that 90% "wouldn't know"
or 10% "wouldn't know"?
I also have
a discretion setting, Cooper.
Oh.
But not a poker face, Slick.
Hey, guys.
Dad's about to go down
for the long nap.
So I wanted to
give you an update.
Uh...
The Earth looks
amazing from here.
Um...
You can't see any of the dust.
(CHUCKLES)
I really hope
you guys are doing great.
I know you're gonna
get this message.
Professor Brand's assured me
that he's gonna get it to you.
Know that I love you.
Is it him?
DONALD:
I don't think so, Murph.
You must be Donald.
Hello, Murph.
Why are you in my dad's truck?
He wanted me
to bring it for your brother.
He sent you a message.
She's pretty upset
with him for leaving.
If you record any messages,
I can get them
to transmit it to Cooper.
Murph is a bright spark.
Maybe I should fan the flame.
She's already making fools
of her teachers.
So maybe she should come
and make a fool out of you.
So where are they?
Heading for Mars.
The next time
you hear from Cooper,
they'll be coming up on Saturn.
YOUNG TOM: school goes,
the administration wants me
to repeat plant pathology.
Which sucks.
But they said I could start
advanced agriculture
a year early.
All right, I got to go, Dad.
Hope you're safe up there.
DONALD: I'm sorry, Coop.
I asked Murph to say hi,
but she's as stubborn
as her old man.
I'll try again next time.
COOPER: You all right, Rom?
This gets to me, Cooper.
This. This.
Millimeters of aluminum,
that's it, and then nothing
out there for millions of miles
won't kill us in seconds.
You know that some of the finest
solo yachtsmen in the world
don't know how to swim?
They don't know how.
And if they go overboard,
they're done.
We're explorers, Rom.
This is our boat.
Here.
- (DEVICE BEEPS)
- (CRICKETS CHIRPING)
(RAIN FALLING)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
COOPER: This is
from the relay probe?
It was in orbit
around the wormhole.
This is the wormhole,
and every time we'd come around,
we would receive images
from the other side
of the foreign galaxy.
Oh, yeah. Like swinging
a periscope around.
Exactly.
So we got a pretty good idea
what we're gonna find
on the other side, huh?
Navigationally.
BRAND ON INTERCOM:
Guys? Looks like we'll be
approaching the wormhole
in about three hours.
Hey, Coop?
Can we stop the spinning?
- Why?
- Um...
Because we're close enough
to see it now?
All right.
(WHISPERS) Thanks.
There, that's it!
That's the wormhole!
Say it, don't spray it, Rom.
It's a sphere.
Of course it is. You thought
it would just be a hole?
No, it's just that
all the illustrations
I've ever seen, they...
ROMILLY: The illustrations
are trying to show you
how it works.
So they say you want to
go from here to there.
But it's too far, right?
Mmm-hmm.
So a wormhole
bends space like this,
so you can take
a shortcut through
a higher dimension.
Okay, so,
to show that, they've turned
three-dimensional space
into two dimensions,
which turns a wormhole into
two dimensions... A circle.
What's a circle
in three dimensions?
- A sphere.
- Exactly.
A spherical hole.
But who put it there?
Who do we have to thank?
I'm not thanking anybody
until we get out of here
in one piece, Rom.
Any trick to this, Doyle?
No one knows.
(SIGHING)
The others made it, right?
At least some of them.
COOPER: Oh...
Everybody ready to say
good-bye to our solar system?
To our galaxy.
Here we go.
(RATTLING)
(BEEPING)
Your controls won't work here.
We're passing through the bulk.
It's space beyond
our three dimensions.
All you can do
is record and observe.
(BREATH TREMBLING)
What is that?
I think it's them.
Distorting spacetime.
Don't! Don't!
(ALARM BLARING)
(ALARM CONTINUES BLARING)
(ALARM STOPS)
What was that?
The first handshake.
We're...
We're here.
So the lost communications
came through.
BRAND: How?
The relay on this side
cached them.
So years of basic data.
No real surprises.
Miller's site has kept
pinging thumbs up,
as has Dr. Mann's.
Edmunds' went down
three years ago.
Transmitter failure?
Maybe. He was sending
the thumbs up
right until it went dark.
But Miller's still looks good,
though, right?
Because she's coming up fast.
Mmm-hmm.
With one complication.
The planet is much closer to
Gargantua than we thought.
COOPER: Gargantua?
It's what we're calling
the black hole.
Miller's and Dr. Mann's
planets both orbit it.
And Miller's is on the horizon?
ROMILLY: As a basketball
around a hoop.
Landing there takes us
dangerously close.
And a black hole that big
has a huge gravitational pull.
Look, I could swing around
that neutron star to decelerate.
No, no, no, it's not that.
It's time.
The gravity on that planet
will slow our clock
compared to Earth's drastically.
How bad?
Every hour we spend
on that planet will be
seven years back on Earth.
(WHISPERS) Jesus!
Well, that's relativity, folks.
Well, we can't just
drop down there without...
Cooper, we have a mission.
Yeah, Doyle, we have a mission,
and our mission Plan A is
to find a planet that
can habitate the people
that are living
on the Earth right now.
You can't just think
about your family.
Now, you have to think
bigger than that, all right?
I am thinking about my family
and millions of
other families, okay?
Plan A does not work
if the people on Earth
are dead by the time
we pull it off.
No. It doesn't.
That's why there's a Plan B.
Okay. Cooper's right.
We need to think about time
as a resource,
just like oxygen and food.
Going down there
is gonna cost us.
All right, look.
Dr. Mann's data
is promising, right,
but it's going to take us
months to get there.
And Edmunds', it's even further.
Now Miller hasn't sent much,
but what she has sent
is very promising.
It's water, it's organics...
You don't find that every day.
No, you don't.
And just think
about the resources,
including time,
that would be spent
trying to get back here.
- Romilly?
- Yeah.
How far off from Miller's
planet do we have to be
to stay out of the time shift?
Just back from the cusp.
Which is here,
just outside of Miller's planet.
- ROMILLY: Right.
- Okay.
Here's Gargantua.
Here's Miller's planet.
Instead of taking the Endurance
into orbit
around Miller's planet,
which would conserve fuel,
but we would lose a lot of time,
what if we take a wider orbit
around Gargantua,
parallel with Miller's planet,
outside of this time shift,
to here?
Then we take the Ranger down,
we get Miller,
we get her samples.
We come back,
we analyze, we debrief.
We're in, we're out.
We lose a little fuel,
but we save a lot of time.
- That'll work.
- That's good.
There's not gonna be time
for monkey business
or chit-chat down there.
So, TARS, you should
definitely stay here.
CASE, you're with me.
Anyone else can stay.
If we're talking
about a couple years,
I could use the time
to research gravity.
Observations from the wormhole,
that's gold to Professor Brand.
TARS, factor an orbit
of Gargantua.
Conserve fuel,
minimize thrusting,
but make sure we stay
in range of Miller's planet.
You got it?
TARS: I wouldn't
leave you behind,
Dr. Brand.
- COOPER: You ready, CASE?
- Yup.
You don't say much, do you?
TARS talks plenty
for both of us.
(BEEPING)
Detach.
- (RATTLING)
- Romilly, are you reading these forces?
ROMILLY: It's unbelievable.
A literal heart of darkness.
If we could just see
the collapsed star inside
the singularity,
yeah, we'd solve gravity.
And we can't
get anything from it?
ROMILLY: Nothing
escapes that horizon.
Not even light.
Oh, the answer's there,
just no way to see it.
There's Miller's planet.
Good-bye, Ranger.
CASE: This is fast
for atmospheric entry.
Should we use
the thrusters to slow?
No.
No, I'm gonna use
the Ranger's aerodynamics
to save some fuel.
CASE: Air brake?
We want to get down fast,
don't we?
Actually, we want to
get there in one piece.
Hang on.
CASE: Brand, Doyle, get ready.
(PANTING)
(BEEPING)
CASE: We should ease!
COOPER: Hands where I can
see 'em, CASE.
The only time I ever went down
was when a machine was
easing at the wrong time.
- CASE: A little caution...
- Can get you killed,
Just like reckless driving.
DOYLE: Cooper,
it's too damn fast!
I got this.
CASE: Should I disable
the feedback?
No. No,
I need to feel the air.
Here we go.
DOYLE: It's just water!
(PANTING)
The stuff of life.
CASE: 1,200 meters.
Do we have a fix on the beacon?
CASE: Got it!
Can you maneuver?
I'm gonna need to
shave some speed.
I'm gonna spiral down
on top of it.
Everybody hang on!
CASE: 700.
On my cue, CASE. On my cue.
CASE: 500 meters.
(BRAND PANTING)
Fire!
Very graceful.
No.
But very... Efficient.
What are you waiting for?
Let's go!
Go, go, go, go, go!
Seven years per hour here.
Let's make it count!
(BRAND PANTING)
CASE: This way.
About 200 meters.
The gravity's punishing.
Been floating through space
too long?
CASE: 130% Earth gravity.
Come on.
- (BRAND GRUNTING ON RADIO)
- Come on, come on.
There's nothing here.
CASE: Should be right here.
If the signal's coming
from here...
Her beacon.
DOYLE: Wreckage.
Where's the rest?
BRAND: Towards the mountains!
Those aren't mountains.
They're waves.
What? What?
Oh, shit. Oh, shit. Oh, shit.
COOPER: That one's
moving away from us.
BRAND: We need the recorder.
Brand, Doyle,
back to the Ranger now!
BRAND: We're not leaving
without her data.
COOPER: Get back here now!
We do not have time!
A second wave is coming!
We're in the middle of a swell.
BRAND: No, I got it.
Get your ass
back to the Ranger, now!
(BRAND GRUNTING)
Brand, get back here, now!
(GASPS)
BRAND: No, Cooper, go.
Cooper, go. I can't make it.
Go!
CASE, go get her.
Get up! Get up, Brand!
DOYLE: Go, go! Go!
I'm not gonna make it!
Yes, you are. Yes, you are!
(GRUNTING)
Come on, CASE has her!
Get back here, Doyle!
(BRAND CONTINUES GRUNTING)
Come on, Brand!
Get to the hatch!
(PANTING)
Go, go! Go!
(BEEPING)
COOPER: Shit.
Manually overriding
inside hatch!
Cooper! Wait!
Cooper, wait! Wait! Stop it!
COOPER: The engines
are flooded!
I'm gonna have to shut her down.
(BRAND SCREAMING)
(GRUNTS)
(BRAND GASPS)
(GASPING)
Holy shit.
- Hang on!
- (CONTINUES GASPING)
(SCREAMING)
(GRUNTS)
(BOTH PANTING)
CASE, what's the problem?
CASE: Too waterlogged.
Let it drain.
God damn it!
I told you to leave me!
And I told you...
Why didn't you leave me?
To get your ass back here!
The difference is one of us
was thinking
about the mission, Brand!
You were thinking about
getting home.
I was trying to do
the right thing!
Can you tell that to Doyle?
(GASPING)
COOPER: CASE, how much time?
45 to an hour.
(GASPS)
COOPER:
The stuff of life, huh?
What's this gonna
cost us, Brand?
A lot. Decades.
(GROANS)
What happened to Miller?
Judging by the wreckage,
she was broken up by a wave
soon after impact.
How's the wreckage
stayed together
after all these years, huh?
Because of the time slippage.
On this planet's time,
she just landed hours ago.
She probably just died
minutes ago.
CASE: The data Doyle received
was just the initial status,
echoing endlessly.
Oh, we are not
prepared for this.
You eggheads have the survival
skills of a Boy Scout troop.
Well, we got this far
on our brains,
farther than any human
in history.
Well, not far enough!
And now we're stuck here
till there won't be anyone
left on Earth to save.
I'm counting every minute,
same as you, Cooper.
Is there any possibility...
I don't know...
Some kind of way we can maybe
all jump in a black hole?
Gain back the years?
(SCOFFS)
Don't shake your head at me.
Time is relative, okay?
It can stretch
and it can squeeze, but
it can't run backwards.
It just can't.
The only thing that can move
across dimensions, like time,
is gravity.
Okay.
The beings that led us here,
they communicate
through gravity, right?
(WHISPERS) Yes.
Could they be talking to us
from the future?
Maybe.
Okay. If they can...
"They" are beings
of five dimensions.
To them, time might be
another physical dimension.
To them,
the past might be a canyon
that they can climb into
and the future,
a mountain they can climb up.
But to us, it's not, okay?
Look, Cooper, I screwed up.
I'm sorry.
But you knew about relativity.
Oh...
Brand...
(INHALES DEEPLY)
My daughter was 10 years old.
I couldn't teach her
Einstein's theories
before I left.
Couldn't you have told her you
were going to save the world?
No.
When you become a parent,
one thing becomes really clear.
And that is that
you want to make sure
your children feel safe.
And it rules out
telling a 10-year-old
that the world is ending.
CASE: Cooper?
(RUMBLING FROM OUTSIDE)
How long for the engines, CASE?
A minute or two.
COOPER: Well,
we don't have it.
Helmets on!
Brand, co-pilot, you're up.
CASE, blow the cabin oxygen
through the main thrusters!
- We're gonna spark it.
- Roger that.
- Locked.
- Depressurizing.
- Engines up!
- (ENGINES POWERING UP)
Hello, Rom.
I've waited years.
How many...
How many years?
ROMILLY: By now it must be...
TARS: 23 years,
four months, eight days.
Doyle?
I thought I was prepared.
I knew the theory.
(WHISPERS)
Reality's different.
ROMILLY: And Miller?
There's nothing here for us.
(SOFTLY)
Why didn't you sleep?
Oh, I had a couple of stretches.
But I stopped believing
you were coming back.
And something seemed wrong
about dreaming my life away.
I learned what I could
from the black hole,
but I couldn't send anything
to your father.
We've been receiving,
but nothing gets out.
BRAND: Is he alive?
Oh, yeah.
Yeah?
Yeah.
ROMILLY: We've got years
of messages stored.
Cooper.
MALE AUTOMATED VOICE:
Messages span 23 years.
Play it from the beginning.
YOUNG TOM: Hey, Dad.
Checking in. Saying hi.
Um...
Finished second in school.
Miss Kurling's
still giving me C's though.
Pulled me down,
but second's not bad.
Grandpa attended the ceremony.
Um...
Oh.
I met another girl, Dad.
I, uh...
I really think this is the one.
Name's Lois.
That's her right there.
(COOPER SOBBING)
Murphy stole Grandpa's car.
She crashed it.
She's okay, though.
Hey, Dad.
Look at this!
You're a grandpa.
His name's Jesse.
I wanted to call him Coop,
but Lois says, uh,
maybe next time.
Donald says he's already
earned the "great" part,
so we just leave it at that.
Just hold him.
(JESSE GURGLING)
LOIS: Oh, dear.
Say "Bye-bye, Grandpa."
- Bye-bye, Grandpa. It's okay.
- (JESSE FUSSING)
Sorry it's been a while.
It's, uh...
(SOFTLY) Just...
What with Jesse and all.
Uh...
Grandpa died last week.
We buried him out in the
back forty next to Mom and...
Jesse.
Which is where we would have
buried you if you'd ever
come back.
Murph was there at the funeral.
We don't see her that much,
but she came for that.
You aren't listening to this,
I know that.
All these messages
are just, like,
drifting out there
in the darkness.
Lois says that, uh,
I have to let you go.
And, uh...
So...
I guess I'm letting you go.
I don't know where you are, Dad,
but I hope
that you're at peace and...
Good-bye.
Hey, Dad.
(WHISPERS) Hey, Murph.
You son of a bitch.
I never made one of these
when you were still responding
because I was so mad at you
for leaving.
And then when you went quiet,
it seemed like I should
live with that decision.
And I have.
But today's my birthday.
And it's a special one,
because you told me...
(SIGHS)
You once told me that
when you came back,
we might be the same age.
And today I'm the age
you were when you left.
(SOBBING)
So it would be a real good
time for you to come back.
(SWITCHES CAMERA OFF)
(SNIFFLES)
I didn't mean to intrude.
It's just that I've never
seen you in here before.
I've never been in here before.
PROFESSOR BRAND:
I talk to Amelia all the time.
It helps.
I'm glad you've started.
MURPH: I haven't.
I just had something
I needed to get out.
PROFESSOR BRAND: I know
they're still out there.
MURPH: I know.
There are so many reasons
their communications
might not be getting through.
I know, Professor.
I'm not sure
what I'm more afraid of.
Them never coming back,
or coming back
to find we've failed.
Then let's succeed.
So...
Back to the fourth iteration.
Let's run it through
some new fields.
With respect, Professor,
we've tried that
hundreds of times.
It only has to work once, Murph.
Every rivet that
they strike could
have been a bullet.
We've done well
for the world here,
whether or not
we crack the equation
before I kick the bucket.
Don't be morbid, Professor.
I'm not afraid of death.
I'm an old physicist.
I'm afraid of time.
MURPH: Time.
You're afraid of time.
For years, we've been
trying to solve the equation
without changing
the underlying assumption
about time.
- And?
- And that means
Each iteration is an attempt
to prove its own proof.
It's recursive.
It's nonsensical.
Are you calling my life's work
nonsense, Murph?
No, I'm saying
you've been trying to
finish it with one arm...
No, with both arms
tied behind your back.
And I don't understand why.
I'm an old man, Murph.
Can we take this point up
at another time?
I want to talk to my daughter.
PROFESSOR BRAND: Stepping out
into the universe,
we must confront the reality
of interstellar travel.
We must reach far beyond
our own lifespans.
We must think not as
individuals but as a species.
"Do not go gentle
into that good night."
COOPER: TARS
kept the Endurance
right where we needed her.
But the trip took years longer
than we anticipated.
We no longer have the fuel
to visit both prospects, so...
We have to choose.
But how?
They're both promising.
Edmunds' data is better,
but Dr. Mann is the one
still transmitting.
We've no reason to suspect
Edmunds' data would have soured.
His world has key elements
to sustain human life.
As does Dr. Mann's.
Cooper, this is my field.
And...
I really believe Edmunds'
is the better prospect.
Why?
Gargantua, that's why.
Look at Miller's planet.
Hydrocarbons, organics, yes.
But no life. Sterile.
We'll find the same thing
on Mann's.
Because of the black hole?
BRAND: Murphy's Law.
Whatever can happen will happen.
Accident is the first
building block of evolution.
But when you're orbiting
a black hole,
not enough can happen.
It sucks in asteroids
and comets,
other events which would
otherwise reach you.
We need to go further afield.
You once said that Dr. Mann
was the best of us.
He's remarkable.
We're only here because of him.
And yet here he is.
He's on the ground,
and he's sending a very
unambiguous message,
telling us to
come to his planet.
Granted, but Edmunds' data
is more promising.
We should vote.
Well, if we're going to vote,
there's something
you should know.
Brand?
He has a right to know.
That has nothing to do with it.
What does?
She's in love with Wolf Edmunds.
ROMILLY: Is that true?
Yes.
And that makes me
want to follow my heart.
But maybe we've spent too long
trying to figure all this out
with theory.
You're a scientist, Brand.
So listen to me
when I say that love isn't
something we invented.
It's (SIGHS)
observable, powerful.
It has to mean something.
Love has meaning, yes.
Social utility,
social bonding, child rearing...
We love people who have died.
Where's the social utility
in that?
None.
Maybe it means something more,
something we can't
yet understand.
Maybe it's some evidence,
some...
artifact of a higher dimension
that we can't
consciously perceive.
I'm drawn across the universe
to someone I haven't seen
in a decade,
who I know is probably dead.
Love is the one thing
we're capable of perceiving
that transcends dimensions
of time and space.
Maybe we should trust that,
even if we can't
understand it yet.
All right, Cooper...
Yes,
the tiniest possibility of
seeing Wolf again excites me.
That doesn't mean I'm wrong.
Honestly, Amelia,
it might.
(SOBS)
TARS, chart a course
for Dr. Mann's.
We'll lose about a third
again. But next year...
(CLICKS TONGUE)
Next year I'm gonna work
Nelson's farm
and I'll make it up.
What happened to Nelson?
LOIS: Murph,
have you eaten enough?
Would you like
some more souffle?
No, no. I'm full, thanks.
It was delicious.
Coop, finish your fritter,
please.
Will you spend the night?
Your room is exactly
as you left it. It's ready.
I need to get back.
(SNIFFLES)
LOIS: My sewing machine
is in there,
but there's plenty of...
I need to...
Too many memories.
TOM: Well...
We might have
something for that.
Hey, Coop.
(COOP COUGHING)
The dust.
Lois, I have a friend who...
(COOP COUGHING)
could look at his lungs.
COOPER: Amelia, I'm sorry.
You were just being objective.
Unless you're punishing me
for screwing up
on Miller's planet.
No, this wasn't
a personal decision.
If you're wrong,
you will have a very personal
decision to make.
Your fuel calculations are
based on a return journey.
Strike out on Mann's planet,
and we'll have to decide
whether to return home
or push on to Edmunds'
with Plan B.
Starting a colony
could save us
from extinction.
You might have to decide between
seeing your children again
and the future
of the human race.
I trust you'll be
as objective then.
He's been asking for you
since he came to.
We were trying to reach you.
MURPH: (WHISPERS)
Hey.
Murph.
Hi. I'm here, Professor.
(WEAKLY) I let them all down.
No, you got us so far!
Real close.
I'll finish what you started.
Good, good, Murph.
You had faith
all those...
All those years.
I...
I asked you to have faith.
I wanted you to believe
that your father...
would come back.
I do, Professor.
Forgive me, Murph.
There's nothing to forgive.
I...
I lied, Murph.
I lied to you.
There was no need for him
to come back.
There is no...
No way to help us.
But Plan A...
All this. All these people.
And the equation.
Did my father know?
Did he leave me?
Do
Not
go
Gentle...
No.
No!
You can't leave.
You... No.
MURPH: Dr. Brand,
I'm sorry to tell
that your father died today.
He had no pain.
He was at peace.
I'm very sorry for your loss.
(SNIFFLES)
Brand, did you know?
He told you, right?
(BITTER LAUGH)
You knew.
This was all a sham.
You left us here.
To suffocate.
To starve.
(BEEPING)
COOPER: Frozen cloud.
(UNLOCKING)
(COUGHS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(SOBBING)
It's okay.
Pray you never learn
just how good it can be
to see another face.
I hadn't a lot of hope
to begin with, but...
After so long, I had none.
My supplies were
completely exhausted.
The last time I went to sleep,
I didn't even set a waking date.
You have literally
raised me from the dead.
- Lazarus.
- Hmm.
What about the others?
I'm afraid you're it, sir.
So far, surely.
No, our present situation
is that there's very little
chance of rescuing any others.
BRAND: Dr. Mann. Dr. Mann?
Tell us about your world.
(SNIFFLES)
Our world, we hope.
Our world, uh, is cold,
stark,
but undeniably beautiful.
The days are 67 hours long,
cold.
The nights are
67 far colder hours.
The gravity is a very, very
pleasant 80% of the Earth's.
Now, up here where I landed,
the water is alkali,
and the air has too much
ammonia in it to breathe
for more than
just a few minutes,
but down at the surface...
And there is a surface.
The chlorine dissipates.
The ammonia gives way
to crystalline hydrocarbons
and breathable air.
To organics.
Possibly, even to life.
We might be sharing this world.
These readings
are from the surface?
Over the years,
I've dropped various probes.
COOPER: How far
have you explored?
I've mounted
several major expeditions.
But with oxygen
in limited supply,
KIPP there really did
most of the legwork.
TARS: What went wrong
with him, sir?
DR. MANN: Degeneration.
He misidentified
the first organics we found
as ammonia crystals.
He struggled on for a time,
but ultimately
I decommissioned him
and used his power source
to keep the mission going.
I thought I was alone
before I shut him down!
TARS: Would you like me
to look at him?
No. No.
He needs a human touch.
TARS: Dr. Brand, CASE is
relaying a message for you
from the comm station.
Okay. Be right there.
Excuse me.
Dr. Brand,
I'm sorry to tell you
that your father died today.
He had no pain.
He was at peace.
I'm sorry for your loss.
BRAND: Is that Murph?
She's... She's grown.
MURPH: Brand, did you know?
He told you, right?
(BITTER LAUGH)
You knew.
This was all a sham.
You left us here.
To suffocate.
To starve.
Did my father know, too?
(SOBBING) Dad?
I just want to know
if you left me here to die.
I just have to know.
(CONTINUES SOBBING)
Cooper, my...
My father dedicated
his whole life to Plan A.
I have no idea
what she's talking about.
DR. MANN: I do.
He never even hoped to
get the people off the Earth?
No.
But he's been trying to solve
the gravity equation
for 40 years.
Amelia, your father
solved his equation
before I even left.
Then why wouldn't he use it?
The equation couldn't
reconcile relativity
with quantum mechanics.
You need more.
More? More what?
DR. MANN: More data.
You need to see
into a black hole.
The laws of nature prohibit
a naked singularity.
Romilly, is that true?
If a black hole is an oyster,
then the singularity's
the pearl inside.
The gravity's so strong,
it's always hidden
in darkness
behind the horizon.
That's why we call it
a black hole.
Okay, but (BREATHING HEAVILY)
if we see beyond the horizon...
We can't, Coop.
DR. MANN:
There are some things
that aren't meant to be known.
Your father had to
find another way
to save the human race
from extinction.
Plan B. A colony.
Why not tell people?
Why keep building
those damn stations?
Because he knew
how hard it would be
to get people to work together
to save the species
instead of themselves.
Or their children.
Bullshit.
You never would've come here
unless you believed
you were gonna save them.
Evolution has yet
to transcend
that simple barrier.
We can care deeply, selflessly
about those we know,
but that empathy rarely extends
beyond our line of sight.
But the lie.
That monstrous lie?
Unforgivable.
And he knew that.
He was prepared to
destroy his own humanity
in order to save the species.
He made an incredible sacrifice.
No.
No, an incredible sacrifice
is being made
by the people on Earth
who are gonna die!
Because in his arrogance
he declared their case hopeless.
I'm sorry, Cooper,
their case is hopeless.
No. No.
We are the future.
Cooper, what can I do?
Let me go home.
GETTY: You're
absolutely positive?
His solution was correct.
He'd had it for years.
It's worthless?
It's half the answer.
Okay. How do you find
the other half?
Out there? A black hole.
But stuck down here on Earth?
Yeah?
I'm not sure you can.
GETTY: God,
they just pack up and leave.
What are they hoping to find?
Survival.
Damn it.
Murph.
Don't... (SIGHS)
Don't people have
a right to know?
Well, panic won't help.
We just have to keep working,
same as ever.
Yeah. But isn't that exactly
what Professor Brand was
manipulating us to do?
Brand gave up on us.
I'm still trying to solve this.
So...
Do you have an idea?
A feeling.
I told you about my ghost.
My dad thought
I called it a ghost
because I was scared of it.
But I was never scared of it.
I called it a ghost
because it felt...
It felt like a person.
It was trying to
tell me something.
If there's an answer
here on Earth, it's back there
somehow, in that room.
So I have to find it.
(ENGINE STARTING)
We're running out of time.
CASE: What about auxiliary
oxygen scrubbers?
COOPER: No,
they can stay, CASE.
I'll be sleeping
most of the way, anyway.
- Hey, Coop.
- Yeah.
I have a suggestion
for your return journey.
Yeah, what's that?
Have one last crack
at the black hole.
I'm going home, Rom.
Yeah, I know.
This isn't going to
cost you any time.
There's a chance
for the people on Earth.
Talk to me.
Gargantua's an older
spinning black hole.
It's what we call
a gentle singularity.
Gentle?
They're hardly gentle.
But the tidal gravity
is so quick that
something crossing the horizon
fast might survive.
A probe, say.
What happens after it crosses?
After the horizon
is a complete mystery.
So, what's to say there
isn't some way that the probe
can glimpse the singularity
and relay the quantum data?
If he's equipped to transmit
every form of energy
that can pulse.
TARS: Just when did this probe
become a "he," Professor?
TARS is the obvious candidate.
I've already told him
what to look for.
TARS: I need the old optical
transmitter off KIPP, Cooper.
You'd do this for us?
TARS: Before
you get all teary,
try to remember that as a robot
I have to do anything you say.
Your cue light's broken.
TARS: I'm not joking.
I'm gonna need TARS
to remove and adapt
some components from KIPP.
Well, I don't want to disturb
his archival functions.
ROMILLY: Oh, I'll supervise.
All right.
Dr. Mann, we need to find
three secure sites.
One for Brand's lab,
two for habitat.
Once those modules
have landed, you don't
want to move 'em.
Well, I can take you
to the probe sites,
but I don't think this...
These conditions are gonna hold.
I think we should wait.
COOPER: CASE is
headed back down
with the rest
of the distillery equipment.
I'd really like to secure
those sites by nightfall.
Well, these squalls
do usually blow over.
Okay then.
- But you're gonna need a long-range transmitter.
- Got it.
- Are you charged?
- Yeah.
Follow me.
TARS, 72 hours, yeah?
TARS: Roger that, Cooper.
DR. MANN: Brand told me why
you feel you have to go back.
But I'd be remiss if I didn't
at least mention that
a mission such as ours
could certainly use
an extra engineer.
(BEEPING)
You better slow down, turbo.
Safety first, CASE, remember.
CASE ON RADIO:
Safety first, Cooper.
COOPER: I have to
tell you, Dr. Mann,
I'm honored to be
a part of this.
But once we set up base camp
and secure those modules,
my work's done here.
I'm going home.
You have attachments.
But even without a family, I can
promise you that, that yearning
to be with other
people is powerful.
That emotion
is at the foundation
of what makes us human.
It's not to be taken lightly.
(LOIS COUGHING)
How long have you
had that cough?
LOIS: A while.
COOP: Mom lets me
play in here.
I don't touch your stuff.
Just take this gently.
DR. MANN: You know why we
couldn't just send machines
on these missions,
don't you, Cooper?
(PANTING) A machine
doesn't improvise well
because you can't program
a fear of death.
Our survival instinct
is our single greatest
source of inspiration.
Take you, for example.
A father
with a survival instinct
that extends to your kids.
What does research tell us
is the last thing
you're going to see
before you die?
Your children. Their faces.
At the moment of death,
your mind's gonna push
a little bit harder to survive.
For them.
- Deep breath.
- (COOP COUGHING)
Uh, hey, I bet you're Coop.
Why don't you have
a seat here for me?
It's bad.
They cannot stay here.
- Okay?
- Yeah.
ROMILLY: TARS,
what's taking so long?
TARS: Professor,
I am having trouble
completing the boot up.
I don't understand.
(EXHALES HEAVILY)
It's funny.
When I left Earth,
I thought I was prepared to die.
The truth is,
I never really considered
the possibility
that my planet wasn't the one.
Nothing worked out the way
it was supposed to.
COOPER: Let's go.
(BEEPING)
You... (SCREAMING)
(DR. MANN GRUNTS)
All right, hey, buddy,
why don't you give me
a big deep breath?
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(COOP BREATHES DEEPLY)
What is this?
What are you doing?
DR. MANN: I'm sorry! I can't
let you leave with that ship.
We're gonna need it
to complete the mission
once the others realize
what this place isn't.
We cannot survive here.
I'm sorry!
(GRUNTING)
DR. MANN: No!
(SCREAMING)
MURPH: They can't stay
here anymore.
You have to leave right now.
Okay. Let me make something
abundantly clear.
- You have a responsibility...
- Tom!
- GETTY: Oh, Jesus.
- TOM: Coop, get her stuff.
She's going home.
Dad didn't raise you
to be this dumb, Tom!
TOM: Dad didn't raise me,
Grandpa did.
And he's buried out back
with Mom and Jesse.
(PANTING)
You faked all the data?
DR. MANN: Yeah.
(BOTH PANTING)
There's no surface?
No.
I tried to do my duty, Cooper,
but I knew the day
that I arrived here
that this place had nothing.
And I resisted
the temptation for years,
but I knew that
if I just pressed
that button, then
somebody would come and save me.
You fucking coward.
DR. MANN: Yes.
Yes.
(GRUNTS)
Listen, if you're not going
to go, let your family go.
Just, like, save your family.
And we go live underground
with you?
Pray that Daddy
comes to save us?
Dad's not coming back.
He never was coming back.
It's up to me.
You're gonna save everybody?
'Cause Dad couldn't do it.
Dad didn't even try!
Dad just abandoned us!
He left us here to die.
Nobody's going with you.
You gonna wait
for your next kid to die?
(WHISPERING) Get out.
And don't come back.
MURPH: You can keep my stuff.
(YELLING)
Stop it!
(PANTING)
- (GRUNTING)
- No. No!
Dr. Mann,
there's a 50/50 chance
you're gonna kill yourself!
Those are the best odds
I've had in years.
- (SCREAMS)
- (AIR ESCAPING)
(COOPER COUGHING)
(GASPING)
(GRUNTS)
(WHIMPERING)
Don't judge me, Cooper.
You were never tested
like I was.
Few men have been.
You tried your best, Murph.
(COOPER CHOKING)
You're feeling it, aren't you?
The survival instinct.
That's what drove me.
That's what drives all of us.
And it's what's gonna save us.
'Cause I want to save
all of us. For you, Cooper.
I'm sorry, I can't watch you
go through this, I'm sorry.
I thought I could, but I can't.
I'm here. I'm here for you.
DR. MANN ON RADIO: Just listen
to my voice, Cooper.
I'm right here.
(CHOKING)
You're not alone.
(PANTING)
Do you see your children?
It's okay.
They're right there with you.
Did Professor Brand tell you
that poem before you left?
Do you remember?
"Do not go gentle
into that good night
"Old age should burn and rave
"At close of day
"Rage, rage against
the dying of the light"
(COOPER CHOKING)
(GASPING)
(CONTINUES GASPING)
Brand! Help!
- Help! Help!
- Cooper?
(PANTING)
BRAND: CASE!
No air.
Ammonia.
BRAND: Cooper! Cooper,
we're coming! CASE!
- CASE: I have a fix.
- BRAND: Go! Go, go, go!
CASE: And away!
Cooper, we're coming,
hang in there. Don't talk.
Try to breathe as little as
possible. We're almost there.
TARS: There's
a security lockout, sir.
It requires a person
to access function.
- It's all yours, sir.
- Thank you.
BRAND: (PANTING)
Try not to breathe.
We're coming.
We're coming right now.
CASE, come on!
Move, move, move!
We got to go faster, CASE!
Faster, faster, faster!
Hang in there. Come on.
(COOPER WHIMPERS)
I see him, I see him!
CASE, bank! Bank right!
(BRAND GRUNTS)
Cooper! Cooper!
I'm here!
(COOPER WHEEZING)
(INHALING)
Joe, get the water truck!
This data makes no sense.
(BRAND GRUNTS)
(PANTING)
I'm sorry.
What?
Mann was lying!
BRAND: Cooper.
Go. Go.
Romilly.
BRAND: Romilly!
Romilly! Do you read me,
Romilly? Romilly!
TARS: Step back, Professor!
Step back!
(PANTING)
COOPER: Romilly...
BRAND: Romilly,
do you read me?
Keep watch!
Lois?
COOPER: What happened
to caution, CASE?
CASE: Safety first, Cooper.
BRAND: Romilly.
Romilly, do you read me?
This is Brand.
Romilly?
CASE: Dr. Brand? Cooper?
There's been an explosion.
Dr. Mann's compound.
TARS! TARS, ten o'clock!
Let me know when TARS is aboard.
TARS: Romilly did not survive.
I could not save him.
- CASE: TARS is in.
- I'll take it from here.
Do we have a fix on the Ranger?
CASE: He's pushing into orbit!
Ah, if he takes control
of that ship, we're dead.
He'd maroon us?
Oh, he is marooning us.
I'll meet you guys downstairs.
You can wait by the car.
Come on. Give me your bag.
Get in the back seat.
Get in the back seat now!
COOPER: Dr. Mann,
please respond.
Dr. Mann, please respond!
CASE: He doesn't know
the Endurance
docking procedure.
The autopilot does.
Not since TARS disabled it.
Nice.
What's your trust setting, TARS?
Lower than yours apparently.
COOPER:
Do not attempt docking.
I repeat,
do not attempt docking.
Please res...
FEMALE COMPUTER VOICE:
Auto-docking sequence
withheld.
- Override.
- Unauthorized.
Override.
Unauthorized.
Do not attempt docking.
I repeat,
do not attempt docking.
Please res...
(GRUNTING)
Moving slowly
toward the Endurance.
(ALARM BLARING)
FEMALE COMPUTER VOICE:
Imperfect contact.
- Override.
- Hatch lockout.
Is he locked on yet?
CASE: Imperfectly.
Dr. Mann, do not...
(ALARM CONTINUES BLARING)
FEMALE COMPUTER VOICE:
Hatch lockout disengaged.
Dr. Mann, do not, I repeat,
do not open the hatch.
I repeat, do not open the hatch.
If you open the hatch,
the airlock will depressurize.
(BEEPING)
What happens
if he blows the airlock?
CASE: Nothing good.
COOPER: Okay, pull back.
Pull back.
Retro thrusters,
everything we've got, CASE!
- CASE: Retros at full!
- Back!
CASE, relay my transmission
to the on board computer
and have it rebroadcast
as emergency PA.
Dr. Mann...
I repeat, do not open
the inner hatch. I repeat...
Brand?
I don't know
what he said to you,
but I am taking command
of the Endurance.
Then we can talk about
completing the mission.
Dr. Mann, listen to me.
This is not about my life.
(ALARM BLARING)
Or Cooper's life.
This is about all mankind.
(ALARM STOPS)
There is a moment...
It is not sa...
Oh, my God.
(SWITCHES CLICKING)
(GEARS ENGAGING)
CASE: Cooper, there's no point
using your fuel to chase...
Analyze the Endurance's spin.
Cooper, what are you doing?
Docking.
CASE: Endurance rotation
is 67... 68 RPM.
Get ready to match our spin
with the retro thrusters.
- CASE: It's not possible.
- COOPER: No...
It's necessary.
CASE: Endurance
is hitting stratosphere!
BRAND: She's got
no heat shield.
- CASE, you ready?
- Ready.
Cooper! This is no time
for caution.
CASE, if I black out,
you take the stick.
TARS, get ready to engage
the docking mechanism.
CASE: Endurance
is starting to heat.
20 feet out.
TARS: I need 3 degrees
starboard, Cooper.
10 feet out.
TARS: Cooper, we are lined up.
Initiating spin!
(BRAND MUMBLING AND GROANING)
(GRUNTING)
(GASPING)
Come on, TARS.
Come on, TARS!
TARS: We are locked, Cooper.
Locked. Easing up!
Easy.
COOPER: Retro thrusters!
Main engines on.
Pushing out of orbit.
Come on, baby.
Killing main engines!
Okay, we're out of orbit.
(LAUGHING)
Okay. And for our next trick!
(CONTINUES LAUGHING)
CASE: It'll have to be good.
We're heading
into Gargantua's pull.
COOPER: Oh, shit.
- CASE, take the stick.
- Roger that.
(PANTING)
(BRAND GRUNTING AND PANTING)
(GRUNTING)
(PANTING)
- (BEEPING)
- (COOPER GRUNTING)
(GRUNTING)
CASE: Cooper, we're slipping
towards Gargantua.
Shall I use main engines?
COOPER: No.
We got to let her slide
as far as we can.
(BRAND PANTING)
COOPER: Give it to me.
TARS: There's good news
and there's bad news, Cooper.
Yeah, I've heard that one, TARS.
Give it to me straight.
The backup generator kicked in,
so the system's stable.
They're all good.
Good.
Okay. The navigational hub
has been completely destroyed.
We don't have
enough life support
to make it back to Earth, but
I think we can
scratch our way
to Edmunds' planet.
What about fuel?
Not enough.
But I have a plan.
We let Gargantua pull us down
close to her horizon.
Then a powered slingshot around,
launching us towards
Edmunds' planet.
BRAND: Manually?
That's what I'm here for.
I'm gonna take us just inside
the critical orbit.
BRAND: What about
the time slippage?
COOPER: Neither one of us
has time to worry
about relativity right now,
Dr. Brand.
I'm sorry, Cooper.
COOPER: Once we've gathered
enough speed
around Gargantua,
we use Lander 1
and Ranger 2
as rocket boosters to
push us out
of the black hole's gravity.
The Lander's linkages
have been destroyed,
so we'll have to
control manually.
Once Lander 1 is spent,
TARS will detach...
TARS: and get sucked
right into that black hole.
Why does TARS have to detach?
COOPER: Oh, we have to
shed the weight
to escape the gravity.
TARS: Newton's third law.
The only way humans
have ever figured out
of getting somewhere
is to leave something behind.
Cooper, you can't ask TARS
to do this for us.
He's a robot.
So you don't have to
ask him to do anything.
BRAND: Cooper, you asshole!
Sorry, you broke up
a little bit there.
TARS: It's what we intended,
Dr. Brand.
It's our only chance
to save people on Earth.
If I can find a way to transmit
the quantum data
I'll find in there,
they might still make it.
Let's just hope there's still
someone there to save.
(HULL CREAKING)
CASE: Maximum velocity
achieved.
Prepare to fire
escape thrusters.
Ready?
Ready.
TARS: Ready.
CASE: Main engine ignition
in three,
two,
one...
- Mark.
- (GASPING)
Come on, baby.
(GRUNTING)
CASE: Lander 1 engines,
on my mark.
Three,
two,
one. Mark.
(LAUGHS)
Ranger 2 engines, on my mark.
Three, two, one...
- Mark.
- Fire!
(GASPING)
Well, this little maneuver's
gonna cost us 51 years!
You don't sound so bad
for pushing 120!
(BOTH WHOOPING)
(SIGHS)
CASE: Lander 1, prepare
to detach on my mark.
Three, two,
one. Mark.
TARS: Detach!
BRAND: Good-bye, TARS.
Good-bye, Dr. Brand.
See you on the other side, Coop.
See you there, Slick!
(BEEPING)
(BREATHING DEEPLY)
Okay, CASE,
nice reckless flying!
CASE: Learned from the master.
Ranger 2, prepare to detach.
What?
No! No! Cooper!
- CASE: Three...
- Cooper, what are you doing?
Newton's third law. You got to
leave something behind.
You told me we had enough
resources for both of us.
We agreed, Amelia,
- 90%.
- CASE: Mark.
Don't.
Detach.
(SOBBING)
COOPER:
Okay... I am nosing down.
Approaching the event horizon.
(EXHALES)
Portside,
dipping down beneath it
to go through it.
Heading towards... Blackness.
I have a visual of the event.
It's all black.
TARS, do you read me?
It's all blackness.
TARS! Do you read me? Over.
Okay.
Screens
getting interference.
(GRUNTS)
Losing control of the stick.
I got flashes.
Flashes of lightness
and blackness.
(STRAINING) The turbulence
in the gravity is increasing.
Uh...
The computers are going down.
(GRUNTS)
(GROANING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Gravitational pull. I'm losing
control of the stick.
(GRUNTS)
(SCREAMING)
MAN 1: Come on and join me!
Cut it, before it jumps.
We need more.
MAN 2: On the next row!
GETTY: Murph? Murph, come on!
FEMALE COMPUTER VOICE:
Eject. Eject.
Eject.
(PANTING)
(BREATHING SHAKILY)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(GASPING)
(GRUNTING)
(COUGHS)
(GASPING)
Ahhh!
(PANTING)
(GRUNTING)
(GASPING)
Murph.
Murph! Murph! Murph!
Murph!
No, no, no!
No! No!
(PANTING)
(SOBBING)
(SCREAMING)
(PANTING)
If you're leaving, just go.
COOPER: No, no. No.
No, don't go.
Don't go, you idiot.
Don't go!
Morse. Morse.
Morse.
Dot.
S.
T.
A.
Dash!
Dash! Dash!
Murph, we don't have time
for this! Come on!
Y.
(GRUNTS)
"Stay!"
(PANTING)
Come on, Murph.
Murph, come on!
What's it say?
What's it say, babe?
"Stay."
Tell him, Murph.
Make him stay.
Make him stay, Murph.
Don't let me leave, Murph!
(SOBBING)
No! No! No!
(CONTINUES SOBBING)
It was you.
You were my ghost.
(RADIO STATIC)
(SOBBING)
TARS: Cooper. Cooper.
Come in, Cooper.
TARS?
Roger that.
You survived.
Somewhere
in their fifth dimension.
They saved us.
Yeah? Who the hell is "they"?
And just why would
they want to help us, huh?
I don't know,
but they constructed
this three-dimensional space
inside their
five-dimensional reality
to allow you to understand it.
Well, that ain't working.
Yes, it is.
You've seen that time
is represented here
as a physical dimension.
You have worked out
that you can exert
a force across spacetime.
Gravity... To send a message.
Affirmative.
Gravity
can cross the dimensions,
including time.
Apparently.
Do you have the quantum data?
Roger. I have it.
I am transmitting it
on all wavelengths,
but nothing is getting out,
Cooper.
I can do this. I can do this.
But such complicated data
to a child?
Not just any child.
What else?
Oh, come on, Dad.
Murph, the fire's out!
Come on!
Even if you communicate it here,
she won't understand
its significance for years.
I get that, TARS. All right?
But we've got to
figure something out
or the people on Earth
are gonna die.
Think, think, think!
Cooper,
they didn't bring us here
to change the past.
Say that again.
They didn't bring us here
to change the past.
No, they didn't bring us
here at all.
We brought ourselves.
COOPER: TARS, give me
the coordinates for NASA
in binary.
TARS: In binary. Roger.
Feeding data.
"It's not a ghost."
"It's gravity."
COOPER: (PANTING)
Don't you get it yet, TARS?
I brought myself here!
We're here to communicate with
a three-dimensional world.
We're the bridge!
I thought they chose me.
But they didn't choose me,
they chose her.
TARS: For what, Cooper?
(LAUGHS)
To save the world.
All of this
is one little girl's bedroom.
Every moment.
It's infinitely complex.
They have access
to infinite time and space,
but they're not
bound by anything!
They can't find
a specific place in time.
They can't communicate.
That's why I'm here. I'm gonna
find a way to tell Murph,
just like I found this moment.
TARS: How, Cooper?
Love, TARS, love.
It's just like Brand said.
My connection with Murph,
it is quantifiable.
It's the key!
TARS: What are we here to do?
Find how to tell her.
The watch.
That's it.
We code the data into the
movement of the second hand.
TARS, translate the data
into Morse and feed it to me.
TARS: Translating data
into Morse.
Cooper, what if she
never came back for it?
She will. She will.
GETTY: Murph,
I can see his car!
He's coming, Murph!
Okay. I'm coming down.
TARS: How do you know?
Because I gave it to her.
TARS: Roger.
Morse is dot-dot-dash-dot.
COOPER: Dot-dot-
dash-dot.
TARS: Dot-dash-dot-dot.
COOPER: Dot-dash-dot-dot.
TARS: Dash-dash-dash.
COOPER: Dash-dash-dash.
(GASPS)
MURPH: He came back!
It was him all this time!
I didn't know. It was him!
Dad's gonna save us.
Eureka!
It's traditional.
(LAUGHING) Eureka!
Did it work?
TARS: I think it might have.
How do you know?
TARS: Because the bulk beings
are closing the tesseract.
Don't you get it yet, TARS?
They're not "beings."
They're us.
What I've been doing for
Murph, they're doing for me.
For all of us.
TARS: Cooper,
people couldn't build this.
COOPER: No. No, not yet.
But one day.
Not you and me. But a people.
A civilization that's evolved
past the four dimensions
we know.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
COOPER: What happens now?
DOCTOR: Mr. Cooper.
Let's take it slow, sir.
Nice and easy, Mr. Cooper.
Remember, you're
no spring chicken anymore.
Actually, you are 124 years old.
(PEOPLE PLAYING BASEBALL
OUTSIDE)
Take it slow, sir.
You were extremely lucky.
The Rangers found you
with only minutes left
in your oxygen supply.
(GLASS SHATTERING)
(CHEERING AND LAUGHING)
Where am I?
DOCTOR: Cooper Station.
Currently orbiting Saturn.
Cooper Station.
Nice of you to name it after me.
(LAUGHS)
What?
The station
isn't named after you, sir.
It's named after your daughter.
Although she's always maintained
just how important you were.
Is she still alive?
She'll be here
in a couple weeks.
She is far too old
to be transferring
from another station,
but when she heard
that you'd been found...
Well, this is...
This is Murphy Cooper
we're talking about.
Yes, it is.
DOCTOR: We'll have you checked
out of here in a couple days.
I'm sure you'll be excited
to see what's in store.
I actually did a paper on you
in high school.
I know all about your life
back on Earth.
Oh, yeah.
Right.
If you'll follow me,
we've got a really
good situation for you.
So, um, when I made
my suggestion to Ms. Cooper,
I was delighted to hear that
she thought it was perfect.
OLD WOMAN 1:
It was just constant.
Just that steady blow of dirt.
Of course, I didn't
speak to her personally.
We always
set the plate upside-down.
Glasses or cups,
whatever it was, upside-down.
My dad was a farmer.
Like everybody else
back then.
There just wasn't enough food.
OLD WOMAN 2: We wore
little things, little strips
of sheet, put it sometimes
over our nose and mouth,
so we wouldn't
breathe so much of it.
Well, it was pretty exciting
for me because it was hope.
OLD MAN: I don't care
who describes it,
there is no way for it to be
exaggerated. It was that bad.
ADMINISTRATOR:
She did confirm
just how much you loved farming.
- Oh, she did, did she?
- Yeah.
Here we are.
Home sweet home.
Everything replaced
and put back where it...
Hey, is this...
Oh, yeah.
The machine we found
out near Saturn
when we found you, yes.
Its power source was shot,
but we could get you
another one if you want it.
Yes. Please.
TARS: Settings.
General settings.
Security settings.
Honesty, new setting,
95%.
TARS: Confirmed.
Additional customization?
Humor,
75%.
TARS: Confirmed.
Auto self-destruct
T minus 10, nine...
Let's make that 60%.
TARS: 60% confirmed.
Knock-knock.
You want 55?
TARS: Is this really
what it was like?
It was never this clean,
Slick. (CHUCKLES)
I don't care much for this
pretending we're back
where we started.
I want to know where we are.
Where we're going.
Mr. Cooper.
The family's all in there.
Family?
Yeah, they all came out
to see her.
She's been in cryo-sleep
for almost two years.
(SOBBING)
You told 'em I like farming.
(LAUGHING)
It was me, Murph.
I was your ghost.
I know.
People didn't believe me.
They thought that
I was doing it all myself.
But...
I knew who it was.
Nobody believed me.
But I knew you'd come back.
How?
Because my dad promised me.
Well, I'm here now, Murph.
I'm here.
No.
No parent should have to
watch their own child die.
I have my kids here for me now.
You go.
Where?
Brand.
She's out there,
setting up camp.
Alone
in a strange galaxy.
Maybe right now she's
settling in for the long nap
by the light of our new sun
in our new home.
My name is Max.
My world is fire and blood.
Why are you hurting these people?
It's the oil, stupid.
- Oil wars.
- We are killing for guzzoline.
The world is running out of water.
Now there's the water wars.
Once, I was a cop.
A road warrior searching
for a righteous cause.
...to the terminal freak-out point.
Mankind has gone rogue, terrorizing itself.
Thermonuclear skirmish.
The earth is sour.
Our bones are poisoned.
We have become half-life.
As the world fell...
...each of us, in our own way,
was broken.
It was hard to know
who was more crazy:
Me...
...or everyone else.
Hello?
Where are you?
Where are you, Max?
- Here they come again.
- Max Rockatansky.
Worming their way
into the black matter of my brain.
- Help us, Max.
- You promised to help us.
I tell myself...
...they cannot touch me.
They are long dead.
I am the one...
...who runs from both
the living and the dead.
Hunted by scavengers.
Haunted by those I could not protect.
So I exist in this wasteland.
A man reduced to a single instinct:
Survive.
Max?
Is that you?
Where were you?
Help us. Where were you?
Where were you, Max?
Stop running.
You let us die!
You promised to help us!
Why?
Witness!
I got him.
We are War Boys!
War Boys!
Kamakrazee War Boys!
Fucacima kamakrazee...
...War Boys!
Hooked on!
Today we're heading...
...to Gas Town!
Gas Town!
Today we're hauling Aqua Cola.
Aqua Cola!
- Today we're hauling produce!
- Produce!
And today we're hauling...
...Mother's Milk!
Mother's Milk!
Joe! Joe! Joe! Immortan Joe!
Rev it up for the Immortan Joe!
Once again, we send off my War Rig
to bring back...
...guzzoline from Gas Town...
...and bullets from the Bullet Farm!
Once again, I salute my Imperator...
...Furiosa!
And I salute...
...my half-life War Boys...
...who will ride with me eternal...
...on the highways of Valhalla.
V8! V8! V8! V8!
I am your redeemer.
It is by my hand...
...you will rise from the ashes...
...of this world!
It's coming. Get ready.
Yes. Yes. Yes. It's coming.
Do not, my friends...
...become addicted to water.
It will take hold of you...
...and you will resent its absence.
Clear off!
Get them all off!
Get them all off.
Get off!
Signal Gas Town. Convoy's on its way.
I got a War Boy...
...running on empty.
Hook up that full-life.
Hey! Careful. That's a universal donor.
Boss, we're not going to Gas Town?
Bullet Farm?
We're heading east.
I'll pass it down the line.
New orders!
Thunder up! Thunder up!
This is not a supply run!
Go. Go.
- Ace, what's going on?
- Go. We're heading east.
- Why?
- I don't know. That's the order.
Moo.
- Hey, Pa.
- Hmm?
You know about this?
Your produce ain't going to Gas Town.
She's gone off-road...
...into hostile territory.
Why would she do that?
Let me see.
Rictus.
- I wanna see.
- Rictus.
Go see what's agitating Dad.
Splendid!
Angharad!
Where are they?
They are not your property.
Miss Giddy?
You cannot own a human being.
Sooner or later someone pushes back!
Where is she taking them?
She didn't take them.
They begged her to go!
Where is she taking them?
A long way from you.
Hey. Hey, what's happening?
Slit!
What's going on? Slit!
Treason. Betrayal.
An Imperator gone rogue.
An Imperator.
Who?
Furiosa! She took a lot of stuff
from Immortan Joe.
What stuff?
Breeders! His prize breeders!
He wants them back!
Not a hand laid on them.
By my deeds I honor him.
V8.
V8! V8! V8!
That's my wheel.
I'm driving.
You're my lancer.
I just promoted myself.
Not today. Today is my day.
Look at you.
If you can't stand up,
you can't do war.
He's right, son.
I'm not staying here dying soft.
You're already a corpse.
- I just need a top-up. More juice.
- No time!
We take my Blood Bag.
We take my Blood Bag
and strap him to the lancer's perch.
It's got a muzzle on it. It's feral.
That's right.
High-octane crazy blood
filling me up.
If I'm gonna die...
...I'm gonna die historic
on the Fury Road.
Yeah. Yeah.
- Organic, hitch up his Blood Bag.
- Eh?
Right-o.
How much more can they take from me?
They've got my blood. Now it's my car!
Immortan!
Immortan Joe!
He looked at me!
- He looked right at me!
- He looked at your Blood Bag!
He turned his head.
He looked me in the eye.
He was scanning the horizon.
No.
I am awaited.
I am awaited in Valhalla!
Confucamus!
Immortan!
Yeah!
Hey! Heads up!
Heads up!
Boss!
We got vehicles from the Citadel.
They're firing flares.
They want reinforcements
from Gas Town...
...and the Bullet Farm.
What is this?
Backup? Decoy?
It's a detour.
Eyes right!
Buzzards!
- Buzzards right! Eyes on! Eyes on!
- Buzzards right!
- Eyes on!
Should we turn it around
and run them into our backup?
No! We're good!
We fang it!
Thunder up! Here we go!
Prepare the gunners!
Morsov!
Come on, attack!
War!
Ready!
She's ours, Slit!
She's ours.
First, we get the Buzzards off her back!
Form up!
That's my head!
Get up! You can do it!
Morsov!
- Morsov!
- No!
- Witness me!
- Witness!
Witness!
Aah!
Fly!
Witness!
Mediocre, Morsov!
- Mediocre!
- Hoorah!
Aah!
Get ready!
Back me in!
They're coming!
We can't breathe down there!
Stay out of sight!
Now!
Aah!
Go back!
Where's he going?
Hydraulics!
Aah!
Yeah.
Now we bring home the booty.
She thinks she can lose us, Dad.
She thinks we're stupid.
She thinks she can lose us in there!
Fang it!
Why can't you stop?
Crew! Out of the way!
Out of the way!
What have you done?
Yeah.
We need counterweight.
Get the Blood Bag down the back.
Hunt them down! Hunt them down!
Hey, head!
Say bye-bye to the neck!
We're going in!
Come on! We've almost got her!
Come on! Hold it steady!
Oh, what a day!
What a lovely day!
I am the man...
...who grabs the sun...
...riding to Valhalla!
Witness me...
...Blood Bag!
Witness!
I live, I die, I live again!
Aah!
We're not going back.
Water.
Ah.
You.
Angharad, is that just the wind...
...or is that a furious vexation?
Ugh!
I got it!
Aah!
Glory me, Blood Bag!
We snagged her alive.
He's gonna shred her. Shred her.
Bolt cutters.
Chain.
Hey, hey!
Oh, look at them.
So shiny. So chrome.
He's gonna be so grateful.
We could ask for anything.
I wanna drive the War Rig.
- What are you gonna ask for?
- That's my jacket.
Heh, heh. Sure.
- You can ask for more than a jacket.
- We're going to the Green Place.
Wait, it's you and me. Ugh!
We're going to the Green Place
of Many Mothers.
How does it feel?
- It hurts.
- Out here, everything hurts.
You wanna get through this?
Do as I say.
Now pick up what you can and run.
Tsa!
Kill switches.
I set the sequence myself.
This Rig goes nowhere without me.
You can get in.
Not without them.
So we wait.
You're relying on the gratitude
of a very bad man.
You've damaged one of his wives.
How grateful do you think he's gonna be?
You're sitting on 2000 horsepower
of nitro-boosted war machine.
I'd say you got
about a five-minute head start.
You want that thing off your face?
Let's go.
Ah, uh-uh.
Of all the legs you had to shoot,
that one was attached to his favorite.
Smeg!
You don't have to do it
just because he tells you.
- What choice does she have?
- He's not gonna hurt us. He needs us.
- Why?
- To bargain.
Oh, he'll hurt us.
Think he's coming to the Green Place?
Never! He's a crazy smeg...
...who eats schlanger!
Nah, stay out of there.
Behind you.
Huh?
The Gas Town Boys.
Don't damage the goods.
What do you see?
Big Rigs...
...Polecats...
...Flamers...
...and there's the People Eater himself.
Coming to count the cost.
Hmm.
Aah!
We're dragging something out back.
I think it's the fuel pod.
No, no.
I'll go.
- Filth! You traitored him!
- Ah!
No unnecessary killing!
- This War Boy wants me dead!
- We agreed!
He's kamakrazee!
He's just a kid
at the end of his half-life!
No! I live. I die. I live again!
- Hold him!
- Tie him up!
Throw him out!
Chuck him out!
You got more friends.
Bullet Farmer.
- They're coming from the Bullet Farm.
- Yeah?
It's over. You can't defy him.
Just watch us, mate!
He is the one...
- ...who grabbed the sun.
- Look how slick he's fooled you.
- He's a lying old man.
- By his hand...
- ...we'll be lifted up!
- That's why we have...
...his logo seared on our backs!
"Breeding Stock!" "Battle Fodder!"
No, I am awaited!
- You're an old man's "Battle Fodder"!
- Killing everyone...
- ...and everything.
- We're not to blame!
Then who killed the world?
I made a deal up ahead. Safe passage.
I don't know if it's still any good.
Get back in the hold!
Keep the hatch open.
I need you here.
You may have to drive the Rig.
Mm.
You.
You stay.
You stay there.
Whatever you do, you can't be seen.
I'm supposed to be alone.
That was the deal.
Down here.
Hey.
What's your name?
What do I call you?
Does it matter?
Fine.
When I yell "fool"...
...you drive out of here
as fast as you can.
This is the sequence:
One. One, two.
One.
Red. Black. Go.
You have it?
It's all here!
Three thousand gallons of guzzoline,
just like you asked!
I'm gonna unhitch the pod.
You drop the rocks.
You said:
"A few vehicles in pursuit.
Maybe."
We count three War Parties!
Yeah, well, I got unlucky.
Let's do this!
Fool!
That's our fuel!
Make way for the Ripsaw!
Come on! Move them!
Once I'm over...
...clear the rocks
and bring everyone through.
Immortan!
Immortan Joe!
I got a War Boy!
Says he was on the War Rig.
You! Climb aboard!
Hey. Hey!
I got his boot!
I got the Blood Bag's boot!
Take me!
I got his boot!
All this for a family squabble.
Healthy babies.
Aah!
Reload the clip.
I can't.
Gun!
Gimme the gun!
Not loaded yet!
Now!
We had a deal!
Ugh!
Rictus!
The wives!
No more flames.
Splendid!
That's my child!
My property!
Immorta...
Immortan. If I get on the Rig,
there's a way inside.
- What is your name?
- It's Nux.
I'll pike her in the spine.
Keep her breathing.
No.
Put a bullet in her skull.
Stop the Rig,
return my treasures to me...
...and I, myself, will carry you...
...to the Gates...
...of Valhalla.
Am I awaited?
You will ride eternal...
...shiny and chrome.
Rictus!
Help him aboard!
Ready?
Here we go!
Aah!
Mediocre!
Schlanger!
Look out!
Angharad!
Get out!
No!
Angharad!
Stop! Turn the Rig around!
Go back for her!
No.
Tell him to turn the Rig around!
Did you see it?
She went under the wheels.
We keep moving.
- No!
- We keep moving!
He doesn't know what he's talking about!
Whatever happens,
we're going to the Green Place.
The stupid Green Place.
We don't even know where to find it!
- You all right?
- On! On!
Cheedo!
Cheedo, don't be stupid.
Stop!
He'll forgive us. I know he will.
There is no going back!
- We were his treasures!
- Cheedo!
We were protected! He gave us the high life!
- What's wrong with that?
- We are not things.
No!
We are not things!
We are not things.
- I don't want to hear that again!
- They were her words!
And now she's dead!
Wring your hands and tear your hair...
...but you're not going back.
You're not going back to him.
Angharad!
Come on! Come on!
So, um, ahem...
...where is this...
...Green Place?
It's a long night's run, heading east.
We need inventory.
Match every gun with its bullets.
I'm gonna go and do some repairs.
We need someone down the back.
I'll go.
No.
I want you to stay together.
I can do it.
What are you doing here?
He saw it.
He saw it all.
My own Blood Bag driving the Rig
that killed her.
Stop doing that.
Shh. Shh, shh, shh.
Stop.
Three times the gates were open to me.
What gates?
I was awaited in Valhalla.
They were calling my name.
I should be walking with the Immorta.
McFeasting with the heroes of all time.
I'd say it was your manifest destiny not to.
I thought I was being spared
for something great.
I got to drive a pursuit vehicle.
For a while even Larry and Barry
stopped chewing on my windpipe.
Who are Larry and Barry?
My mates.
Larry and Barry.
If they don't get me,
then the Night Fevers will.
Well, we've only got four for Big Boy here,
so he's all but useless.
But...
...we can squirt off this little pinky
a raunchy 29 times.
Angharad used to call them Antiseed.
Plant one and watch something die.
Hold on, mate.
We are down
30,000 units of guzzoline...
...19 canisters of nitro, 12 assault bikes...
...seven pursuit vehicles.
The deficit mounts.
And now, sir...
...you have us stuck in a quagmire.
Hey, Joe!
Boss!
Your girly's breathing her last!
What about the child?
Are you coming, brother?
Wait!
It's gone awful quiet in there.
Get it out.
Get it out!
Come on! I've been called to the torture!
Patience!
Oh, you stay here with your grief, Daddy.
- I'll fetch them for you.
- Be careful! Protect the assets!
Just one angry shot...
...for Furiosa.
Hut!
Yeah!
Crying shame. Heh.
Come.
Another month...
...could have been your viable human!
Was it a male?
Your A-1 Alpha prime.
Hey, Rictus!
You lost a baby brother!
Perfect in every way.
I had a baby brother!
I had a little baby brother!
And he was perfect!
Perfect in every way!
Come on.
Wouldn't wanna shoot the wives, sir.
Just probing.
He wants to help!
Who?
The War Boy!
Where did he come from?
I thought we threw him off the Rig!
There's high ground...
- ...just beyond that thing.
- He means the tree.
Yeah. Tree!
Leave him to me.
Say, anyone notice that bright light?
Encroaching gunfire?
Get out.
I can do this. I know this machine.
He does. He's a Revhead.
You've got two left!
On him.
Don't breathe.
Ugh!
Hey!
Hey! Hey!
War Boy!
I'm gonna use the winch
around the tree thing!
Take this.
Let's get the engine plates.
You drive the Rig!
- Hold up a flare!
- I am holding a flare!
- Closer!
- It's right in front of your eyes!
Aah!
Hut! Hut!
Blood Bag!
I am the scales of justice!
Conductor of the choir of death!
Sing, Brother Heckler.
Sing, Brother Koch!
Sing, brothers, sing! Sing!
Don't they know they're shooting at us?
Gun fever!
I never thought I'd do something
as shine as that.
How are the engines?
Very hot and real thirsty.
Hey. You need to take the War Rig
half a klick down the track.
What if you're not back by the time
the engines have cooled?
Well, you keep moving.
What do you suppose he's gonna do?
Retaliate first.
Let's go!
- Are you hurt?
- Huh?
You're bleeding.
That's not his blood.
What is this?
It's Mother's Milk.
It's okay.
Sleep.
Get some rest.
How do you know this place even exists?
I was born there.
So why'd you leave?
I didn't.
I was taken as a child.
Stolen.
You done this before?
Many times.
Now that I drive a War Rig...
...this is the best shot I'll ever have.
And them?
They're looking for hope.
What about you?
Redemption.
Hey, what's that?
I remember something like that.
Help me!
- Help me, please!
- Uh, uh.
Please!
That's bait.
Stay in the Rig.
Hurry! Please, hurry! They'll be back!
I am one of...
...the Vuvalini!
Of the Many Mothers!
My Initiate Mother was K.T. Concannon!
I am the daughter of Mary Jabassa.
My clan was Swaddle Dog!
It's me.
There's something in the eyes.
Perhaps it is Jabassa's child.
This is our Furiosa.
How long has it been?
Seven thousand days.
Plus the ones I don't remember.
Furiosa.
What happened to your mother?
She died.
On the third day.
From where did you come?
The West. Citadel. Beyond the mountains.
The men.
Who are they?
They're reliable.
They helped us get here.
Where did you find such creatures?
So soft.
This one has all her teeth!
Oh.
I can't wait for them to see it.
See?
See what?
Home.
The Green Place.
But if you came from the West...
...you passed it.
The crows.
The creepy place with all the crows.
- The soil.
- We had to get out.
- We had no water.
- The water was filth.
It was poisoned. It was sour.
And then the crows came.
We couldn't grow anything.
Where are the others?
What others?
The Many Mothers.
We're the only ones left.
Look.
That's what you call a satellite.
Miss Giddy told us about those.
They used to bounce messages
across the Earth.
Shows.
Everyone in the old world
had a show.
Do you think there's still...
...somebody out there?
Sending shows?
Who knows?
Those are the Plains of Silence.
Stay right where you are, little Joe.
Kind of lost its novelty out here.
You having a baby?
Warlord Junior.
Gonna be so ugly.
It could be a girl.
You kill people with that, do you?
Killed everyone I ever met out here.
Headshots. All of them.
Snap. Right in the medulla.
Thought somehow you girls
were above that.
Come here.
Take a peek.
Seeds.
These are from home.
Heirlooms. The real thing.
I plant one every chance I get.
Where?
So far, nothing's took.
Earth's too sour.
Aah. So many different kinds.
Trees, flowers, fruit.
Back then, everyone had their fill.
Back then,
there was no need to snap anybody.
Can I talk to you?
I've talked with the others.
We're never gonna have a better chance
to make it across the salt.
If we leave the Rig here, and load the
motorcycles up with as much as we can...
...we can maybe ride for 160 days.
One of those bikes is yours.
Fully loaded.
You're more than welcome
to come with us.
I'll make my own way.
You know, hope is a mistake.
If you can't fix what's broken, you'll, uh...
You'll go insane.
Where are you, Max?
Where are you?
Help us. You promised to help us.
Come on, Pa! Let's go.
All right.
This is your way home.
We go back?
Mm.
- Back?
- Yeah.
I thought you weren't insane anymore.
What are they saying?
He wants to go back from where they came.
The Citadel.
What's there to find at the Citadel?
Green.
And water.
There's a ridiculous amount of clear water.
And a lot of crops.
Got everything you need.
Long as you're not afraid of heights.
Where does the water come from?
He pumps it up from deep in the earth.
Calls it Aqua Cola and claims it for himself.
And because he owns it, he owns all of us.
I don't like him already.
It'll take two weeks
to skirt the Wall of Mountains.
No.
I suggest we go back the same way we came.
Through the canyon.
It's open. We know that. Right?
He brought all his war parties through.
So we take the War Rig and we charge it
right through the middle of them.
We can decouple the tanker...
...at the pass.
Shut it off behind us.
Kaboom.
And how exactly do we take the Citadel?
Assuming we're still alive by then.
If we can block the pass, it'll be easy.
All that's left are his War Pups
and War Boys too sick to fight.
And we'll be with Nux.
He's a War Boy.
He'll be bringing us home.
Bringing back what's stolen, as he's meant to.
Yeah.
It feels like hope.
I like this plan.
We can start again.
Just like the old days!
Look.
It'll be a hard day.
But I guarantee you
that a 160 days' ride that way...
...there's nothing but salt.
At least that way, you know,
we might be able to...
...together...
...come across some kind of redemption.
War Rig!
That's the War Rig!
That's them.
Why are they going back?
Do they wish to surrender?
They are heading for the canyon.
They're going back to the Citadel!
They know it's undefended!
Bollocks!
Roll up!
Go!
- What are you doing?
- Praying.
To who?
Anyone that's listening.
Here we go, girls!
That's mine!
He'll try to get in front of us.
Spike our wheels.
Don't blow my engine.
Gonna nudge him.
Just a little.
You filth! You traitored him!
Yeah!
Go.
Aah! Aah!
Ha!
Aah!
Gotta back off.
Engine one is gone.
Two's about to blow.
Right.
Are you a Black Thumb?
Uh-huh.
All right. Engine one. Now.
You and me. Fifth wheel.
We'll unhook the tanker.
One man, one bullet.
- I cannot see.
- Maadi! Maadi!
I can't see.
Oh.
Hey!
Harpoons and plows!
They're hauling us back!
Leave three bolts. Three.
Hey, you! Aargh!
Are you okay?
I think she's hurt.
Hey!
No!
Hey.
Stay with me.
- Stay with me.
- Hey.
- Hey! Are you there?
You finish that! I'll finish her!
Unh!
Valhalla!
Aah!
Ha!
Engine one's good.
For now.
She's hurt! She's hurt...
...real bad!
Aah!
You hear that?
We're gonna see two airborne V8s.
I'm gonna need you to drive.
I'll get him out of our way.
Rictus!
Take me!
Cheedo!
- What are you doing?
- Good girl.
- Come here.
- Aah!
Aah!
Big Boy!
Here! Here!
Unh!
Remember me?
Aah!
He's dead!
He's dead.
When you're across safe,
I'll jam the throttle and follow you.
Come on!
Hurry! We're nearly at the pass.
Witness me.
Rictus!
Why is she making that noise?
She's pumping air into her chest cavity.
She's collapsing her lungs...
...one breath at a time.
I know.
I am so sorry.
I know. I know.
Hold it there.
All right.
Put that on there. Press it in. Hey.
Hey.
Home.
- No, no, no. No, no, no.
- She's exsanguinated.
- Drained all her blood.
- Well...
Hold these.
We need that.
Needle.
Come on.
Take this.
Keep her awake.
Furiosa.
Okay, that's not retracting.
There we go.
All right, hold it up. Hold it up.
All right.
Sorry.
There you go. Okay. There you go.
Max.
My name is Max.
Yeah. Mm-hm.
Mm.
That's my name.
Brake!
Reveal yourself.
He's got something.
It's Immortan Joe.
The Immortan Joe is dead!
Furiosa!
She's back.
Let them up! Let them up!
Let them up!
Come on, let's do it!
Let them up. Come on.
Come on.
Good morning. On this day,
July 1st, 2014. At this hour, 0600.
We are at the very first airport in the world...
The CW-7, which despite being the topic of
so much controversy over the past 7 years,
has continued development.
Protests from environmental groups and
a number of developing countries continue...
It has been claimed that CW-7
is the answer to global warming.
And we are witnessing it!
...world leaders, who argue that
global warming can no longer be ignored.
Today, 79 countries will begin dispersing CW-7
into the upper layers of the atmosphere.
...spray out into the upper layers of
the atmosphere and
surprisingly bring down average
global temperatures to the finest levels.
It is just a day away that
our long time crisis of global warming...
According to scientists, the artificial cooling
substance CW-7 will succeed
in bringing average global temperatures
down to manageable levels,
as a revolutionary solution to
mankind's warming of the planet.
Head check!
Alright. Get in line.
Everybody sit down.
One.
Two.
Three.
Four.
Five.
Six.
Keep going.
Go on.
Hey you. Sit down!
Curtis, sit down.
Sit down!
I said sit down!
- What the fuck are you doing?
- Counting.
Can't you sit and count?
You wanna get shot? You're crazy.
Shut up, Edgar. I'm thinking.
Are there any experienced violinists here?
Raise your hands!
Violinist!
Stand up, come forward.
Food! Come and get it.
Violinists? They're having a laugh?
Those bastards in the Front Section,
think they own us.
Eating steak dinners and listening to
string quartets and that.
We'll be different when we get there.
I want steak.
Excuse me sir!
My wife and I played violin
in the Boston Symphony Orchestra.
I was first chair.
Can you still play?
Of course. You never forget.
Show me your hands.
You. Follow me.
Leave your belongings, we just need your hands.
Not both?
Yes. Both hands.
My wife, Doris, plays beautifully.
Better than me even.
They just need one person.
Then I won't go.
Doris, Doris.
Sit down everyone.
- Sit down, Edgar.
- They can't just...
Sit down.
Fucking bastards.
Now isn't the time.
Well when is the time?
Soon.
Doris, I'll be back Doris. It's alright.
I'll come back.
What does the steak taste like again?
I had it once, but I can't remember...
If you can't remember then it's better to forget.
Alright then, what does it,
what does it smell like when it's cooking and that?
When it emanates around the place.
Curtis, is this it?
It's not it.
And I've heard this...
Curtis! Here!
Tim-bo. How's it hanging, buddy?
Give me a pound. Blow it up.
Hey, listen. I think I need that protein block.
How about I trade you? This one for that one?
No.
Nice bargaining, Curtis. Here.
Give me this one, I'll give you that.
Hey, relax, relax.
Come here, Timmy. Come here.
Come right...
I have an idea.
I'll give you this one and that one for that one.
What do you say?
No.
Go get him.
Timmy!
Timothy! Your mom's gonna give you
a damn good spanking!
Where the fuck he went?
Hey, come here. Come here. Give us it. Give us it.
You're alright, Jose. How you doing man?
Timmy! Work with me here!
Edgar, why did you let him get up there?
No, I didn't. He got up there by himself.
He's very nimble.
- He's five.
- He's a very nimble five year old.
Timmy! Sweetie, come down.
Come here.
What do you want for it?
In the whole wide train?
In the whole wide train.
The ball!
The ball? No, no, I'm sorry,
I can't do that. I can't do that.
Yes. I get the ball for a whole hour.
Done.
Curtis. Is it time?
Not yet, Tanya. Soon.
Red letter?
Yeah. It's the one we've been waiting for.
Our informant gave us the name.
N, A, M...
Nam Koong Min Soo.
He's a security expert.
He's in the Prison Section now.
Wait! You're joking, right?
- He's in prison?
- Hey, out of here.
No, I'm just saying, what kind of
chance do we have...
Edgar.
I just think that if this guys says that
he's such a great security expert
why can't he just break himself...
That's enough! Go!
Let's go, Tim. Come on. Let's go.
Edgar just wants to help, you know.
He thinks the world of you.
He shouldn't worship me the way he does.
I'm not who he thinks I am.
Few of us ever are.
Alright. We're here, Tail Section,
Quarantine Section, Prison Section.
Gate.
Four seconds when all three gates are opened at once.
We have four seconds to go through
three gates and bust Nam out.
Then Nam gets us the rest of the way?
Our fate depends on this man?
Yeah. If we can get him to cooperate,
he can take us all the way to the front of the train.
Very front section.
Yeah.
From here right to the front of the train.
Everything in one stroke.
We control the engine, we control the world.
Without that, we have nothing.
All past revolutions have failed because
they couldn't take the engine.
What are you saying?
This time, we take the engine.
Then what?
We kill him.
Wilford?
You should run the train now, not Wilford.
I'm a shadow of my former shadow.
My day was decades ago.
How old is Gilliam?
Shut up, Edgar.
And listen, I'm not saying that I want that
to happen, that's not what I'm saying.
What I mean is he will die someday.
And when that happens
you're gonna have to take over.
You're gonna have to run the train.
I'm not a leader.
I don't know. I think you'd be
pretty good if you ask me.
Hey, Edgar.
How far back can you remember?
- I don't know, like what?
- Your mother. You remember her?
I can remember her face, every once in a while...
But it's not clear.
Stay down everybody.
Everybody stay in your place.
Don't fucking look at me!
Keep down, keep down!
Medical Inspection. All the kids.
All the kids come with me. Just the kids.
All the kids.
Stay back there, ma'am. Just stay back there.
Stay back there. Stay.
Hello, what's this? We have one more.
Yup, come.
No, no, all need to go.
Come on.
No, no, we don't need to.
There's nothing wrong with him.
It's just a little medical check, sir. You just
stay back there. You just stay back there.
You! Go and check!
Don't move! Stay there!
Go, Timmy, go! Go!
That's her baby!
Andy!
Give me my son, you fucking bitch!
Andy! Andy!
How did you let him throw his shoe?
Timmy!
At this altitude, we need only 7 minutes.
Seven minutes allotted for your speech, sir.
This is so disappointing.
No no, we don't need all that.
We've only got seven minutes.
Passengers.
This is not a shoe. This is disorder.
This is size ten chaos.
This. See this. This is death.
In this locomotive we call home,
there is one thing
that between our warm hearts and the bitter cold.
Clothing? Shields? No! Order.
Order is the barrier that
holds back the frozen death.
We must all of us, on this train of life,
remain in our allotted station.
We must each of us occupy
our preordained particular position.
Would you wear a shoe on your head?
Of course you wouldn't wear a shoe on your head.
A shoe doesn't belong on your head.
A shoe belongs on your foot.
A hat belongs on your head.
I am a hat. You are a shoe.
I belong on the head. You belong on the foot.
Yes? So it is.
In the beginning, order
was prescribed by your ticket.
First class, economy, and free loaders like you.
Eternal order is prescribed by the Sacred Engine.
All things flow from the Sacred Engine.
All things in their place.
All passengers in their section.
All water flowing, all heat
rising pays homage
to the Sacred Engine. In its own
par-ti-cu-lar pre-ordained position.
So it is.
Now, as in the beginning, I belong to the front.
You belong to the tail.
When the foot seeks the place of the head,
a sacred line is crossed.
Know your place!
Keep your place!
Be a shoe!
We have 42 seconds left.
So we could go to a comment of Mr. Wilford,
the Divine Keeper of the Sacred Engine.
Sir? Mr. Wilford?
Are you there?
Are you there, sir?
Oh, it's breaking off.
Mr. Wilford is a very busy man.
So it is.
- Are we just gonna watch?
- Not now.
I'm not just gonna fucking sit here...
No, I'm alright.
Stop. Stop right there. Sit down!
Put that useless gun down, put it away.
Long time no see, Mr. Gilliam. It's a pleasure.
You look healthy.
He's fine.
Minister Mason, please deliver
a message to Mr. Wilford.
Certainly. What shall I say?
Tell him, he and I need to talk.
Well. You can talk to me.
Mr. Wilford has no reason to visit here...
Not here. At the front.
Your son will be a hero. Promise.
Or daughter, whatever it is.
I got it, I got it.
Your contribution has been duly noted. Thanks.
So sorry to interrupt you while you're praying.
What are you doin', man?
So sorry. Sumimasen.
Look. There's your Buddha back, thanks very much.
Move, move, move!
Stop fooling around!
I've got a better batch.
Stronger, fresh, uncut.
Wanna try some?
How many protein blocks for
ten rocks of uncut Kronole?
They don't have bullets.
Why do you say that?
You remember what Mason said?
She said, "Put down that useless gun."
She meant she wouldn't
give the order to shoot me.
No.
No, I think the guns are literally useless.
They used up all their bullets
four years ago, in the last revolt.
Bullets are extinct.
If you're wrong, we could be finished
before we even start.
I think we should be patient.
Wait for the next red letter.
Stay together. Left and right.
Not yet. Up, up. Now left, to the left.
Good, now forward.
Hello, Andrew! Andrew!
Wake up, rise and shine.
When you dream too much
of the sun, you forget the trees.
I believe this is your son.
I'm, I'm sorry, it's not very good.
It's not my best work, it's a little dark.
But if you look very deep into the eyes,
you can see a little bit of hope.
What about my boy?
You've got one of Timmy?
Oh yes, Tanya, I do. Easy, easy.
Come off this easy. You'll hurt yourself.
Here, there you go. Timmy.
Look at him.
Funny little smile.
Curtis, you gotta let me come with you.
No, Tanya. I'm sorry.
You will be if you don't let me come.
I'm going to the front and I'mma make that
bitch sorry she put her hands on my boy.
Make this one tighter.
You know I'm stronger than
all these skinny ass soldiers anyway.
Please!
Oh shit, what's going on?
They changed the schedule, boys. Move it back!
Now or never! They're coming now!
Don't panic! Stick with the plan.
Hide that! Hide it in your clothes!
Hide your weapons in your clothes!
Head check.
Line up.
Alright, sit down.
One, two, three, four...
What the fuck do we do?
I've had enough of this protein block bullshit!
Yeah, this is bullshit!
We're fucking hungry, man!
I want chicken!
We're not gonna sit down for this shite!
We want chicken! Chicken!
It's okay.
You want him fucking dead? Is that it?
Be quiet!
Still going for it, are we?
Come on, let's go! Let's do it.
The rifles.
No, we can overwhelm them.
We easily outnumber their bullets.
This is it.
Curtis, come on. We're out of time.
You gotta do it now.
They've got no bullets!
I'm fine, Grey. You go now!
"Nam Koong Min Soo. Kronole Addict."
That explains a lot, doesn't it?
Hurry up, Edgar.
Hurry up?
So sorry for keeping you all waiting.
Obviously I work here.
Open it.
Here we go!
Hey, Kronole head!
So, this is Kronole?
I heard it's pretty big in the front section.
Careful, that's how these guys hallucinate.
It's industrial waste.
And it's highly flammable.
Are you Nam Koong Min Soo? Security specialist?
Did you design all the door locks
and security systems on the train?
Look at him man, he's gone. Look at his eyes.
He's fried his brain with that fucking shite.
Are you Nam?
Nam, are you listening?
Yes, I'm listening, fuck.
It's not "Nem", it's "Nam".
Namgoong Minsoo, shit.
Surname is Namgoong,
first name is Minsoo, asshole.
Unknown words found.
Please try again with correct vocabulary.
We need your help.
For what?
We're going to the front and
we need you to open up the gates.
What if I say no?
Uncut. Straight from the barrel.
Every door you open, you get one lump of Kronole.
Jesus! Marlboro Light?
I can't believe it. Cigarettes have been
extinct for more than 10 years now.
Do you want some, asshole?
I bet you fuckhead never smoked one before.
I'm gonna make this real simple for you.
You help us, you get your drug.
If not, we put you back where we found you.
What'll it be, asshole?
Chan.
Chan. Get outta here. Just get out.
Hey, that's enough.
Put him back in the fucking drawer!
Get up.
My Daughter, Yona.
If I go, she goes too.
So, you're coming with us?
One gate, 2 lumps of Kronole.
She's an addict, too?
Nobody there.
Kronole.
Look at all these beds. Where is everybody?
Looks like they left in a hurry.
There's some food on the table.
This can't be a window, can it?
Still cold.
Dead. All dead.
Alright! Let's go everyone!
Stay focus. We didn't come here for this.
Alright! You heard the man. Let's go! Move!
Nem! Nam!
Kronole.
How did you know there was nobody there?
He's running.
Paul?
Paul!
What the hell is he doing, man? Paul!
He looks so different.
Yeah, just a second. Used to be automatic.
But parts went extinct.
He's not the Paul I remember.
No. Paul! It's Curtis!
Ain't comin' back... so now I got to do it.
Manually!
So that's how it's made. Still hot.
Look at them all! Man, you did some nice work!
That's right, man! There's your food!
There's your protein blocks!
Is this why they took you? To make this garbage?
Paul?
You've been alone this whole time?
Alone! In the zone!
We're going to the front. Come with us!
Oh, right! You're going to the front? Yeah, man!
But, no way man. My place is here. Alright?
Here? Making this crap? Why?
You can't draw this.
Okay.
All this time, we've been eating this shit?
Hey, I eat them too, you know.
Every single day.
Where did you get this?
Have you been the one writing these?
I don't write 'em.
Why do you have this? Who gave this to you?
They just leave 'em for me ,man. I put them
in the protein blocks. I send them on. That's it!
The Water Supply Section?
Yeah. It's just a few cars up. It's where
the water's cleansed and recycled.
It's one of the most
crucial sections in the train.
If we take it, we have the upper hand?
We don't even have to
go to the very front.
We control the water, we control the negotiation.
Uh, hi, hi, excuse me. Sorry to bother you there.
Can I get you a glass of water or
something to speed this up?
Listen! Would you get on with it, man?
You're keeping us all fucking waiting!
Am I?
Yeah, you are.
Although you've been
fucking smelling that flammable shite,
that time is probably a distant
fucking concept for you, isn't it?
Of course, I'm only doing this for Kronole.
Here we go again, Kronole this, Kronole that.
Christ almighty, man. Do some fucking work!
You're the one who gives it to me.
Are you a bit thick? That's what you ask for
each time you open a gate!
Of course, I'm only doing this for Kronole.
Yona. It's Yona, right?
How old are you?
Seventeen.
Seventeen. You're a train baby, then?
How 'bout you?
Seventeen years on Earth.
Seventeen years in the Tail Section.
Earth? What was it like?
I don't remember.
Why?
I don't want to remember anything
before I met Gilliam.
Yona.
Are you clairvoyant?
Clairvoyant? What's that?
Well, you always seem to know what's behind the gates.
Do you see things in your mind?
Don't open it.
What?
Lock the gate!
Be careful.
Yeah, you too.
Team 2 move!
Move forward!
Passing Yekaterina Bridge!
We're at the bridge, guys!
Ten. Nine.
Eight. Seven. Six.
Five. Four.
Three. Two. One.
Happy New Year!
Fucking hate getting old, I fucking hate it.
Wilford! Banzai! Banzai!
Everybody down!
Hang on!
Impact!
Not yet! A second one!
Stay down!
Nam, what are you doing man? What are you doing?
He's high as a fucking kite.
Here it comes.
Safe passage.
Hey, watch it! Watch out!
Come on!
One, two, three. One, two.
Happy Yekaterina Bridge, you filthy ingrates!
You people, who if not for the benevolent Wilford,
would have frozen solid 18 years ago today!
You people...
Who have sucked on the generous titty of Wilford
ever since, for food and shelter!
And now, in front of
our hallowed water supply section, no less!
You repay his kindness with
violent hooliganism?
You scum.
Precisely 74% of you shall die.
My friend, you suffer from
the misplaced optimism of the doomed.
This is going to be good.
What? What did you say?
He said you guys are fucked.
You stupid Tail Sectioners.
There's a tunnel right after Yekaterina Bridge.
A tunnel?
Mm-hmm, a fucking long one!
Let's go.
Everybody back!
Chan. Get outta here. Just get out.
Chan! We need fire!
Chan! Bring the fire!
Tell them in the back
we need to get the lights up here!
Chan has the matches!
Got you, motherfucker!
Officer Fuyu! What are you doing?
Don't look at me, you dozy bugger!
Look there!
Put me down! Stop squeezing my legs!
Surrender!
Surrender! Surrender!
He will kill me if we don't surrender!
Shit...
Curtis!
Stop! Stop everybody!
Drop your weapon.
Stop!
Everybody stop!
Do what he says, for crying out loud.
Drop your weapons!
Don't look.
Survivors! Wash yourselves!
The Water Supply Section.
Wash away the blood.
Have you seen these kids?
I don't know anything about...
Look! Where are they, you bitch?
I don't know. I don't know.
It's not me. It's not me.
Tell us or I'll cut your fucking arm off.
Even shorter than mine, you bastard!
Wilford... Wilford knows.
Wil... Wilford... Wilford likes kids.
He does. That's why he sends that
yellow one Claude to get them for him...
It... it's Wilford you want, not me.
Wilford likes kids?
All he cares about is his wretched engine!
The Engine is Sacred.
And Wilford is Divine.
Wilford is merciful.
Call him. See if he'll come save you.
Yes.
Wilford The Merciful. Call him.
He won't come here. He won't leave his Engine.
We're going to rip you into little pieces.
He still won't come?
Well, we control the water.
We turn that off, he'll have to come.
Turn off the water?
Well, you'll only be condemning your own people.
The water comes from the front.
The nose of the train breaks up the snow
and ice and turns it into water.
It's like an elephant's trunk. The water
comes in the mouth, not in the bum.
Curtis!
Yes. Wilford knows you well, Mr. Curtis Everett.
He's been watching you.
And we know you won't harm your own people.
Too bad you couldn't save
your second in command.
- What was his name, Edgar?
- Shut the fuck up!
Curtis! Curtis! I can help you!
You can fucking die is what you can do.
No, I can help you! I swear it!
Listen, listen to me!
Wilford won't come here! He's not coming!
You've got to go to him!
And I can take you. I know the train.
I can guarantee you safe passage.
Why the fuck would I trust you?
Because I want to live.
So you'd sell out Wilford The Benevolent?
If I take you to the front,
you have to kill him.
I'll get you close enough.
You kill him and let me live.
Curtis?
You're still determined to push ahead?
Of course. We're not even halfway.
You've already gone further than anyone else.
Further than MacGregor four years ago.
Ten cars, twenty cars, it doesn't matter
unless we make it to the engine.
They'll just regroup and attack us again.
We gotta pull them out by the roots.
But so many have been killed.
We've lost so many.
I know.
Have you seen our men? They are exhausted.
I told them to wash themselves,
so that I could assess the damage.
Let me go ahead.
I've got Mason now.
I can move a lot faster.
You stay here with the wounded.
Guard the prisoners.
When we take the engine,
I'll call for you to lead us.
Stop it, Curtis. Why are you doing that?
You know very well that you're already our leader.
You have to accept that now.
How can I lead if I have two good arms?
It's faded a lot.
Better to have both arms.
Can't do a lot with one, you know.
Especially when you hold a woman.
It's much better to have two arms, wouldn't you agree?
When you get to the narrow bridge,
big gate with the W on it.
Wilford's behind that.
Don't let Wilford talk.
Cut out his tongue.
Okay, let's all get in there, squeeze in!
Perfect, perfect! The hat becomes you well.
Now, Grey... You must go with Curtis.
Oops, forgot somebody.
Kronole.
Don't mind me. Back to work,
everyone, back to work.
Minister.
Are you okay?
I'm okay.
Please don't eat it, don't eat it.
No, no, no, no, they're very friendly.
They won't bite.
Well, they might bite the tomato, but...
Can I eat this?
Train baby like you wouldn't know.
I used to walk on this every day.
Under the snow this is everywhere.
Earth.
What's this?
It's moving.
Over there.
What's that?
Hey.
Do any of you feel like sushi?
Hell yeah, line that shit up.
Right?
You people are very lucky.
This is only served twice in a year,
in January and July.
Why? Not enough fish?
Oh, "enough" is not the criterion.
Balance.
You see, this aquarium is
a closed ecological system.
The number of individual units must be
very closely, precisely controlled
in order to maintain
the proper sustainable balance.
No.
You eat this.
You know what that's made of?
Dig in.
Curtis, my friend, do you think we might dispense
with the restraints for this next Section?
I am not your friend and why would I?
For the sake of the young? Education?
Quiet! Quiet!
Good morning, children.
I am pleased to present guests from the Tail Section.
Yes and what do we say to
Tail Section guests, children?
Good morning, Tail Section guests.
Timmy! Timmy!
Andy! Andy! Andrew...
This little boy. His name is Timmy.
This is my son. Please, take a
good look at the picture!
I saw them!
- When?
- Where?
Came through there, went through there.
Is that all, boy?
Yes.
Were they crying?
No, but they looked like they wanted to.
I heard all Tail Sectioners were lazy dogs
who slept all day in their own shit.
No, they're very nice!
And very just and merciful. So it is.
Minister Mason, we were
just about to show a video.
Very good!
Wilford!
From a very young age, Mr. Wilford's
love of locomotives was apparent.
When I grow up, I want to
live in a train. Forever!
Forever!
His early dreams were realized
when he founded his transportation empire
the Wilford Industries.
But his greatest dream was to
construct a luxury locomotive cruise line.
Connecting railways of
the entire world into one!
A circular railway that extends for 438,000 kilometers
and completes one circle every year.
Impervious to the extreme cold of the Arctic
and the scorching heat of the African desert.
Wilford's miracle train is self-sustaining
and possesses the most sophisticated designs
and advanced technology known--
As hard as it is to believe,
people in the Old World made fun of Mr. Wilford.
They criticized him for over-engineering
and over-equipping this wonderful train.
But Wilford knew something they did not.
And what was that?
Old World people were frigging morons
who got turned into popsicles!
Well, sort of.
Mr. Wilford knew that
CW-7 would freeze the world.
So what did the prophetic Mr. Wilford invent to
protect the chosen from that calamity?
The Engine!
Rumble, rumble, rattle, rattle.
It will never die!
What happens if the engine stops?
We all freeze and die
But will it stop, oh, will it stop?
No! No!
Can you tell us why?
The engine is eternal
Yes!
The engine is forever
Rumble, rumble, rattle, rattle!
Who is the reason why?
Wilford, yeah!
Wilford! Wilford! Hip hooray!
I love that one, such a tonic.
Oh, it's time, children!
Come this way! Don't trip now!
Don't push! There's plenty of room.
Who can tell me what's coming up?
The Frozen Seven!
Pay attention. This tableau
will surely be on the exam!
Fifteen years ago, in the third year of
the train, seven passengers tried
to stop Wilford's Miracle Train and go outside!
And what do we call this event, Magdalena?
The Revolt of the Seven.
Very good. Long before you were born.
Of course, they failed to stop the train.
Instead, they jumped out of the running train.
Here they come now.
You look too.
Why?
There they are. That's how far they made it.
That person in the front...
...was a cleaning lady from the front section.
She was an Inuit. You know, Eskimo.
She taught me about every type of snow and ice.
She believed we could survive outside the train.
If we ever go outside the train?
We'd all freeze and die!
If the engine stops running?
We'd all die!
And who takes care of the Sacred Engine?
Sir Wilford!
Children! It's the New Year eggs from Mr. Wilford!
Touch them, they are still warm.
These eggs are boiled using water
heated by the Sacred Engine itself.
As a special treat, we have playing for us,
the world-renowned first chair violinist of
the Boston Symphony Orchestra.
Mr. Gerald McInster!
Is that really Gerald? He looks damn great!
No, thank you very much.
Let's go, Curtis.
Happy New Year!
I thought the chicken was extinct.
There are actually many things on board
were rumored to be extinct.
Such as?
This.
Andrew! No!
It wasn't me! It wasn't me!
No.
Curtis!
You have to lead us.
Curtis, my friend.
We understand each other.
Listen to my words! It wasn't me!
We go forward.
Open!
Hurry!
It's Mason.
Shit. Check her pulse.
Hey, hey, fire regulation...
God, that does not look good.
He's coming.
Got the master key, right?
Wait, don't shoot. Please don't shoot.
You just killed a Front Section Passenger! I'm...
I didn't see a thing.
Where are you going? Wait, just wait a minute!
Can't we talk about it just for one second...
You son of a bitch!
Close the door.
Tanya.
Oh...
My Timmy.
We're gonna find him. I promise.
I know.
Thank you.
You grab some too.
Hey, turn around, motherfucker!
You got my Kronole!
I want that shit!
I'm coming after you, man!
I want my Kronole back!
That's my Kronole, motherfucker!
I swear, man! I'm gonna kill you,
you spaced-out fuck!
Open the door.
Come on, Kronole.
Kronole? You want Kronole?
Here. Take it.
Open it. Open the gate!
You're crazy.
Fucking obsessed with gates.
Here, have a smoke.
You should be grateful.
The world's last cigarette, you tail section dick.
You ever been to the Tail Section?
Do you have any idea what went on
back there? When we boarded?
It was chaos.
Yeah, we didn't freeze to death
but we didn't have time to be thankful.
Wilford's soldiers came and they took everything.
A thousand people in an iron box.
No food, no water.
After a month, we ate the weak.
Do you know what I hate about myself?
I know what people taste like.
I know that babies taste best.
There was a woman. She was hiding with her baby.
Then some men with knives came.
They killed her and they took her baby.
And then, an old man...
No relation, just an old man.
Stepped forward and he said, "Give me the knife."
And everyone thought he'd kill the baby himself.
But he took the knife, and he cut off his arm.
And he said, "Eat this. If you're so hungry,
eat this. Just leave the baby."
I have never seen anything like that.
And the men put down their knives.
Probably guessed who that old man was.
That baby was Edgar.
And I was the man with the knife.
I killed Edgar's mother.
And then one by one, other people in the
Tail Section started cutting off arms and legs and...
...offering them.
It was like a miracle.
And I wanted to.
I tried. I just...
A month later, Wilford's soldiers
brought those protein blocks.
We've been eating that shit ever since.
Eighteen years I've hated Wilford.
Eighteen years I've waited for this moment.
And now I'm here.
Open the gate.
Please.
Thanks for your story, Curtis.
But I don't want to open the gate.
You know what I really want?
I want to open the gate.
Not this gate.
But that one.
The gate to the outside world.
It's been frozen shut for eighteen years.
You might take it as a wall.
But it's a fucking gate.
Let's open it and just get the hell out.
And freeze to death? What are you, fucking crazy?
What if we don't?
What if we could survive outside?
Remember the Yekaterina Bridge?
When you were being chopped up.
There's something I look at every New Year.
Under the snow is a crashed airplane.
Ten years ago, I could barely see the tail.
Now I can see its body and its wings.
There's less ice and snow.
In other words, it's melting.
The type of snow that's about to melt.
A little push and it all falls down.
Recently...
...you know what I saw?
Outside the window, there was...
Nevermind. I don't have to tell you this.
You gotta take it easy on that Kronole.
Snorting that flammable
shit's gonna fry your brain.
That's exactly right.
Kronole is originally...
...an industrial waste, highly flammable.
When it's lit, boom!
Simply put, it's a fucking bomb!
I didn't stock up on it for years just to get high.
It's to blow up this gate.
Give me the matches!
What the fuck are you doing?
Give it to me.
Take that off the door.
Curtis Everett.
I've been asked to extend a formal invitation from
Mr. Wilford to join him for dinner.
After you.
Curtis! Is that you?
Curtis, dear boy. Come in.
Let's take a look at you.
You hungry? You did a man's
work coming all this way.
Please sit down.
You are the first human being to have walked
the total length of this train. Tail to Engine.
Did you know that? Well done. Bravo.
None of your people have ever been here.
To the engine.
I've never been to the Tail Section.
Why not? Too dirty for you?
Don't want to rub against
the vermin of the Tail Section?
Do you think my station is
without its own drawbacks?
It's noisy. And it's lonely.
Right.
Steaks. Plenty of room.
This whore to bring you anything you want.
Curtis, everyone has their preordained position.
And everyone is in their place except you.
That's what people in the best place
say to people in the worst place.
There's not a soul on this train
who wouldn't trade places with you.
Would you trade places with me?
Fuck you.
Curtis, dear boy, the fact is we are
all stuck inside this blasted train.
We are all prisoners in this hunk of metal.
Medium rare?
And this train is a closed ecosystem.
We must always strive for balance.
The air, the water, the food supply,
the population...
...must be always kept in balance.
For optimum balance,
however, there have been times
when more radical solutions were required.
When the population needed to
be reduced rather drastically.
We don't have time for true natural selection.
We would all be hideously overcrowded
and starved waiting for that.
The next best solution is to have individual
units kill off other individual units.
From time to time, we've had to
stir the pot so to speak.
The Revolt of the Seven.
The MacGregor Riots.
The Great Curtis Revolution!
A blockbuster production with
a devilishly unpredictable plot!
Who could have predicted your counterattack
with the torch in the Yekaterina Tunnel?
Pure genius. That wasn't what
Gilliam and I had in our plan.
What?
Don't tell me you didn't know.
Gilliam and I. Our plan.
Gilliam?
Gilliam.
The front and the tail
are supposed to work together.
He was more than a partner, really.
He was my friend.
Bullshit.
I don't believe you.
Our original agreement was for
the insurgency to end at the Yekaterina Tunnel.
And all the survivors would go back to
the Tail Section to enjoy much more space.
You're a fucking liar.
Gilliam would never do that.
It all worked out in the end.
Your counterattack actually made
the insurgency ten times more exciting.
Unfortunately, the front suffered
more losses than anticipated,
and Gilliam had to pay the price.
Ironic, isn't it?
How people dramatically cross that
thin barrier between life and death?
Now, there is just one last thing for us to do.
Tally up the numbers.
Hello, Wilford. It's me.
I'm at Gilliam's place.
Hold on.
Is it still the same number?
Yes, it still stands at 74 percent.
Okay. Carry on.
Wait.
Spare eighteen to celebrate our 18th year.
It's a... An excellent idea. Yes.
Your people.
God damn it, Claude. Mind the Engine!
She's getting sensitive recently.
Sit down and mind your table manners.
Just relax.
Calm down.
Boy, now I can see what Gilliam meant.
He told me you were brilliant and clever,
but always so tense.
When's the last time you got laid?
Like Gilliam said, holding a woman
is much better with two arms.
I'll miss Gilliam.
I'll miss our late night phone chats.
He could go on for hours,
all with only one arm!
What's with that face? What's the matter?
You look like a crazy person. As if there
aren't enough crazies on this train!
Blood!
Are you okay?
What happened?
Get down!
Yona.
Open that gate and get the Kronole!
See those wires inside?
Shit, tons of 'em...
Kill! You punk!
I believe it is easier for someone to survive on
this train if they have some level of insanity.
I mean as Gilliam well understood,
we need to maintain a proper
balance of anxiety and fear,
chaos and horror in order
to keep life going.
If we don't have that, we need to invent it.
In that sense,
the Great Curtis Revolution
you invented was truly a masterpiece.
Yona!
Red goes into 8!
No, 7!
Come with me, Curtis.
Something I want to show you.
You deserve it.
Come on.
She's waking up now.
Cozy, yes? Peaceful.
You are now in her heart.
I've devoted my entire life to this.
The Eternal Engine.
It is eternity itself.
Have you ever been alone on this train?
When was the last time you were alone?
You can't remember, can you?
So please do, take your time.
I just wrote it.
It's for you, Curtis.
Here.
I am old.
I want you to take my station.
It's what you always wanted.
It's what Gilliam wanted too.
You must tend the Engine, keep her humming.
Look, Curtis. Beyond the gate.
Section after section precisely
where they've always been and
where they'll always be all adding up to what?
The train.
And now, the perfectly
correct number of human beings
all in their proper places all adding up to what?
Humanity.
The train is the world, we the humanity.
And now you have the sacred responsibility
to lead all of humanity.
Without you, Curtis, humanity will cease to exist.
You've seen what people do without leadership.
They devour one another.
Yona, the Kronole!
Yona, stop!
No bullet?
Put the Kronole on the gate.
Look at them.
That's how people are.
You know. You've seen this.
You've been this.
Ridiculous, pathetic, aren't they?
You can save them from themselves.
This is what Gilliam saved you for.
Curtis.
This is your destiny.
It's ready!
Curtis has the match!
Curtis!
The match!
The space only allows for a very small person.
Young children under five.
The Engine lasts forever
but not so all of its parts.
That piece of equipment went extinct recently.
We needed a replacement.
Thank goodness the Tail Section
manufactures a steady supply of kids.
So we can keep going manually.
You fucking bastard!
Yona.
Take the fire.
Only one left!
Andy? Is that you?
Andy! You remember me?
Andy, stop! Listen to me!
Don't go up those stairs! Listen!
Andy!
Come here! Come over here!
Andy, listen to me!
Get out of there!
God damn it, Andy, listen to me!
Oh Curtis, don't be so melodramatic.
You know everyone has
their own preordained position.
Nice.
Dad! Dad!
Curtis. Curtis.
Just stay there!
First stage removal. First stage removal.
Streets prohibited to non-permits in one hour.
This conversation with Governor Henry C. Santini...
is brought to you by
Soylent Red and Soylent Yellow...
high-energy vegetable concentrates...
and new, delicious Soylent Green...
the miracle food of high-energy plankton...
gathered from the oceans of the world.
Because of its enormous popularity,
Soylent Green is in short supply.
Remember, Tuesday is Soylent Green Day.
And now, Governor Santini.
Thank you, Richard. Thank you.
It's a pleasure to be able to talk
to the people of the city of New York.
Bullshit.
Hey. What did you dig up
in those cases I gave you?
Matthewson...
murder.
Out of your jurisdiction,
across the city line in Philadelphia.
Chergov, murder.
Went home yesterday.
Donaldson, multiple rape.
Has a record in the Bronx.
Can be extradited.
Get him the hell out of Manhattan.
What about Zolitnikoff?
Well, give me time, will you?
You've been telling me that
for the last three days.
Well, I can't locate the files.
I spent hours on it at the Exchange today.
Talked to every other book
who was there.
You know, there are 20 million guys
out of work in Manhattan alone...
just waiting for my job and yours too.
I want to close that case
and sign it out.
What the hell kind of miracle
do you want of me?
I'm just an ordinary police book,
not the Library of Congress.
I don't know why I bother.
Because it's your job.
Besides, you love me.
- That margarine's turned.
- Son of a bitch.
Zolitnikoff, no record.
Matthewson, no jurisdiction.
Chergov, home. And Donaldson, extradite.
Why don't you eat something?
- I'm not hungry enough yet.
- It's not bad.
Tasteless, odorless crud.
You don't know any better.
Oh, for--
You know, when I was a kid...
food was food.
Before our scientific magicians
poisoned the water...
polluted the soil,
decimated plant and animal life.
Why, in my day,
you could buy meat anywhere.
Eggs, they had. Real butter.
Fresh lettuce in the stores.
I know, Sol. You told me before.
How can anything survive
in a climate like this?
A heat wave all year long.
A greenhouse effect.
Everything is burning up.
Okay, wise guy.
Eat some Soylent Green and calm down.
I finished it last night.
I was hungry, damn it.
- I'll hustle some more on Tuesday.
- You do that.
I don't want to get caught in another riot.
Get off. I'll charge up the batteries
before I go.
- You'll get a heart attack.
- I should be so lucky.
I've pedaled this damn thing
halfway around the world.
You know, I'm getting pretty sick of you.
Yes, but you love me.
Night shift again. I'll be damn late.
So get something to eat.
- What?
- Go with God.
Schmuck.
Gilbert?
Hey, Mr. Donovan.
I have something for you.
Get inside.
Great.
Handmade, isn't that?
Do you have the words straight?
I won't understand them
if I live to be 100.
You won't.
Okay.
There!
It's good to hear you laugh.
- Come on and play.
- No, thank you.
- Thank you for the toy.
- I'm glad it amuses you.
Let me do something for you.
Are you ready, Miss Shirl?
It's getting late.
Go ahead.
According to the inventory,
we're low on everything.
Okay, but I'm gonna bring you a surprise.
I demolished five saucers with one rocket.
Not bad for an amateur.
- I've got your curfew pass.
- Oh, good. I thought I'd lost it.
That makes it 279 D's and 15 cents.
Call it 279 D's even for Mr. Simonson.
Sign it, Brady.
Mr. Brady?
Think I forgot? I didn't forget.
You asked for something special,
and I got it. Come on over here.
How often can I offer a customer
something really fantastic?
Look.
Beef, Miss Shirl.
Beef like you've never seen before.
What do you want?
You, Mr. Simonson.
I knew soon.
They told me to say
that they were sorry...
but that you had become unreliable.
That's true.
They can't risk a catastrophe, they say.
They're right.
Then...
this is right?
No, not right.
Necessary.
To who?
To God.
I made the routine check.
He was alive at 10:35.
- What was your name again?
- Charles.
- Charles what?
- Just Charles.
It's perfectly legal.
God, we haven't had any trouble here
in years, not years.
The scanners and alarms
went out of order last Thursday.
- Come on. Let's have a look.
- Yes, it was Thursday.
The problem is parts.
The original manufacturer's out of business.
Our men fabricate replacements.
Takes them forever, just forever.
Nothing works, not really.
You can't believe the problems I have.
I'll have to tell the other tenants.
What do I do? Call each of them and say
Mr. Simonson in 22A was slaughtered?
Unit scanner and alarm,
the best there is.
We should have more guards.
- I told management--
- Wait.
We should have more guards.
Detective Thorn, 14th Precinct.
Tab Fielding. I was Mr. Simonson's bodyguard.
Furniture?
- Yes.
- Simonson's?
- Personal or building?
- Building.
- Where's Simonson?
- In the living room.
Let's go.
- What was his full name?
- William R. Simonson.
Occupation?
- Rich.
- Rich what?
Lawyer. Politics.
I had the impression
he was more or less retired.
Say, does this building
have a food inventory?
Yes, sir.
Wouldn't you know?
Get me some booze.
- That's not within your jurisdiction--
- Relax.
You're not working for him anymore.
Your contract's been canceled.
I've been paid to the end of the month.
Get the bottle.
Your boss didn't put up much of a fight.
He wasn't the type.
- Most people like to live.
- If you say so.
You're a dream.
Bourbon! Son of a--
Hey. Where were you, bodyguard,
when they were butchering your boss?
- He sent us out shopping--
- Us?
The girl and I. You know, Shirl.
So?
Well, we got back at 11.
I saw the jimmy marks on the door and ran in...
but obviously it was--
You know how to write?
Yes.
Why don't you go in the foyer
and write me a statement?
Include all your movements
tonight and yesterday...
and your employment number. Okay?
Okay.
He'd be alive if we hadn't gone out.
Now, you have nothing to regret.
He told us to go.
I think he wanted to die.
It was a stupid, amateur burglar.
Nobody's fault, Shirl.
Honey, it wasn't anybody's fault.
Working on your report?
- I was just trying to--
- Yeah, I know.
Hey, what's your name? Shirl?
Yes.
Come on in here a minute, Shirl.
Come on.
Shut the door.
Let's see your hands.
How many times you been
in trouble with the police?
- Never.
- I can't hear you.
Never!
No fresh bruises.
He didn't knock you around, huh?
You're a lucky girl.
- He never hit me.
- What?
He was a gentle man.
He never abused me.
I wished he'd lived forever.
- Unless you were fooling around.
- No.
- With the bodyguard maybe?
- No, I'm straight.
Ask Charles. I don't cheat.
Come on.
I'd never risk my job.
When you came back,
did you see the body?
Just for a moment.
- Was it like it is now?
- Yes, like it is.
Yeah?
- Sanitation squad is here.
- Just a minute.
What's your arrangement here?
I stay for the next tenant,
if he wants me.
I may have to see you again.
All right.
Okay, Shirl. That's all.
Thorn, I thought they had you
on riot control.
Right, Wagner.
Hatcher's got you working a double shift?
Me and everybody else.
- No wonder you look lousy.
- Thanks.
- How do you want him marked?
- Simonson. Murder. Dispose.
- They're full up at waste disposal.
- So check dispatch.
Here. You better sign for him.
- My usual cut?
- You'll get your cut.
Just so we understand.
Where are they taking him?
- What's the difference?
- Tell me, please.
He'll be driven outside the city
to a waste disposal plant.
When my grandmother died...
there was a ceremony.
- I remember.
- I know.
You got your report?
What about the death benefit?
We hold it, pending next of kin.
There is no next of kin.
You can file a claim in 30 days.
I was thinking of Shirl.
Sure you were.
Hey, Wagner!
Give me a lift home?
Hey, Sol!
What are you doing home?
What time is it?
Paper.
- New paper.
- Have some pencils.
Did you ever see a cake of soap that big?
Courtesy of your next assignment,
William R. Simonson.
Chelsea Towers West.
"Soylent Oceanographic Survey Report...
2015 to 2019."
Two volumes.
- Where in hell did you get all these?
- Off his shelves.
The only reference books he had.
You like them?
I love them.
Do you know how many books
were published once upon a time?
When there was paper and power
and presses that worked and--
What the hell?
Oh, my God.
This Simonson was a great man.
Love apple.
Isn't that beautiful?
Sol.
Beef?
Oh, my God.
How did we come to this?
Why the hell don't you get out of here?
Go back to your foolish work.
Come on, Sol. Don't take it so big.
Look, we're doing okay.
We're doing fine.
We're doing lousy...
just like when I was a boy.
Nobody cares. Nobody tries...
including me.
I should have gone home long ago.
Come on. I need you.
Simonson, William R.
Number ACX2167D.
- 200 D's cash or 250 in food coupons?
- Cash, please.
Death benefits, line up
at tables one and two.
Hey, Callahan, busy house tonight, huh?
So we'll double up the Tuesday riot detail
here at 62nd tomorrow.
That'll leave us thin up here at 101st,
so we'll back up with scoops there.
Got that?
So you finally made it.
- Do you know what time it is?
- You're the one with a watch.
I can't. The damn thing won't run.
Let me see it. Maybe I can fix it again.
Okay.
Oh, let's see. The Matthewson murder....
He's in Philadelphia, out of our jurisdiction.
His wife's been lying.
We'll pick her up if we can find her.
Here. Sign.
Zolitnikoff.
I'm working on it.
Which means you still
haven't got a damn thing.
How old is Sol Roth now?
He's doing all right.
He's had it.
It's time for you to get another book.
- I'll make arrangements.
- No.
- Sooner or later.
- Not now.
Well, it's your job.
Simonson.
Supposed to look like he was killed...
when he caught some punk
burglarizing his apartment.
- Well, what do you say?
- It was an assassination.
Just like that?
One: The alarm system was out of order
for the first time in two years.
Two: The bodyguard was conveniently out shopping.
Three: The punk didn't take anything.
And four: The punk was no punk.
He used a meat hook instead of a gun
to make it look like a punk.
- What did you take?
- Everything I could lay my hands on.
Well, what's for Mother?
One bill for me, 50 for Kulozik, 50 for you.
Ten for Wagner from your end.
- Simonson must have been big.
- How big?
Enough for Chelsea Towers West.
- Who did the inside work?
- For my money, it's the bodyguard.
- What about the furniture?
- Like grapefruit.
You never saw a grapefruit.
You never saw her.
Come on. Shove.
- You know what I really think?
- What?
I think it's really busted this time.
Quick-energy yellow Soylent
made of genuine soybean!
Hey! Watch where the hell you're stepping!
What may I do for you, sir?
Thorn, 14th Precinct.
We run a clean building here, Mr. Thorn.
- I want to see Tab Fielding.
- Second floor to the right.
- Who's there?
- Police.
Just a minute.
I'm not dressed!
Let me see your badge.
Open up.
All right.
Detective Thorn, 14th Precinct.
Sorry to make such a racket.
I want to see Mr. Fielding.
He isn't home.
- You Mrs. Fielding?
- I'm Martha Phillips. I live here.
I just met Tab yesterday
in connection with a case.
I had a few more questions
I wanted to ask him.
- Would you know where he is now?
- No.
When will he be back?
I don't know. He just left.
Swell.
New furniture?
- I've been with him for four years.
- Furniture?
Yes.
Hey, this is really a terrific place.
That's rice.
Yeah, I've seen it before.
Tab does pretty well for himself, doesn't he?
- He's got a good reputation.
- Who with?
- The people he works for.
- Who's that?
You know, Chelsea West.
Yeah. Well, when he gets back,
tell him Detective Thorn was here. Okay?
Anything you say.
Come on in here a minute, will you?
Sure.
I haven't seen an incinerator for years.
- Used it lately?
- No, it doesn't work.
What does?
Really a nice place you got here.
Really nice.
Plenty of room to move around.
Yeah.
We were very lucky to get it.
Sorry I had to bust in like this.
You know? Just routine.
- I haven't been very nice.
- You're just fine.
I should have offered you something, Mr. Thorn.
If I'd had the time,
I would've asked for it.
Son of a bitch.
I haven't eaten like this in years.
I never ate like this.
And now you know what you've been missing.
- There was a world once, you punk.
- Yes. So you keep telling me.
I was there. I can prove it.
I know. I know.
When you were young,
people were better.
Oh, nuts. People were always rotten.
But the world was beautiful.
It's late.
I gotta get to work.
What have you dug up on Simonson?
I've got a handful of reference work
20 years out of date.
You throw out a name
and you expect a miracle.
Simonson, Sol. Report, huh?
Schmuck.
Biographical survey, 2006.
Last one they published.
Simonson, William R.
Born 1954.
Evidently unmarried.
Graduated Yale Law School in 1977.
Principal partner, Simonson,
Borden and Santini.
- Governor Santini?
- Hold still. There's more.
In 1997, he was the director of
Holcox Manufacturing, Norfolk, Virginia.
Specialist in manufacturing
freeze-drying equipment...
for commercial food processing.
And in 2018...
Holcox was acquired by Soylent...
and Simonson became a member of the board.
The board of Soylent?
Your dead one was a very important man.
Soylent controls the food supply
for half the world.
- What about those?
- Oh, very technical and highly classified.
Unnumbered copies.
Officially, they don't exist.
Perfect.
- What else do you want?
- Everything.
Well, law, Soylent, oceanography--?
Across the board.
Across--? Oh, that's impossible.
Check the Exchange.
I need you to tell me that?
You know, I was a teacher once,
a full professor, a respected man.
Make a special effort, will you, Sol?
This case is for real, for a lot of marbles.
- For who?
- Never mind.
- Don't forget to pick up the water ration.
- I'll do that. I'll die if I don't get water.
Hey.
- Taste that.
- Taste what?
Taste it.
Strawberries?
Hundred and fifty bucks a jar of strawberries.
Thorn.
ID is RC105.
Get me the 14th Precinct.
Thorn, how about paying us a visit?
I can't. I'm following up the Simonson thing.
- Well, what have you got?
- He was a director of Soylent.
- What else?
- Well, right now, somebody's tailing me.
He's damn good at it.
Big deal.
Would you believe bodyguards
are buying strawberries for 150 D's a jar?
You'd better report in here right away.
Yes, sir, first thing in the morning.
That was Thorn.
He's a damn good cop.
Appreciate the difficulty, Ed.
But the department wants to cooperate
with the governor's office, right?
Whatever you say, sir.
It looks like a fair-complected man...
maybe someone close to you, a protector.
And if we refer back
to this card back here...
if you look at it, the time sequence
indicates a three-month period.
The cards indicate a secure trend
should follow shortly.
So things are looking up a bit, Kathy.
Thank you.
- Your hair looks beautiful.
- Thank you.
Who is it?
Thorn. Detective Thorn.
I had a few more questions
I wanted to ask.
Having a party?
Just my friends.
It's okay.
Ice.
Jeez.
That's great.
It's still over 90 out there.
Hey.
You know, if I had the money,
I'd smoke two, three of these every day.
Come on in here.
On the bed.
This is a nice place,
the way it's fixed up.
Perfume.
He was murdered, you know. Assassinated.
Robbery had nothing to do with it.
You understand?
Yes.
- Did he have any relatives?
- I never heard of any.
- Do you know who he worked for?
- No.
- You were with him for three years.
- He never talked about his work.
Did you meet his friends?
Sure, I met some of his friends.
What were their names?
- I was never really introduced, you know.
- Oh, come on, Shirl.
Well, there was a Mr. Lempeter...
a man called Tompkins...
and somebody called Santini.
That's all I remember.
He didn't bring people up here very often.
Santini's the governor.
So?
Where did you go with Simonson?
No place.
Shopping once in a while.
- Except--
- Except?
He took me to church.
Church?
About a month ago, and then again
a few days before he died.
What did he do there?
He prayed.
And he talked to a priest.
That's about all.
- Why would he take you to church?
- He didn't say.
Why do you think?
I think he just wanted
to have somebody along.
He was very strange towards the end.
He didn't touch me for months.
And sometimes for no reason at all,
he'd start to cry.
I saw him cry more than once.
Old people do that.
Do they?
I can't figure this Simonson.
If I was like him, rich, important...
plenty to eat...
real bourbon...
and a girl like you...
you wouldn't see me in church.
What are you doing here?
I've been looking all over the building for you.
I'll teach you to break my rules!
Furniture stays in units!
I've told you before.
- No!
- I mean it!
- I'll get rid of the whole--
- Hold it!
I didn't know you were here, Mr. Thorn.
We give them a day off a month.
We don't have to.
And they break every regulation in the book.
You'd think they'd be grateful for
what they've got here. Wouldn't you?
I'll tell you, Charlie...
they're here because
I called them for questioning.
- Is that so?
- Yeah.
Don't you believe me, Charlie?
You should have told me.
Why?
Regulations.
You wanna file a complaint?
What do you say, Charlie?
No.
I don't want to do anything unfriendly
like that, Mr. Thorn.
I wonder if any of these girls
want to file a complaint against you.
Maybe not.
Maybe they want to keep it friendly.
I hope so.
Don't you, Charlie?
Don't you?
Yes.
Get the hell out of here.
Look, maybe we better all go.
Come on.
Come on, baby.
Charles isn't as bad as some.
Don't you ever get mad?
What for?
I left my stuff in here.
It's still dark.
You could stay a while.
You could wash up.
I'll make you breakfast.
Why should you?
There's plenty of food in the refrigerator.
Charles wouldn't dare make trouble
for you now.
I got work.
I don't wanna be alone.
I'm frightened when I'm alone.
There's nothing I can do for you, furniture.
I got nothing to give.
The new tenant is coming
to look over the place.
He may not want me.
Well, I got a place,
but it's nothing like this.
This is like my home.
I've been here a long time.
You could take a shower
and let the water run as long as you like.
You got....
You got hot water here.
Very hot.
Jeez!
I haven't had a hot bath....
I'll rub you down afterwards.
All right.
You turn that air conditioner on
all the way.
All the way up. We'll make it cold,
like winter used to be.
- What about breakfast?
- Anything you like.
- Strawberries.
- An egg.
- No, strawberries.
- I've never seen strawberries.
All right. An egg then.
Who the hell needs strawberries?
Mommy! Mommy!
Mommy. Mommy. Mommy.
- Hey, Sister.
- Mommy!
Mommy! Mommy!
- Where's the priest?
- You'll find him over there.
Thorn, Father, 14th Precinct.
My name is Paul.
Have I done something?
No, I'm investigating the murder
of Mr. William Simonson.
- Who do you say?
- Simonson.
Quite an important man, a rich man.
I have no recollection.
- You talked to him.
- Did I?
No doubt about it.
A rich man.
Yes, I remember.
We don't see rich people here anymore.
There isn't even enough room for the poor.
There's just too many.
Far too many.
- Fa--
- My memory's eroded.
Chiefly, I assign space to people
who need space.
Do you need some space?
I need to know what he said to you.
- Are you sure he's dead?
- Yes.
- Really dead?
- He's dead.
- What did he talk to you about?
- Come back tomorrow. I'm very tired.
Father.
Father, did you hear his confession?
There should be a requiem mass,
but there's no room.
- Should I make room?
- This is very important.
I can't help you.
Forgive me. It's destroying me.
- What is?
- The truth.
The truth Simonson told you?
- All truth.
- What is it?
What did he confess?
Sweet Jesus.
- We're closing the Simonson case.
- The hell you say.
You heard me. The Simonson case is officially closed.
Felonious assault. Sign.
Yesterday you agreed it was assassination.
There's been 137 reported murders since then,
and we won't solve them either.
I'm not gonna falsify that report.
Got a suspect?
I've got leads.
This isn't somebody you scratch
after 24 hours and forget.
I told you there's been a tail on me.
Something stinks here.
- Look, you'll sign this, and I'll bury it.
- Like hell you will.
A member of the board of the Soylent Corporation...
was torn apart with a meat hook!
You can't sweep that carcass under the rug.
Who bought you?
You're bought when they pay you a salary.
Who's they?
High and hot. They want this case
closed permanently! Sign this!
You sign it!
If I close and somebody higher and hotter
wants to know why, it's my job!
Sign it. I'll cover for you.
I won't put my job on the line for you, Hatcher.
Not my damn job!
Hey, big shot.
Hatcher says you're on riot control.
Great. That really makes my day.
This was once called Gramercy Park.
Now it's the only tree sanctuary
in New York.
Governor. Sorry to disturb you this way, sir.
Not at all, Donovan. Not at all.
Your secretary told me where to find you.
It's urgent...
- or I wouldn't have come out here.
- I understand.
Now, what is it?
I'm to inform you the board
is determined to resolve...
the Simonson investigation immediately, sir.
- I thought it was resolved.
- Yes, sir.
But the police officer involved
refuses to close the case.
Perhaps because he went to church yesterday.
- What does that mean?
- It was Simonson's church.
The cop spoke 20 minutes with the priest.
So?
The same priest who heard Simonson's confession.
I don't wanna hear any more about it.
I can't hear any more about it.
Just do what you have to do.
Bless me, Father, for I have sinned.
It has been six months
since my last confession.
A real bargain, folks. Synthetic footgear.
Plastics. Plastic ware.
We have a large assortment of plastic ware.
Some are a little chipped.
Others have hardly any cracks.
Quick-energy yellow Soylent
made of genuine soybeans.
Soylent crumbs! Two D's a kilo.
Nothing cheaper in the market. Come and get it.
Soylent buns!
Get your genuine Soylent buns!
Keep moving right along.
Soylent Green. Soylent Green right here.
They gave me a quarter of a kilo.
I stood in line the whole lousy day,
and they gave me a quarter of a kilo!
Do you believe that?
Let me go! Are you gonna put up with this?
They're running out of the damn green.
- Idiots.
- Some foul-up at transport.
- This crowd will blow.
- I know.
Got the scoops standing by,
but I don't know if they can handle this.
When you gonna make the announcement?
As soon as I get up the nerve.
About five minutes, I guess.
Better pass the word.
Right.
This is the police.
This is the police. This is the police.
I am asking you to disperse.
The supply of Soylent Green
has been exhausted.
You must evacuate the area.
The scoops are on their way.
The scoops are on their way!
I repeat: The scoops are on their way.
Today is Tuesday!
Why would you leave that door open?
Mr. Fielding.
- Why did you set up Simonson?
- I didn't.
You're all there is.
- Who pays your bills?
- I do.
Oh, no. I won't hit a cop. Bastard.
Yeah, I know.
You get life for that, jerk!
Life in a waste disposal plant
in a Soylent factory someplace.
How about that big, fat Soylent Corporation?
Do you work for them like Simonson did?
How much did they pay you for that one?
Does Soylent buy your strawberries?
Anybody tails me, bothers me one more time...
I'll come back here and kill you both.
Got it?
Get off my back!
Thorn.
I was worried about you.
- What happened?
- Never mind.
It doesn't matter.
- Good evening, Mr. Roth.
- Good evening.
Thank you.
- Good evening, Mr. Roth.
- Mr. Roth.
- Evening.
Good evening, Your Honor.
I assume you have a priority police problem.
Yes, Your Honor.
It's about William Simonson.
And...
these.
Thorn.
Thorn. It's curfew.
How do you feel?
A lot better.
I did the best I could...
but I still think you should go see
the police doctor.
He might relieve me from duty.
You need a rest.
More than two days, and I lose my job.
- We could go to another city.
- What for?
They're all like this.
- The country?
- That's not allowed.
Those farms are like fortresses.
- Why?
- Good land's gotta be guarded...
the way they guard
the waste disposal plants...
and Soylent factories and the plankton ships.
You know, there are idiots in this world
who wanna take everything we've got.
- Maybe Simonson was one of them.
- I don't believe it.
It means there's no place for us to go.
That's right.
Why should we?
You be careful now.
Keep the scanners on.
Don't go anyplace without a bodyguard.
The new tenant comes tonight.
He'll like you.
You're a hell of a piece of furniture.
Don't talk to me like that.
Please.
Okay.
It's horrible.
You must accept it.
I see the words, but I can't believe them.
Believe.
The evidence is overwhelming.
- Simonson was a member of the board.
- Yeah.
He learned these facts,
and they shook his sanity.
The corporation knew...
he was not reliable anymore.
They feared he might talk...
and so he was eliminated.
- Then why are they doing this?
- Because it's easier.
I think "expedient" is the word.
What we need is the proof
of what they are doing...
before we bring it
to the Council of Nations.
Good God.
What God, Mr. Roth?
Where will we find him?
Perhaps at home.
Yes, at home.
I waited two whole damn years for an apartment
to open up in this building.
It's a nice place.
- How long have you been here?
- A long time.
How old are you?
Twenty-one.
Charles said you were 24.
That makes us both liars.
All right.
I sleep late.
I like a big breakfast and no lunch.
I'll organize the dinner menu.
Three or four times a week,
I have guests.
Sometimes it's business,
and then we have to be alone.
Sometimes it's fun,
and then we like a girl who's fun.
Are you fun?
May I help you, sir?
- It feels good.
- Yes, sir. Won't you come in?
And your favorite color?
Orange, I guess.
- Music?
- Classical.
- Light classical.
- I'm sure you'll enjoy it.
Sign here, please, Mr. Roth.
- A full 20 minutes?
- Oh, certainly. Guaranteed.
Thank you.
This way, please, Mr. Roth.
Good evening, ma'am.
May I have your name, please?
Well, I see that orange
is your favorite color.
- You want Mr. Solomon Roth?
- That's right.
This way, please.
My God.
It's truly unfortunate
that you missed the overture.
- I want to see him.
- That is prohibited during the ceremony.
Well, I can assure you--
Open that damn thing right now...
or I swear to God
you'll die before he does.
All right! All right.
Sol, can you hear me?
- Thorn?
- Yes.
Thank you for coming.
- Oh, dear God.
- I've lived too long.
No.
I love you, Thorn.
I love you, Sol.
Can you see it?
Yes.
Isn't it beautiful?
Oh, yes.
I told you.
How could I know?
How could I?
How could I ever imagine?
Horrible.
Simonson.
Soylent.
Listen to me, Thorn.
Thorn, listen.
I can't hear him.
Do something, damn it!
Yes, Sol.
You've got to prove it, Thorn.
Go to the Exchange.
Please, Thorn.
You've got to prove it, Thorn.
The Exchange.
Go to....
Hey!
- Dispatch.
- Thorn, ID RC105.
Get me the 14th Precinct. Urgent.
Just a moment.
- The circuit is in use.
- Well, break in!
It's a 6-1 priority.
Look, get me Chelsea Towers West.
Apartment 22A.
- Cut in if you get the 14th.
- Understood.
- Hello?
- Shirl, it's me.
Oh, Thorn, I'm so glad.
I have to talk to you.
No, there's no time.
- The new tenant wanted me.
- Good. Stay with him.
I want you to stay with him always.
Oh, Thorn, I want to live with you.
Just live.
- I have Lt. Hatcher.
- Plug him in.
Thorn?
Thorn.
- Thorn, where the hell have you been?
- I'm at the Exchange.
Hatcher, help me.
There's another one over there.
- Hey, punk, are you with us?
- Hatcher.
- Did I get him?
- Yeah, you got him, all right.
You don't listen too good,
but you're a damn good cop.
Hatcher...
get to the Exchange.
You gotta tell them they're right.
But let's take care of you first.
You don't understand.
I've got proof.
They need proof.
I've seen it. I've seen it happening.
They've gotta tell people.
- Tell them what?
- The ocean's dying. Plankton's dying.
It's people.
Soylent Green is made out of people.
They're making our food out of people.
Next thing, they'll be breeding us
like cattle for food.
You've gotta tell them.
I promise, tiger. I promise.
I'll tell the Exchange.
You tell everybody.
Listen to me, Hatcher.
You've gotta tell them!
Soylent Green is people!
We've gotta stop them somehow!
[English - US]
Out there
There's a world outside of Yonkers
Way out there
beyond this hick town, Barnaby
There's a slick town, Barnaby
Out there
Full of shine and full of sparkle
Close your eyes
and see it glisten, Barnaby
Listen, Barnaby
Put on your Sunday clothes
There's lots of world out there
Get out the brilliantine
and dime cigars
We're gonna find adventure
in the evening air
Girls in white in a perfumed night
Where the lights are
bright as the stars
Put on your Sunday clothes
We're gonna ride through town
In one of those new
horse drawn open cars
We'll see the shows at Delmonico's
And we'll close the town in a whirl
And we won't come home
until we've kissed a girl
...ride through town
In one of those new
horse drawn open cars
We'll see the shows
at Delmonico's...
And we won't come home
until we've kissed a girl
Buy N Large is your super store
We got all you need
and so much more
No Monday in your Sunday
No Monday in your
Sunday clothes
Put on your Sunday clothes
when you feel down and out
Strut down the street
and have your picture took
Dressed like a dream
Your spirits seem to turn about
That Sunday shine is a certain sign
That you feel as fine as you look
And we'll recall
When time runs out
That it only
took a moment
to be loved
a whole life
long
And that is all
that love's about
...a moment
To be loved
a whole life
long
Hold me close and hold me fast
The magic spell you cast
This is la vie en rose
When you kiss me heaven sighs
And though I close my eyes
I see la vie en rose
When you press me to your heart
I'm in a world apart
A world where roses bloom
And when you speak
Angels sing from above
Everyday words seem
to turn into love songs
Here is a little song I wrote
...note for note
Don't worry
Be happy
Monday in your Sunday
No Monday in your Sunday clothes
Put on your Sunday clothes
when you feel down and out
Strut down the street
and have your picture took
Dressed like a dream
Your spirits seem to turn about
That Sunday shine is a certain sign
That you feel as fine as you look
...new down to your toes
Get out your feathers
Your patent leathers
Your beads and buckles and bows
And that is all
that love's about
And we'll recall
When time runs out
That it only
Took a moment
to be loved
A whole life
long
...find adventure in the evening air
...horse drawn open cars
Buy N Large
...it only takes a moment
...Sunday clothes
when you feel down and out
Strut down the street
and have your picture took
That Sunday shine is a certain sign
That you feel as fine as you look
Beneath your parasol...
...when time runs out
That it only...
Buy N Large is your super store
We got all you need
Put on your Sunday clothes
when you feel down and out
And that is all
That love's about
And we'll recall
When time runs out
Took a moment
to be loved
a whole life
long
Did you think that your feet
had been bound
By what gravity brings
to the ground?
Did you feel you were tricked
by the future you picked?
Well, come on down
All these rules don't apply
When you're high in the sky
So come on down
Come on down
We're coming down to the ground
There's no better place to go
We got snow up on the mountains
We got rivers down below
We're coming down to the ground
We hear the birds sing in the trees
And the land will be looked after
We'll send the seeds
out in the breeze
Did you think
you'd escaped from routine
By changing the script
and the scene?
Despite all you made of it
You're always afraid
of the change
You've got a lot on your chest
Well, you can come as my guest
So come on down
Come on down
We're coming down to the ground
There's no better place to go
We got snow up on the mountains
We got rivers down below
We're coming down to the ground
We hear the birds sing in the trees
And the land will be looked after
We'll send the seeds
out in the breeze
Like the fish in the ocean
We felt at home in the sea
We learned to live off the good land
We learned to climb up a tree
Then we got up on two legs
But we wanted to fly
And when we messed up
our home land
We set sail for the sky
We're coming down to the ground
There's no better place to go
We got snow up on the mountains
We got rivers down below
We're coming down to the ground
We hear the birds sing in the trees
And the land will be looked after
We'll send the seeds
out in the breeze
We're coming down
Coming down to Earth
Like babies at birth
We define new priorities
These are extraordinary qualities
We're coming down to the ground
There's no better place to go
We got snow up on the mountains
We got rivers down below
We're coming down to the ground
We hear the birds sing in the trees
And the land will be looked after
We send the seeds
out in the breeze
We're coming down to the ground
There's no better place to go
We got snow up on the mountains
We got rivers down below
We're coming down to the ground
We hear the birds sing in the trees
And the land will be looked after
We send the seeds
out in the breeze
We define new priorities
These are extraordinary qualities
To find on Earth
(Narrator) 'The future.
'The polar ice caps have melted,
'covering the earth with water.
'Those who survived
'have adapted to a new world.'
Ah!
(Gargling)
(Metal clanging)
(Breeze plays harmonica notes)
(Chimes tinkling)
(Whistles)
(Speaking PortuGreek)
Bad luck, English.
But the Slavers are producing
a good grade epoxy these days.
Cost you a handful of dirt
or maybe that wind chime.
- What are you doing here?
- Just waiting.
Take your hand off the sail.
Take it off!
I've seen your boat before.
Haven't seen you.
Took it legal.
The previous owner was dead
on the tiller when I found it.
You had another hour
before I traded up again.
- Just improving my means.
- Well, I owe you, then.
No, thanks. I got all the supplies I need.
Just came from an atoll.
Eight days east, if you are interested.
Two Drifters meet.
Something needs to be exchanged.
I know the code,
but I'll give you this one for free.
Nothing's free in Waterworld.
(Chuckles) Yeah.
Smokers.
Just enough wind to get away clean.
(Drifter) Forget the bag!
It's not worth it.
You'll never make it with your sails down.
Hey!
Ha-ha-ha!
What can I say?
Joe, he's going for it.
What the hell...?
Never seen that before.
Here we go! Go! Drive! Drive!
Faster! Faster!
Whoo!
Come on! He's gonna get it!
- Go!
- Get him! Get him!
(Chuckles)
No!
No! Argh!
(Smokers yell)
- (Gunfire)
- Argh!
(Drifter cries out)
(Shouts in PortuGreek)
(Exchange in PortuGreek)
(Old man) Do you want keep these hair?
Do you want keep these hair?
Take small hydro. Small cup hydro.
How many ways can I say it?
Go on, hit the swell.
Do you want keep these hair?
Take small hydro.
What do you think?
He does have a bush on him.
Do a side barter if you want,
but don't open the gates.
(Old man) Small cup hydro!
Do you want keep these hairs?
Inbound! Straight out.
Ingls!
Flags down, Drifter.
We've got enough traders.
(Murmuring)
- (Woman) What does he have?
- (Man) What's he got?
Dirt!
(Man) Open the gates!
(Chattering)
(Elder)
Bones to berries, veins to vine.
These tendons to trees,
this blood to brine.
Too old she was.
This woman does leave us,
recycled and enshrined
in the presence of him who leads us.
(Children chattering)
My eyes! That hurts!
(Child) What is that?
You know me?
- I know what you are.
- Good.
Then you know
if you look for trouble here,
you'll find more than you can handle.
You've got two hours.
I'll only need one.
He's coming over here.
- Me!
- You each get one
if everything's here when I get back.
(Man) Look at that.
- Pure dirt.
- (Gasps)
3.2 kilos.
How d'you come by so much of it?
Another atoll 30 horizons west of here.
- Where'd they get it?
- They didn't say.
(Man) We heard about that place.
Heard they was all killed.
- That's why they didn't say.
- Smokers?
Maybe Smokers, maybe Slavers.
So what's it worth? We trading or not?
We'll tally it like...
pure hydro.
Works out to...62 chits.
- I want twice that.
- (People gasp)
You drive a hard bargain.
Dirt?
I have never seen purer.
- I just want one sip of hydro.
- No, not till you tell me.
She's got inkings on her back. I seen her.
They say if you read the marks
on the child,
they'll lead you all the way to Dryland.
- Dryland's a myth.
- Aw, some still believe.
They say the Smokers even got
an eye out for her.
Well, then,
we better keep it to ourselves.
- Help you?
- Yeah.
- Where's the store?
- You found it.
You don't have much.
You the man with the dirt?
I'll take the hydro. All six Gs.
Got any canvas? Line?
I've got line. It's hair. No canvas.
I'll take the line.
- Any seeds?
- Nope.
- Wood?
- No.
Magazines?
If I had a magazine,
I'd retire.
Something to drink?
A cup of hydro.
Pure.
Skol.
- One more.
- Make it two.
A man this rich will buy
for a fellow outwater, I'm sure.
One.
That's an interesting pair of boots
you've got.
- Trade?
- No.
So how long you been out there, man?
Don't hurt asking. Talking costs nothing.
- Depends. What lunar is it?
- Well, let's see.
April, March, June. It's August.
- This August?
- Yep.
So how long?
- Fifteen.
- Fifteen lunars?
(Whispers) That's her.
Enola, hey, what are you doing?
- No, you can't have that.
- I need another piece to draw some more.
I'll get it. I'll give it to you.
Just stay in the back.
With all those chits,
you could order up a bath.
- Why are you talking to me?
- Just being friendly.
- Is that a tomato plant?
- Yeah.
- You have a keen eye.
- I saw one in a picture. How much?
Half your chits.
- I'll take them, too.
- Take what? You bought everything.
I'll take them shelves.
So, what did you see out there
in your 15 months?
- Such as?
- An end to all this water.
You're asking the wrong person.
- The one they buried today.
- Uh-huh?
She found the only end there is.
I've got a proposition for you, Mariner.
I'm not bargaining. I'm leaving.
But you haven't even heard anything yet.
Or seen it.
You may have noticed us burying a citizen
today. That makes room for one more.
I'm not staying.
Oh, we're not asking you to.
All we want is your seed.
(Man) We can look to our own
for impregnation,
but too much of that sort of thing gets...
undesirable.
When she's pregnant, you go on your way
with all the supplies you need.
You don't have anything. You're dying.
No man stays out that long
and turns down a woman.
He's hiding something.
Maybe he's a Smoker spy.
(Whistles)
When the Elders say so, you can leave.
And not before.
Ah. Gills.
- Mutation!
- He's a Muto!
(Grunting)
Aaargh!
(Man) Get him!
(Man) Throw the nets!
(Yelling)
(Man) He's a murderer!
Aargh!
By what right?
You pay me to keep the peace.
- This isn't it.
- No! He has killed one of us.
- He was defending himself.
- He needs to be destroyed!
- Kill him!
- That may be.
- But not here, and not like this.
(Metal gears turning)
(Boy) What is it?
Hey!
(Man) Too tight! I can't get it off.
(Man) Open the gate!
(Chuckling)
(People arguing)
(Man) Order!
This is another device we found
on the boat.
A garrote cord for strangulation!
We, we don't know what this is all about,
but we believe it to be
some sort of torturing device!
And this - this is a spy tool!
For listening to the unsuspecting!
The evidence speaks for itself.
I move that we dispense with the Muto
as soon as possible and...
(Helen) Why?
Why not use him?
Because he is a threat to the safety
and the purity of this atoll.
- He is not a threat. He's in a cage.
- He killed one of ours, Helen.
(Shouts of agreement)
- Is he dangerous or not?
- I'd say he is now.
But he came in here with all this dirt,
the likes of which we haven't seen
since Enola came.
Oh, what about it?
So it had to come from somewhere.
- What if it came from Dryland?
- Ah, don't start!
He came from the west, I can tell you.
Smokers come from there, from the west.
But if he is a spy,
this ichthy man will give away
our position, our weaknesses.
And if he isn't?
He is still a Muto and he could
contaminate our community!
- And others!
- What others?
We haven't seen another atoll
in over a year.
- Let's keep to the issue at hand.
- No, this is the issue at hand.
Every year, every month, it gets worse.
There are fewer atollers, fewer traders.
Dead gardens,
these windmills that don't work.
Desalinators that can't be fixed.
This place,
this whole way of living, it's ending.
- Doesn't anyone else see that?
- When I was a boy, we had lots of atolls.
You keep on praying for help and now
one man comes here who might actually...
- He's not a man!
- It doesn't matter what he is!
I say, if he knows the way to Dryland,
make him show us where it is!
People have looked for centuries
and death is all they found.
- At least they died trying!
- It's a hoax!
The sooner you realize that, Helen,
the better off we're all going to be!
We'd be better off if we got rid
of that girl of hers, too.
(Man) Right!
Smokers are looking for her!
I heard it from a trader.
- (Bangs gavel)
- One matter at a time!
I say get rid of both of them!
- The Muto and the girl!
- Yes!
- (Clamor)
- Yes! Kill them!
Order!
(Humming)
(Footsteps approach)
(Sniggering)
You'd like this, wouldn't you?
- Stick him.
- He sure is quieter than he was.
- Come on, let's go.
- No! Stick him again.
I know you want it. I know -
maybe he don't eat his own kind.
Aaaargh!
(Gregor) Aha! That's it!
A-ha-ha! That's it!
Don't move, my dear!
Polaris to Taurus.
I forgot Taurus, the bull.
In the shoulder of the bull
there's six sisters.
Or seven, but you can only see six.
At the beginning of each lunar,
one sister is lined up with Scorpius!
And Scorpius has a tail just like an arrow
on the circle on the back of the child!
If I take into account the seventh sister,
and give the seventh sister a lunar,
that lunar would run perpendicular
to Scorpius,
creating a horizon, a straight line,
that would run directly...
directly toward...
Dryland?
No.
(Screams) Is it a map?
Is it calendar?
Is it symbols? Is it language?
- You'd tell me if you knew, eh, Enola?
- Mm-hm.
- What are you drawing?
- I don't know.
Helen, look. Look at
the prodigal child's latest vision.
(He chuckles)
We've got to get out of here.
- I take it the meeting didn't go well.
- They're cutting us adrift, Gregor.
No, they'll not hurt you.
I'd turn their lights off if they did.
How soon before we can go?
Another week, ideally.
We don't have a week.
Helen, I don't have any idea yet
where we can go.
Try. Try it once again.
There's nothing in them.
I've been through the books.
There's nothing in these books.
She is the annunciation. I know it.
I just don't know how.
I'm a stupid man.
The answer's right there. It's...
It's just beyond me.
Maybe he knows.
Ah, yes, I see.
They are webbed.
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven,
eight, nine, ten digits. That's wonderful.
They tell me, too, that you have gills.
Isotropic gills.
Are they merely vestigial or functional?
My name is Gregor. I've just come
to pay you a little vi...vi...
Oh, my God.
I'm sorry. I'm not laughing at you.
I'm excited.
Your gills, they are functional. Ichthys
sapien. You can breathe in the water.
How deep can you go?
Look, I'm only here because I want
to learn more about you.
(Mariner spits)
You don't like humans very much, do you?
I can't say that I blame you.
But, tell me, are all of your kind
as bad-tempered as you?
- I have no kind.
- Oh, fish rot.
I'd be surprised if there weren't others.
If there aren't, there will be eventually.
Anyway, I come here
because I need to ask you a question.
Where... Where did your dirt come from?
Is it from Dryland?
Do you know what this is?
The Ancients, they did something terrible,
didn't they? To cause all this water.
- Hundreds, hundreds of years ago.
- If I tell you, will you open this lock?
I haven't a key.
- There's a mooring cleat down there.
- What?
- As good as any key.
- A mooring cleat?
I won't hurt anyone. I'll just leave.
- I'll be right back.
- (Man) Gregor!
- What's your business there? Move along!
- I'm not a brave man.
If you know anything about Dryland,
please, tell me.
Please. Don't let it die with you.
No, no, no.
Stop!
(Man) Gregor?
Move along!
(Smokers howl like wolves)
(Bell tolls)
- Get out of the way!
- Oh!
(Elder) After considerable deliberation
of the evidence at hand,
it is our decision that this Muto
does indeed constitute a threat.
Therefore,
in the interest of public safety,
he is hereby sentenced to be recycled
in the customary fashion.
Proceed.
I'm sorry.
Bones to berries, veins to vines,
these tendons to trees,
this blood to brine.
Too strange for life he was,
this Muto now does leave us,
recycled and entombed,
in the presence of him who leads us...
Smokers!
Dead out of the sun!
To your posts!
(Alarmed yelling)
(Woman) Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
Kill!
There!
Aaah! Aaah!
Get to your posts!
We are safe, behind this wall!
Aren't we?
Let me out! Let me out! I'll fight!
Get those bullets loaded!
- I can't find my dad.
- He's probably on the wall.
Go in, get a weapon and fight! Go now! Go!
Go, go!
Give me the key to the city now.
Let's go! Let's go! Let's go!
Floor it! Floor it! Go on!
(Woman screaming)
Swab it! Swab it!
Hurry them up!
Burn down the door!
Burn it down!
Aargh!
We'll have this atoll in no time.
Crank it! Crank it!
Look!
(Yelling)
- Now!
- Aaaah!
(Screams)
Oh, no!
Oh, my...!
Helen!
Keep that gas going! Fill 'em up!
Aaargh!
Aargh!
It's the girl they want!
Give them Enola and they'll leave!
Come quickly! Helen!
Aah! Aaargh!
You're not supposed to go yet!
Infernal machine!
Damn you!
Gregor? Gregor! Wait!
Helen, I tried. There was an accident.
I couldn't make it stop. Hurry!
You can make it if you try!
Up those stairs! Run!
- Wait!
- Quickly! I'll throw you a rope!
- Run quickly!
- Throw the rope now!
Throw the rope! No!
- No!
- Wait!
- Don't leave us!
- No!
I'm sorry! It was an accident!
Helen!
Enola! Helen, I'm sorry!
Shoot him. Shoot him.
Aaargh!
If I let you out of here,
you're taking us with you.
Sure.
Enola, get down.
Come here. Get down.
Hurry! Come on!
Get the gate!
Argh!
(Mariner) Hurry up!
Kamikaze! Come on!
That made a hole.
Find her! Get the girl!
There!
Go! Get that guy! Go! Kill him!
- Wow!
- Enola!
- You're too slow!
- Run to the other side.
Come on!
Grab on! Hold on, hold on.
It's stuck! I can't make it through!
Let her go!
- (Bullets fly)
- Just drop her!
Turn the wheel! The wheel! Turn it.
That!
- Come on, push it!
- I am!
Hurry! Push it hard!
Push it hard!
OK, OK!
Now pull it! Pull it! Go! Go!
Pull it!
- Enola, jump.
- (Bullets hit hull)
- Just look at me! Jump!
- OK!
Well, excuse me!
Did I say anybody could leave
before the battle was over? Did I?
- No!
- Well, do something! I hate sails.
Hey!
- Can you steer?
- Can I trust you?
Answer me this, somebody.
Why is that boat still firing?
- What's that cousin's name?
- Chuck.
- Hey, Chuck!
- He's pulling him right into us!
Maybe he doesn't answer to Chuck.
Call him Charles. Charles!
- Stop him! Stop him!
- (Machine gun roars)
(Men cry out)
Charles!
Adios, cousins.
(Woman) Put me down! Put me down!
She's here somewhere. Keep looking!
(Chainsaw buzzes)
Ah!
(Stammers)
660 Gs of hydro,
three-quarter grade or better,
120 keys of assorted edibles -
fish and plankton cakes -
and 60 keys lamp oil,
44 old-grow grapevines,
ten assorted fruit trees,
zero reloads - no ammo storage
on this particular atoll.
Uh, zero go-juice.
No refining capability.
Primitive savages!
Oh... How about smokes?
Uh, zero. Zero smokes.
I remember when this used to be fun.
How long since we had
a really good crusade?
- I know, I know.
- Tell me, how long?
- I don't know...
- Remember,
there used to be atolls on every horizon.
Mm-hm.
Where the hell are they all going?
Well, we sunk a few.
- I found this.
- Nord... Oh, now that's warmer.
- All right. And the girl?
- Not here. She might have gotten away.
That's why we came here!
We didn't come here to practice!
We don't need practice!
- What you got?
- A couple of heartbeats.
Aren't saying much.
If you notice the arterial nature
of the blood from the hole in my head,
you can assume we're all having
a real lousy day.
So here it is. I need to know
about that tattooed girl.
- First one that tells me lives.
- I saw a girl! I saw her!
She had a big tattoo on her.
You won. Start over.
I-I saw a girl. I'm not sure,
but I think she got on that boat
with three hulls.
The boat that cost me a thousand Gs
of go-juice?
- The Muto's boat.
- Muto?
Yeah, he's got these slits here,
like...like fish gills.
He wasn't really a man.
A fluke of evolution!
Oh, I'm sorry. A fluke of...
- Evolution.
- I know!
Let's have an intelligent conversation.
I'll talk and you listen.
In the beginning,
the provider said,
"Let there be water!"
and the seas came forth.
- He created everything that we know...
- Hey, hey! The Deacon!
The air that we breathe!
He made also both man and fish
and no combination thereof!
He does not abide the notion of evolution!
Amen!
- No! You said you wouldn't kill me!
- Did I say that? Witnesses? Anybody?
- Yes, yes, yes, you did.
- Ah, I may have!
I may have.
No!
We get to the 'Dez,
take up that sky boat,
send it out on patrol.
We got to keep an eye out
for that ichthy freak!
I know what you're thinking.
How much longer that hydro would last
if there weren't three of us on this boat.
Well, Enola won't drink much.
And I won't...
I won't drink at all.
Not till we get there.
Get where?
Wherever you're going.
Wherever you got your dirt.
I told you I salvaged it
off an atoll the Smokers hit.
Smokers don't leave anything after a raid.
Especially dirt.
You've been there, haven't you?
Dryland?
You know where it is.
- Yeah, I know where it is.
- Oh...
And...
- And we're going?
- You and I are.
The kid we've got to pitch over the side.
- What?
- My boat's tore up.
I'm taking on water. I'll be lucky to get
half a hydro ration out of that.
You know, I said I won't drink.
For 12 days?
No. It's better one of you dies now
than both of you die slow.
Wait, wait.
We saved your life. We got you out.
No, you got me out so you could get out.
We're even.
She can cook. She can fish.
- So can I.
- Take my necklace.
- I got better ones below.
- No, look! Oh.
After what you went through
back there on the atoll,
I can understand why you would want to.
But she's a child.
(Humming)
Is there something else, then?
Enola, go below.
Enola.
Yeah.
You said so yourself.
Been out there a long time.
A couple of hours ago,
I was potential dirt to you.
- We're not like that.
- You all are.
Know what I was really thinking?
Why I don't drop both of you
in my wake right now.
You got nothing I need.
You're taking us to Dryland.
Killing's a hard thing to do well.
- Believe me, I'm not the one to start on.
- Both of us!
- How long do you plan to hold that on me?
- As long as it takes.
OK.
Ah!
Let me out! Let me out of here!
You coward! Don't you touch my child!
Come here! I...
(She grunts)
Oh...
OK, now don't move, OK?
There. Oh, looking real good, yeah.
There.
There. All done.
Now there may be some small problem
in depth perception.
It better not screw up my short game.
Well?
- (Woman) Looks good.
- It's better than your real eye.
- Much better.
- What do you say, Toby? The truth.
- Looks like shit.
- That's why I love children. No guile.
It does look like shit!
- And it feels like cold shit!
- Deacon?
Sorry It's just there's a problem
in the pit. Maybe you should come.
Let's drive.
To the pit.
Don't bother with the scenic route.
Drive!
(Deacon) Hey, it's driving better.
( "Peter Gunn Theme")
(Rowdy yelling)
Get off!
Get off! Get out the way!
- Get out the way!
- All right, all right. OK, OK.
Bless you, cousins.
Bless all you cousins over there.
Keep up the good work!
Growth is progress, growth is progress.
(Man) Somebody!
Hey, up there!
Take it off!
- Yes?
- Your Deaconship.
Hello!
Good morning. Or night.
Whichever the case may be.
What is it? I'm a busy man.
I thought you should know
you're down to exactly
four feet nine inches of black stuff.
- Thank you, sir.
- How many Gs after refining?
- Maybe three refuelers.
- We'll burn through that in two lunars.
Sweet Joe! What's happening to this place?
- We outgrowed it.
- All right.
The only thing that is important
is the tattooed girl.
We don't spare any go-juice finding her.
We don't waste it anywhere else. Cancel
all those tractor pulls and all that stuff
until later. You got it?
Dryland is the mother lode.
Ha-ha! On your toes.
Why don't you use sea hydro?
The salt's harder on the filters.
Can we have some?
It's for her, not me.
Here, come on.
- Is he going to take us to Dryland?
- Sure he is.
Yeah.
All of it, all of it, all of it.
Good. Good, good. Come on.
Thanks for not killing us.
Just stay away from him.
- Hi.
- Move.
(Helen) Enola! Enola, come here!
Come on!
Enola, come over here.
Hey!
- What are you doing?
- Decorating your boat. It's ugly.
- Where did you get this?
- From down below.
This is mine!
You don't touch anything of mine.
- I drew it for you.
- Don't draw on anything! Understand?
This is my boat.
I got it the way I like it.
You take up space
and you're slowing me down.
You know, she's just a little girl.
She doesn't know your rules.
You wanna stay? You teach her.
Enola, what did I tell you?
You're not so tough, you know that?
How many people have you killed?
Ten? Twenty?
You talk a lot.
I talk a lot cos you don't talk at all.
So how many?
- Including little girls?
- I'm not afraid of you.
I told Helen you wouldn't be so ugly
if you cut your hair.
In fact, you talk all the time!
It's like a storm when you're around!
(Helen) Enola! Hey, what are you doing?
- Helen!
- She can't swim!
(Enola) Help me! Helen!
Helen, help me!
Help!
Helen! Help!
Hold on.
Look at me, look at me.
Oh... Wait. Come on.
Please!
Oh, please!
(Helen coughs)
Hey!
Hold on. OK... Almost.
(Gasping)
(Enola gasps)
Thanks. But I swear,
if you ever touch her again...
Sonofabitch! Look at me! You'll go to bed
that night and you will never wake up.
- Shut up.
- What?
- (Helen) Smokers?
- Yeah.
Well, can't we outrun them?
- (Plane engine hums)
- Not with my sail down.
- What are you thinking about?
- That's a nice touch.
That's them!
Don't hit the kid!
(Laughing)
Hey!
Coward!
(Laughs)
- (Gun jams)
- Fuck!
No!
Hey! Urgh!
Cut it!
Come on! Come on!
(Mast creaking)
Aaah!
(Helen) Oh...I'm really sorry.
I'm sorry! You didn't give me much choice.
I know. But you ran away.
I... What?
What are you do...? No! Please, no!
(Grunting)
Don't ever touch anything
on my boat again.
She said she was sorry!
That means you're supposed to
say something back!
- Did you say something?
- (Enola) Mm-mm.
(Deacon) Fore!
- Nice putt.
- It wasn't a putt. That was a drive.
I wasn't even using my good eye. Damn it!
You got an ashtray or something?
Oh, man.
Damn thing never did work right.
- You said to bring the pilot.
- Yes, I did.
- Well, he's here.
- Why didn't you tell me?
Come on, Nord. Well, tell me about it.
- The child. Did he have her with him?
- Yeah. And some atoll bitch!
They killed Ed!
Now, now. Don't you fret yourself.
Plenty more where Ed came from.
- Heading west south-west?
- From here.
If we launch now,
we can cut him down just about here.
- If he doesn't change course.
- That's not likely.
He's a wily one, that ichthy demon.
(Drifter calls out)
- Drifter?
- Mm-hm.
Are we going to stop?
- (Drifter) Look at the flag!
- His flag's up.
I thought you all stopped for each other.
Maybe he has some FOOD!
Don't find many who follow the rules
any more.
Make it quick. What's your business?
Trade.
Got any resin?
Resin? He's out of his mind.
He's out of his mind completely. Resin?
You've been outwater a long time,
haven't you?
Don't be joking me, man! Resin!
You don't got enough.
- How about food?
- Could you say that again, please?
- Well, yeah, food.
That'd be good, eh?
I haven't eaten in, well, you know,
forever.
Which one of you two is the cook, then?
I usually fall for the waitress.
- Like you said, I don't have much.
- I'll decide.
Look at you. We could start
with that wee orchard over there.
Woo!
(Mariner) All right. Hold it there.
- We can talk.
- Fair enough.
(Muttering)
It's a nice rod, isn't it?
I like that rod. It's a nice rod.
My favorite.
Got yourself a wee harem going here,
don't you now?
- What do you want for the women?
- We're not for sale.
Not for sale? I mean, there's
no such thing as not for sale.
Not for sale, not for sale. Aye.
Are they a pair
or would you sell them separate?
Our business is done here, unless
you've got some resin you can part with.
I told you once already, I don't have any.
I don't have it, don't have it.
Haven't seen any for trade in lunars now.
Wait. Wait, wait, wait.
I do have something
that'll make you change your mind.
Something you can't pass on.
I took it off an atoller refugee camp.
Life savings of the entire clan.
Paper! Look at my wee paper.
Paper! Have you ever seen paper?
Look at it, smell it.
I'm saving it for a special trade.
Don't you do it.
Maybe I'm talking to the wrong person.
Whose boat is this anyway?
- Is it your boat or your boat?
- It's his boat, but he doesn't own us.
- Half an hour.
- He's obviously out of his mind.
I've got two pages in here, man!
- I'd get half a dozen girls with this.
- Half an hour.
- You trading or not?
- Don't!
Shut up.
OK.
45 minutes with the wee one. I like to do
the talkin', if you know what I mean.
No!
Fair enough.
Come, come, come, come, come.
No. My boat.
That's fair enough.
Good, good, good, good, good.
Helen...
- Sit down.
- Enola, just do as he says.
Half an hour.
Well...
It's been a while for me now.
Guess it's been more than a while,
actually, but...
I've only got half an hour.
Half an hour, half an hour, half an hour,
half an hour, half an hour.
OK, right, right, right.
You're so beautiful.
Anyone ever told you that?
Give me that! What are you doing?
It's just a game!
Oh, I...
I... We was just playing.
Trade's off.
I changed my mind.
Well, um...
Well, you can't do that.
I mean, a deal's a deal. Aye.
I just did.
She's mine, aye. No, no, no.
I won't have it.
- No.
- Go on.
Go, go, go, good. Aye, aye.
Don't go too far now!
This won't take but a minute.
I hate this boat.
I...hate...this...boat!
You garbage!
You...
You're pretty stingy for a man
who's got everything, aren't you?
Aargh!
(Crashing and yelling)
Where's me boat?
(Mutters to himself)
Help me to me boat.
Ah! The boat...
Yeah, if he knows he's been spotted,
he'll expect us to expect him
to change course,
which is exactly why
he'll keep his heading.
The important question is
where's he headed?
And does he know
how precious his cargo is?
Dryland.
Salvation.
Room to grow 18 holes.
36, 72!
I say that he's headed here
and we take him here.
How long before we get some wind?
Days, maybe.
Then why don't we fish?
What for?
- So we can get something to eat?
- We ate two days ago.
You ate.
Just...
Just help me fix this.
I'll catch something myself.
You're not going to catch anything
with this around here.
Look,
we're not trying to make you angry.
And you don't disappear
when you turn your back.
- You don't know what fishing's like here.
- Then you do it, if you're the authority.
Maybe he doesn't know how to fish.
- I think you're right, Enola.
- Shut up, will ya?
- I'm trying to listen for engines.
- I will not shut up!
Until you stop what you're doing and help
me find something to eat for this child!
I will scream so loud that it...
Put that... No!
You'll never catch anything with this.
It's useless.
(Helen) Look, I'm sorry!
You were right about the pole.
You were right!
But we have to eat.
I know you can hear me!
We can fish for ourselves.
Just show us what to do.
- You must know. Even you've got to eat!
- You just sit there.
What...?
(Muffled explosion)
Happy now?
(Enola happily hums)
You don't like my singing, do you?
Helen says you don't like my singing
cos you can't sing.
- Ever try and listen?
- To what?
The sound of the world.
- I don't hear anything.
- That's because you're too loud.
And moving around all the time.
Try sitting still.
Eyeball?
Go ahead. Drink all you want.
It's gonna rain tonight.
I wish I had feet like his.
- Then maybe I could swim.
- Enola...
(Belches) Sorry.
I never met a person
who couldn't swim before.
I can't.
People said I was weird.
Maybe they're right.
Maybe they were right about you, too.
(Wind whistles)
( Mellow jazz trumpet plays)
Is that from Dryland?
(Turns music off)
Yeah.
(Sighs)
- I don't even know your name.
- I don't need one.
Enola wanted to give this to you.
And this.
She won't take it again.
You don't look much like her.
I'm not her mother,
if that's what you're asking.
You act like it.
About six years ago,
this basket floated into the atoll
with Enola in it.
Of course, everyone wanted to shove her
back out to sea. That was the law.
She was so precious.
I wanted to keep her.
So the Elders talked and said
that if I wanted her so badly,
I could never have a child of my own.
There was no one else.
She would have died otherwise.
So?
It's called compassion.
Oh...
You probably wouldn't understand
after being alone so much.
I'm not alone.
I've got this boat for a friend.
It don't lie to me,
don't cut my throat when I'm asleep.
Gives me a place to be.
I pity you, really.
- What's pity?
- You don't know?
If I knew, I wouldn't ask.
Well, if you don't know,
I could never make you understand.
- What are those marks on her back?
- Nothing.
- They're just fanciful things.
- Like what she draws?
She draws what she sees.
She's like a mirror.
People on the atoll thought she was a...
Freak?
Uh-huh. Yeah.
I just thought she was special.
I'm not giving it to her. It's just...
A loan.
Yeah. I'm not giving it to her.
Is Dryland beautiful?
You'll see.
(Enola giggles)
Enola?
Enola! What are you doing?
- Those monsters will kill her!
- They're asleep now.
Hands around my neck.
Let the water tell your arms and legs
how to move. Going down. Hold your breath.
- What is it?
Barter outpost.
- You said we'd get to Dryland today.
- Today, tomorrow. What does it matter?
We need resin.
(Speaks PortuGreek)
- What is that?
- It's PortuGreek.
Their own language.
That's what I thought.
Ah.
There's my girl. Yes.
Howdy, darling.
Come on in here now.
- What's going on?
- Smokers.
What the hell...?
He's spotted us!
Sound it! Sound it! Sound it!
Sound it! Sound it!
Woo-hoo!
Enola!
Starboard side! Now!
Get in the chair!
Watch it! He's clearing the net!
Go to the helm!
- Get the centerboard!
- Centerboard?
What centerboard? Where exactly?
I don't know what to do!
Under the helm, pull the handle!
Hey. Hey!
It's too late! Over here.
Aaah!
No!
Give me that rifle.
Boy, if you want to do something right,
you've got to do it yourself.
All right.
Ugh!
I winged him.
Load all the go-juice onto one boat
and run the freak down.
You can't catch him with ten boats
and you want to send just one?
Well, I pray that you're joking.
Bring me the Trackers.
You lied to us!
You were going to sell us back there!
Then we both lied.
What?
I saw what I saw.
- He's hurt.
- So he should be.
He was going to sell us.
No wonder you let her keep it!
You leave it!
- Why do they want her?
- There's nothing human about you.
They should have killed you
the day you were born.
They tried.
No more lies.
- Ah!
- What are the marks on her back?
People say it's the way to Dryland.
- Dryland's a myth!
- No!
You said so yourself that you know
where it is. You did.
You're a fool to believe in something
you've never seen before.
I've seen it. I've touched it. Dirt
that was richer and darker than yours.
In the basket we found Enola in!
- It doesn't exist!
- How can you be so sure?
I've sailed farther than most have
dreamed. And I've never seen it.
- But the things on your boat.
- Things on my boat? What?
There are things on your boat
that nobody has ever seen!
What are these shells?
And that reflecting glass?
And...and...and the music box.
If not from Dryland, then where? Where?
You want to see Dryland?
You really want to see it?
I'll take you to Dryland.
Get in.
- Well, what about Enola?
- There's only air for one.
- Get in the water.
- It'll be all right.
Don't touch anything.
OK?
I didn't know.
All this time?
- I didn't know.
- Nobody does.
- Can you get us out of here?
- I'd say there's two chances of that.
- Hey!
- No way and no how.
Should have bought me that drink.
Come on!
This way. Come on!
(Celebratory whooping)
(Man) Yeah!
Proper introductions first.
I'm the Deacon.
(Laughing)
If you don't recall the face, perhaps
it's cos I didn't always look like this.
Now, I suspect
she's somewhere real close.
So we could tear this boat apart,
but I'd rather somebody just tell me
where she is.
The first one that does that lives.
And the runner-up... Well, actually,
there are no runners-up.
Oh, sweet Joe, I love this part.
Choose 'em. One, two. Live or die.
You know, personally,
I'd rather shoot
the sperm of the devil here. Huh?
But you know something?
I don't think you're going to tell me,
are you? Huh? Too bad.
Come on. Eh?
What do you say? She's not your kind.
You don't even have a kind.
If you say it,
he'll still kill us both.
Let's not get ahead of ourselves.
If you don't tell me,
I swear to Poseidon
that we'll torch your boat.
Refresh my memory-
what if neither one of them talks?
- Never happened before.
All right! If they won't tell us
where she is, do 'em! Both of them!
- Just kill 'em now!
- No!
So gullible! Ha-ha! Bring her here.
- (Smokers cheer)
- Seek and ye shall receive!
So ends your daily sermonette!
Ha-ha-ha-ha-ha!
- Yes!
- Yeah!
Yes!
Here, take her, boys. Take care of her.
What is it?
Stunning.
I don't have words to even begin to...
It's magnificent.
Look at that! That square footage.
Huh? Huh?
Now figure this map out. Turn her upside
down. Does that mean anything to you?
No.
All right. We'll figure it out
back at the 'Dez, boys. Careful with her.
- What about them?
- Do 'em both. Torch the boat.
Aargh!
We have to go under!
No! I can't breathe like you!
I'll breathe for both of us.
Woo!
(Enola) Helen, help!
Helen!
My boat.
Enola...
(Deacon) A-ha!
All right!
I can't wait to get this thing out,
build some highways and some freeways!
There you go, cuz. Be careful now.
You break 'em, you can't use 'em.
Come on! What's happening, cousin?
Not a word.
She just sits there and leaks.
A shiver to the liver. This'll make her
give up all her secrets, huh?
Yeah, or kill her. Let me talk to her
first. I'm real good with kids.
What is this? Get those chains off her!
What are we, barbarians here?
Goodness gracious. Snakes alive.
Come on, out of here,
you big, nasty animal, you!
Rub-a-dub-dub. (Chuckles)
You want to come over here
and sit on my lap?
No.
How about a cigarette?
Nothing like a good smoke
when you miss your mom.
Never too young to start.
No.
Well, I got something right here
I know you'd like.
Like to draw, don't you? Huh?
Now they're yours,
if you help me
with just one problem. All right?
Now I got this parish.
A good parish.
A large parish.
Getting larger all the time, in fact.
Now, you know,
I just don't have enough space
- for all these people.
- Why don't you make less people?
Pardon?
The atoll. Babies are born
only when there's room.
That way,
there's food and hydro for everyone.
Well, that's a...quaint suggestion,
but it don't really play here,
considering we are, in fact,
the Church of Eternal Growth.
See, what we need is more land,
for more people.
Now... Now that tattoo on your back.
I've been told that that...
that's actually a map?
It's the way to Dryland.
Now we're getting someplace.
Could you teach me how to read that?
Setback.
Well, have you ever heard
any of your friends talk about it?
You know, like your mommy
or your pet fish? He say anything?
You shouldn't make fun of him.
He wouldn't like it.
Girl, I don't give a shit what he'd like.
He took out my eye!
And if I ever see him again,
I'm gonna cut open his head
and I'm gonna eat his brain!
You think he'd like that?
You can't kill him.
He's even meaner than you are.
But he's not here.
And he ain't coming.
And no one's gonna save you.
He'll come for me. He will.
Well, you better tell me
what I wanna know
or he can save what's left of you
in a goddamn jar!
I'm glad we had this little talk.
Chain her.
Chain her up.
He'll come for me! He'll take me away!
We're going to die here, aren't we?
Aren't we?
After the atoll,
when I offered myself to you,
why didn't you take me?
Cos you didn't really want me.
Not really.
Have I been sleeping?
I was dreaming.
It's funny.
I always thought Dryland floated.
Or drifted with the wind.
That's why it was so hard to find.
Why did you believe in it so much?
Cos we weren't made for the sea.
We've got our hands and our feet.
We're supposed to walk.
I miss her sound.
Don't you?
Might get some hydro out of this.
I can't go on.
Not without her, or Dryland.
I don't want to live
if there's nothing left,
there's no hope.
You're still here.
Thank you for saving me.
You can thank the Ancients.
- This is what they had.
- This is what they made of it.
That's why I am what I am.
I may not be human, but I don't quit.
Never have.
No matter what they throw at me, I...
(Gregor) Helen!
Helen!
No, no, no, no! Helen, up! Above you!
(Helen) Gregor!
(Gregor laughs)
Smart thinking to burn your boat!
Without the smoke,
I never would have found you.
Who's that with you?
Ichthys sapien! Is that really you?
I'll throw the rope down.
You catch it. I'll help you climb up.
Helen!
- Where's Enola?
- Smokers took her.
They'd have me, too,
if it weren't for him.
My friend,
thank you. Very human of you.
Grab your things quickly. Quickly.
Come.
You see? Right down there.
There's several other survivors.
We'll just start over again.
Don't worry. They'll welcome you,
just like Gregor did.
(Man) You can't ask us to go and get her.
(Woman) Enola's the reason
we're in all this trouble. Forget it!
(Helen) They need to find Dryland
just like we do.
Of course.
(Helen) If the Mariner's willing to go
after her, then why not us?
(Woman) We don't want you here!
You or the girl!
Helen...
The papers the Mariner brought you.
It's the same language
the tattoo is written in.
86...56.
27, 59. If I can figure out
what these numbers refer to...
- They refer to nothing.
- What?
Dryland doesn't exist.
(Man) You're as crazy as she is!
We're wasting valuable time. More Smokers
will come. We need to be moving now.
- We need this child to find Dryland!
- I'm not going.
- (Man) I say let him go.
- (Woman) We're better off without them!
You won't go after her either?
- I thought you were different.
- I am different.
(Man) Hey, hey! That's my sail!
- What's he doing?
- Leaving.
Not in one of our boats!
You can give it to him or he'll take it.
Enola said you were her friend.
What do I tell her when I see her again?
Lies.
If it makes you feel better.
Don't blame him.
Survival is all he knows.
That's why someday there will be
so many like him,
probably so few of us.
(Engines roar)
- What do you want?
- Uh, all kinds of things.
But, uh, right now
we'll settle for everything you've got.
Ain't that right, Bones?
(Man) You destroyed our homes!
Why can't you leave us alone?
I don't know.
It's a character thing, I guess.
Ain't that right, Bones?
Bones?
I'm going after Enola.
Here, you know,
for a hideous freak, you're OK.
It was a joke!
- Know what that is yet?
- The numbers? Yes, I think I do.
It seems to be some ancient form
of geographic location.
Latitude, longitude.
It doesn't make sense, though.
The numbers,
they seem to be backwards or something.
- It's upside down.
- The world?
- The poles have reversed themselves?
- I've been mapping the cities below.
The world wasn't created in a deluge.
It was covered by it.
- (Man) That's blasphemy!
- No, it's true.
I've seen it with my own eyes.
There's land.
- Right under our keel. None of it's dry.
- Some is.
Enola's been there. I know that now.
I saw what she drew.
That's why he's going after Enola.
To find Dryland.
I don't care about Dryland.
This is ridiculous.
Going after the Smokers?
He doesn't even know
which direction they came from.
If she's alive,
I'll bring her back to you.
(Woman) Forget about the Muto, Helen!
If he brings her back, they'll kill us!
We've got to go help him.
I can't ask him to do this alone.
Don't worry, my dear.
You're not going to have to.
- Hey, Doc, what's this?
- Where?
- Above the squiggle. Looks like a star.
- Or a meteor.
It's a mole.
- You got that tattoo figured out yet?
- It'd be easier if it was flat.
Big and flat. It needs to be flat.
- What have you got in mind?
- Well, you cut it off her back,
stretch it, mount it,
give us a proper look.
(Deacon)
Take her down below until I holler.
Saint Joe, we're close.
After centuries of shame.
(Distant echoing voices)
(Laughter and yelling)
- They're getting ugly.
- Don't I know it.
Announce me, cousin.
- Hey, here he is.
- (Crowd roars)
Rise up, brothers and sisters,
turn your eyes
and open your hearts
to your humble benefactor,
your spiritual shepherd
and dictator for life,
the Deacon of the 'Dez!
(Crowd roars)
(Deacon) Children,
children of the provider,
citizens of the good ship,
please now, hear me speak.
- I've had a vision.
- (Man) We're tired of your visions!
What about the land you promised us?
(Crowd cheers)
- Yeah!
- (Deacon) Oh, ye of little faith.
I've had a vision so great,
that as it came to me, I wept.
- And in this splenditudinous...
- (Smoker) Is that Bone's vehicle?
(Deacon) I saw - and you know
what it is that I saw.
I saw...
- the land.
- (Cheering)
(Crowd chanting)
- Horse, is that you?
- (Jet ski engine revs)
Look, just bring it in slow, OK?
I don't have all day.
(Engine revs)
Horse!
Just bring it up slow.
I said slow!
You killed Smitty, cousin.
- Nice landing!
- (Laughter)
Smitty, man, always in the way!
Smitty? I quit!
I'm in charge now, baby!
Yeah, I'm in charge.
I'm in charge!
(Deacon)
'And he said this to me personally.
'We are to go there
and we are to settle it.
'And we are to build the...'
You shouldn't be doing that.
You're going to get in trouble.
Huh! That's right.
You're not afraid. You've got
your pet freak coming to rescue you.
He's not a freak
and he can take you any time!
He's killed dozens of people.
He doesn't have any mercy or anything.
He even kills little girls.
Haven't we all?
Dang!
It's Horse.
Find him! Find him!
Yes! Yes! Yes!
- Come on.
- Getting nervous, aren't you?
I don't get nervous.
(Deacon)
And if there's a river, we'll dam it!
And if there's a tree, we'll ram it!
Cos I'm talkin' progress here!
Yes, sir!
- I'm talkin' development!
- Yeah!
We shall suck and savor
the sweet flavor
of Dryland.
(Enola) Your face is all red.
Helen said anybody that has a face
that red has either had too much sun
- or too much to drink.
- All right, that's it.
- I'm gonna burn your face!
- All right.
- What's up?
- We're just talking about her friend.
- What's his name?
- He doesn't have a name.
- So Death can't find him.
- (Mocking noises)
He doesn't have a home
or people to care for.
He's not afraid of anything,
men least of all.
He's fast and strong like a big wind.
He can hear 100 miles
and see 100 miles underwater.
He can hide in the shadow of a noon sun.
He could be right behind you and you won't
even know it till you're dead!
Give it a rest.
- He'll come for me. He will.
- Yeah?
Well, I hope he does.
Remember you said that.
(Deacon) Look at us.
Look at us here today.
Dryland is not just our destination,
but it is our destiny!
(Speech continues)
Find him! Find him!
How can I find this glorious place?
And he said to me,
"A child
"shall lead you."
A child.
- And behold...
- It's time.
The instrument of our salvation!
(Crowd roars)
Our guide in the wild!
Our beacon in the darkness!
Turn her around, Nord.
She has shown me the path!
And before the holy-most moment
is upon us,
let's sacrifice one to old Saint Joe!
And let's get this tub of shit
up to speed!
(Chaotic yelling)
Yep.
- Stroke!
- Pull!
Stroke!
Pull!
(Galley master) Stroke!
Stroke!
- So which way are we rowing?
- I don't have a goddamn clue!
Don't worry. They'll row for a month
before they figure out I'm faking it.
- But, um... Why?
- Oh, you want details?
Well, I'm not telling these savages
we haven't solved the map yet.
I promised them results and I'll get 'em
if I gotta cut 'em out of her back!
Who is that? Who is that?
(Man) Maybe one of the spare rowers?
Why aren't you rowing?
- It's him!
- It is him.
You guys are in so much trouble.
Well, I'll be damned.
It's the gentleman guppy.
He's like a turd that won't flush.
I want the girl.
You know,
I thought you were stupid, friend.
But I underestimated you.
You are a total freakin' retard!
(Maniacal laughter)
I want the girl. That's all.
What on this screwed-up earth
makes you think you're going to get her?
You know what this is?
I drop it, you burn.
We all burn.
No, wait, wait, wait.
Let's not do anything rash here.
I mean, are you sure she's worth all this?
She never does stop talking.
She never shuts up.
- I noticed.
- What is it, then?
Huh? It's the map.
She's my friend.
Golly gee.
A single tear rolls down my cheek.
You're gonna die for your friend.
If it comes to that.
He's bluffing! I'll kill him.
- He's not bluffing. He never bluffs.
- Shut up!
You know, I don't think you're going to
drop that torch, my friend.
- Why not?
- Because you're not crazy.
No!
Oh, thank God.
Aargh!
(Heavy gunfire)
(Man) Look out!
Get him!
Let's go, goddamnit!
(Man screams)
Don't just stand there - kill something!
Was this your big vision?
Aaargh!
Ah!
I've always wanted to drive this monster!
(Man) There he is! There he is!
That's him there!
Aargh!
Aaaargh!
(Enola) Let me go!
Let go!
(Explosion)
Let me go!
(Enola) Let me go! Let go!
Let go! Let go!
Let me go! Let go!
(Laughs)
You should have stayed on the water.
(Clicks)
You know how to fly an airplane?
You're lucky I do.
Ow! Now you stop it!
You behave yourself now!
Up!
(Explosion)
It's going down. It's sinking!
- Gregor, bring us right down on top.
- Hurry, Gregor!
- (Gregor) Don't worry!
- Hurry.
(Hull creaks)
Enola! Up here! Grab on!
Are they on yet?
- What is it?
- I don't know!
No!
Gotcha! I'm gonna rip
your cute little lungs out!
Aaaah!
Aaargh!
Pull! Almost!
(Gregor laughs)
(Explosion)
No!
- Aaaaargh!
- No! Enola!
Saint Joe! Hole in one.
- Helen!
- Enola!
- (Gregor) Helen!
- Hey!
Hey!
If I can't have Dryland, no one will!
Oh... Oh, no, quick!
What are we going to do?
Tie this off!
Hurry! Tie it!
- Got it!
- Ah!
Aaaargh!
Get them up now!
(Straining)
Of course.
Of course, the numbers.
The numbers! They...
(Giggling) That must be it!
What?
- I was swimming.
- I saw.
(Gregor) My friends, my friends, look!
Look, this map...
This map, it bears a grid system
with numbers the Ancients used
to determine geographic location
on the world,
just like the numbers and symbols
on Enola's back.
First, they would determine
the angle of the sun using this
and that would tell them where they were
and which direction they had to go.
If I take a bearing from the sun and
reverse the co-ordinates on Enola's back,
then Dryland is that way!
(He chuckles)
(Seagulls cry)
- (Helen laughs)
- It's fresh! All of this!
It's fresh!
(Gregor laughs)
(Helen) Come on!
Woo!
I've found something!
Maybe we should put them under the dirt.
I think it was their way.
(Gregor)
They must have known they were dying.
(Helen laughs)
(Music box plays)
I'm home.
- Where's the Mariner?
- He was outside.
Wait! Wait, I want to show you this.
(Thunder of hooves)
(Whinnying)
(Chorus of bird calls)
First time in your life you got nothing
to say?
Enola, I have to go now.
But you came back for me.
I like you.
Why are you leaving?
- I don't belong here. I belong out there.
- You belong here.
It's too strange here.
It doesn't move right.
Helen said that it's only landsickness.
We're all feeling it. It'll go away soon.
It's more than that.
Well, goodbye, my friend.
Oh, I have something for you.
It's dirt!
Don't trade it all in one place.
Or do! It will give you reason
to come back for more!
(Gregor laughs)
- It's all I got, Drifter.
- It's enough.
Is it that easy for you
to just drift away?
I never said it was easy.
I don't understand.
I mean, you brought us here.
You belong here as much as anyone.
Maybe more.
What do you think you're going to find?
What are you looking for out there?
Gregor once said there might be
others like me somewhere.
I have to know.
Helen, if...
If I find any others out there like you,
I'll tell them about this place
and how one woman with hope and courage
found it.
I have something for you.
- Something you'll need on your journey.
- I don't have much to barter with.
It's no trade. It's a gift.
- No such thing in Waterworld.
- Well, then, let this be the first.
It's a name.
It's from an old story about a great
warrior returning from battle.
He just set sail
and the water god cursed him,
and for the next ten years
he drifted on the seas.
The warrior drifted on the seas,
unable to find his way home,
until finally the gods took pity on him.
And they called up a warm wind
that blew him home.
To his family.
And he never left them again.
His name was Ulysses.
It's a good name.
(Panting)