♪ Out there
There's a world outside of Yonkers ♪
♪ Way out there
beyond this hick town, Barnaby ♪
♪ There's a slick town, Barnaby ♪
♪ Out there
Full of shine and full of sparkle ♪
♪ Close your eyes
and see it glisten, Barnaby ♪
♪ Listen, Barnaby ♪
♪ Put on your Sunday clothes
There's lots of world out there ♪
♪ Get out the brilliantine
and dime cigars ♪
♪ We're gonna find adventure
in the evening air ♪
♪ Girls in white in a perfumed night ♪
♪ Where the lights are
bright as the stars ♪
♪ Put on your Sunday clothes
We're gonna ride through town ♪
♪ In one of those new
horse drawn open cars ♪
♪ We'll see the shows at Delmonico's ♪
♪ And we'll close the town in a whirl ♪
♪ And we won't come home
until we've kissed a girl ♪
♪ ...ride through town ♪
♪ In one of those new
horse drawn open cars ♪
♪ We'll see the shows
at Delmonico's... ♪
♪ And we won't come home
until we've kissed a girl ♪
♪ Buy N Large is your super store ♪
♪ We got all you need
and so much more ♪
♪ No Monday in your Sunday ♪
♪ No Monday in your
Sunday clothes ♪
♪ Put on your Sunday clothes
when you feel down and out ♪
♪ Strut down the street
and have your picture took ♪
♪ Dressed like a dream
Your spirits seem to turn about ♪
♪ That Sunday shine is a certain sign ♪
♪ That you feel as fine as you look ♪
♪ And we'll recall ♪
♪ When time runs out ♪
♪ That it only ♪
♪ took a moment ♪
♪ to be loved ♪
♪ a whole life ♪
♪ long ♪
♪ And that is all ♪
♪ that love's about ♪
♪ ...a moment ♪
♪ To be loved ♪
♪ a whole life ♪
♪ long ♪
♪ Hold me close and hold me fast ♪
♪ The magic spell you cast ♪
♪ This is la vie en rose ♪
♪ When you kiss me heaven sighs ♪
♪ And though I close my eyes ♪
♪ I see la vie en rose ♪
♪ When you press me to your heart ♪
♪ I'm in a world apart ♪
♪ A world where roses bloom ♪
♪ And when you speak
Angels sing from above ♪
♪ Everyday words seem
to turn into love songs ♪
♪ Here is a little song I wrote ♪
♪ ...note for note
Don't worry ♪
♪ Be happy ♪
♪ Monday in your Sunday ♪
♪ No Monday in your Sunday clothes ♪
♪ Put on your Sunday clothes
when you feel down and out ♪
♪ Strut down the street
and have your picture took ♪
♪ Dressed like a dream
Your spirits seem to turn about ♪
♪ That Sunday shine is a certain sign ♪
♪ That you feel as fine as you look ♪
♪ ...new down to your toes ♪
♪ Get out your feathers
Your patent leathers ♪
♪ Your beads and buckles and bows ♪
♪ And that is all ♪
♪ that love's about ♪
♪ And we'll recall ♪
♪ When time runs out ♪
♪ That it only ♪
♪ Took a moment ♪
♪ to be loved ♪
♪ A whole life ♪
♪ long ♪
♪ ...find adventure in the evening air ♪
♪ ...horse drawn open cars ♪
♪ Buy N Large ♪
♪ ...it only takes a moment ♪
♪ ...Sunday clothes
when you feel down and out ♪
♪ Strut down the street
and have your picture took ♪
♪ That Sunday shine is a certain sign
That you feel as fine as you look ♪
♪ Beneath your parasol... ♪
♪ ...when time runs out ♪
♪ That it only... ♪
♪ Buy N Large is your super store
We got all you need ♪
♪ Put on your Sunday clothes
when you feel down and out ♪
♪ And that is all ♪
♪ That love's about ♪
♪ And we'll recall
When time runs out ♪
♪ Took a moment ♪
♪ to be loved ♪
♪ a whole life ♪
♪ long ♪
♪ Did you think that your feet
had been bound ♪
♪ By what gravity brings
to the ground? ♪
♪ Did you feel you were tricked
by the future you picked? ♪
♪ Well, come on down ♪
♪ All these rules don't apply
When you're high in the sky ♪
♪ So come on down ♪
♪ Come on down ♪
♪ We're coming down to the ground ♪
♪ There's no better place to go ♪
♪ We got snow up on the mountains ♪
♪ We got rivers down below ♪
♪ We're coming down to the ground ♪
♪ We hear the birds sing in the trees ♪
♪ And the land will be looked after ♪
♪ We'll send the seeds
out in the breeze ♪
♪ Did you think
you'd escaped from routine ♪
♪ By changing the script
and the scene? ♪
♪ Despite all you made of it ♪
♪ You're always afraid
of the change ♪
♪ You've got a lot on your chest ♪
♪ Well, you can come as my guest ♪
♪ So come on down ♪
♪ Come on down ♪
♪ We're coming down to the ground ♪
♪ There's no better place to go ♪
♪ We got snow up on the mountains ♪
♪ We got rivers down below ♪
♪ We're coming down to the ground ♪
♪ We hear the birds sing in the trees ♪
♪ And the land will be looked after ♪
♪ We'll send the seeds
out in the breeze ♪
♪ Like the fish in the ocean ♪
♪ We felt at home in the sea ♪
♪ We learned to live off the good land ♪
♪ We learned to climb up a tree ♪
♪ Then we got up on two legs ♪
♪ But we wanted to fly ♪
♪ And when we messed up
our home land ♪
♪ We set sail for the sky ♪
♪ We're coming down to the ground ♪
♪ There's no better place to go ♪
♪ We got snow up on the mountains ♪
♪ We got rivers down below ♪
♪ We're coming down to the ground ♪
♪ We hear the birds sing in the trees ♪
♪ And the land will be looked after ♪
♪ We'll send the seeds
out in the breeze ♪
♪ We're coming down ♪
♪ Coming down to Earth ♪
♪ Like babies at birth ♪
♪ We define new priorities ♪
♪ These are extraordinary qualities ♪
♪ We're coming down to the ground ♪
♪ There's no better place to go ♪
♪ We got snow up on the mountains ♪
♪ We got rivers down below ♪
♪ We're coming down to the ground ♪
♪ We hear the birds sing in the trees ♪
♪ And the land will be looked after ♪
♪ We send the seeds
out in the breeze ♪
♪ We're coming down to the ground ♪
♪ There's no better place to go ♪
♪ We got snow up on the mountains ♪
♪ We got rivers down below ♪
♪ We're coming down to the ground ♪
♪ We hear the birds sing in the trees ♪
♪ And the land will be looked after ♪
♪ We send the seeds
out in the breeze ♪
♪ We define new priorities ♪
♪ These are extraordinary qualities ♪
♪ To find on Earth ♪